<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Cryptography with longevity. A post-quantum secure blockchain featuring a stateful signature scheme and unparalleled security. - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 16:26:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/the-quantum-resistant-ledger" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL: April 9 — 15th]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-april-9-15th-a667a93bada9?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/a667a93bada9</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[localization]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 06:09:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-04-16T06:11:45.783Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL: April 9 — 15th</h3><h4>Internationalisation and localisation, Mobile progress, &amp; OTS tracking</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*0CjtFKaM3MBIZU-o95vjpA.png" /></figure><h3>Internationalisation and localisation</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Tm0YeeWv8WtIERYU_iCzbQ.jpeg" /><figcaption>Language processing has come a long way in terms of ease of implementation. Over-ear Headphones for scale.</figcaption></figure><p>i18n, or <em>internationalisation,</em> is the design and development of something that enables l10n, or <em>localisation</em>. There’s also g11n (globalisation) and l12y (localizability), which I’m only mentioning to emphasise the shared love for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Numeronym">numeronym</a>’s in this space.</p><p>To this end, we’ve recently had a call-out to those who speak different languages (l10n) to help moderate different language channels on our discord. This will be with the assistance of google translate (i18n), so everybody can feel like they have a bit of a babel-fish by their side — though I expect conversation will get pretty interesting as a few things are lost in translation.</p><p>For now this is starting with the languages Chinese (simplified), Dutch, French, German, Hindi, Italian, Japanese, Korean, Russian, and Spanish so long as there’s at least 1 moderator depending on his/her availability. It is also starting out as something segregated to the QRL Discord, with hopes it will expand beyond that as time, along with The QRL, moves forward.</p><p><strong><em>We are still in need of moderators</em></strong>, so if you’re calm, cool and collected, please fill out the <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSc4ba7nrxTMn2jYZKdSdAURs04XnvVQv1TO8PmA3om-PMFiNQ/viewform">Google Form</a>. If you have done so already, and you haven’t been contacted, expect a DM in the coming days.</p><h3>Mobile</h3><p>Applications have been submitted to both the iOS and Android stores and are just undergoing further scrutiny and final adjustments. There’s no timeline here, but it shouldn’t be much longer. This will complete our ecosystem with:</p><ul><li><a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org">Web-wallet</a> support.</li><li>Desktop wallets for <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/releases">Windows, Linux, &amp; Mac</a>.</li><li>Hardware wallet with the <a href="https://support.ledger.com/hc/en-us/articles/360019184453">Ledger Nano</a>.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/offline-wallet-generator/releases">Offline-wallet-generator</a>.</li></ul><h3>OTS Tracker</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Ucuk3JIhGKWiz7UOuelsfg.png" /></figure><p>We’ve always had a way to access what OTS keys someone has used by looking at the [meta] dropown in explorer at the bottom of an address page stuck in a disused lavatory with a sign on the door saying ‘beware of the leopard’.</p><p>While style is slated to be improved upon, there will be a separate tab that can display, <em>at a glance,</em> what OTS keys have and have not been used, leopards not included.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=a667a93bada9" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-april-9-15th-a667a93bada9">Last Week in QRL: April 9 — 15th</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL April 2–8]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-april-2-8-2bb96cd9510b?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/2bb96cd9510b</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[multi-signature-wallet]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[weekly-update]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 18:33:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-04-08T18:33:07.604Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>News and notes from QRL</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*c7sWAG2qhrxhNL_SJiJM0w.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Spring is upon us in many parts of the northern hemisphere as we enter the second week of April. Much like the changes in the natural world, some of the upcoming updates and evolution at QRL are already visible, some are just around the corner, and some are still further off towards the horizon. We will continue to keep you updated with blogs like this one, so tune in each week to see what has been going on (that we can talk about) at QRL.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*UDxH03pjgrssTBvdt0ldlA.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>theqrl.org:</strong> Improve QIP ingest + QIPs update</li><li><strong>MongoDB:</strong> Additional state and transaction data for explorer v2</li><li><strong>Multisig: </strong>Send and vote transactions complete</li><li><strong>Multisig: </strong>Test node deployed</li></ul><h3>Website Update</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*8ujihDyR2jmzU_PkJnjEhw.png" /></figure><p>As mentioned in a <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-march-12-18-2019-4e5c48d32651">previous “Last Week in QRL” blog</a> — we have and will continue to be updating the website. Some changes have been made internally and are merely waiting to be pushed to the website, while others are still being worked on.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/193/1*_lmLZqe7KHNkFF-34G00Mw.png" /><figcaption>New Getting Started dropdown</figcaption></figure><p>One such change is pictured above. We will be expanding the “Getting Started” section of the website to include a drop-down menu with a variety of links to various resources for a new user. Whatever someone is interested in doing with the network or coin, they can find their path(s) here.</p><p>As with all changes to the user experience, feedback is appreciated. We have already seen some very useful and constructive feedback to some of the changes we have pushed to the website, and we are very thankful for it. One of the strengths of our community has always been the passion present within it, and constructive feedback is a wonderful manifestation of this passion.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/961/1*yByZaav-CdoDTnBm1MaApg.png" /></figure><p>One such area where we received feedback was our team of core contributors. We had removed the specific section highlighting them, in favor of a more holistic list of our top open source contributors on GitHub. The top contributors list still features all of the core contributors, though it does not highlight them. We received feedback from numerous sources that the more expanded list of contributors was good, while also receiving feedback that the loss of the highlighted core contributors list left things unclear. As a result of that feedback, we have reinstated the <a href="https://theqrl.org/team/">team of core contributors</a> page.</p><p>We hope you continue to send in your feedback, as we continue to push updates live to the website moving forward. As always, we are happy to receive feedback on out <a href="https://github.com/theQRL">GitHub</a>, <a href="https://discord.gg/HTJsBgr">Discord</a>, or <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/QRL/">Reddit</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=2bb96cd9510b" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-april-2-8-2bb96cd9510b">Last Week in QRL April 2–8</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Start of a Journey]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-start-of-a-journey-cf7fb47f0c?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/cf7fb47f0c</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistance]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 19:08:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-04-03T13:39:37.709Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR — We are launched! The QRL network is one week old. Brief overview of media coverage, and a few words on what comes next</em></p><h3>Taking The First Step</h3><p>To paraphrase J. R. R. Tolkien, “It’s a dangerous business, going out your door. You step onto the road, and there’s no knowing where you might be swept off to.” Our launch was that stepping out our front door, onto a road that may lead us to any number of destinations. Such is the nature of product development, even more so when one is developing an open-source network. Once an open-source network is launched and out in the world, it can never really be said to be the sole property of any given team, even the team that created it. Somewhat similar to sending a child off to university, we do wonder what interesting styles and new pieces of flair our network might pick up out there in the wide world, but ultimately we are proud as parents of how far we have come.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/640/1*-hpTwPBdIofrkUJrmFDHKQ.jpeg" /><figcaption>Emotional state of the QRL team during launch</figcaption></figure><h3>We Launched!</h3><p>On the morning of June 26th, 2018 The Quantum Resistant Ledger launched its blockchain network. The moment we had all been working towards, and that our community has been patiently (and occasionally not-so-patiently) waiting for, had arrived. After ensuring the initial stability of the network, we opened it up to the public and to our delight, people began, almost immediately, to mine, create tokens and transfer value on the network.</p><p>It was a year’s worth of work, a group of individuals (a fellowship, if you will), coming together from different backgrounds to try and bring about a solution to a potentially existential problem facing our communal space. Despite some trials and tribulations, we fought on, making tough choices when necessary, but ultimately delivering our prize.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/640/1*gpJXbgrYLGGofjqj_5gwGw.jpeg" /><figcaption>The QRL Team, after a long road to a successful launch</figcaption></figure><p>We are happy to announce that there have been no major network outages, network collapses, 51% attacks, or significant periods of time without a block. All of the major mining pools that have taken to our network have reported smooth sailing. We have responded to every support ticket, and without fail have either alleviated the issue raised, or helped in its eventual conclusion. This would not have been possible without the hard work and dedication of the entire team, and it has been a pleasure to see their commitment to the project.</p><h3>In The Media</h3><p>We were delighted to see media outlets cover our launch, both with organic coverage and via our press release. Here are some of the articles that covered our launch:</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.chipin.com/quantum-resistant-ledger-launches-new-blockchain-network/">Quantum Resistant Ledger Launches New Blockchain Network</a> — Chipin</li><li><a href="https://thisweekincrypto.co/quantum-resistant-ledger-launches-new-blockchain-network/">Quantum Resistant Ledger Launches New Blockchain Network</a> — This Week In Crypto</li><li><a href="https://cryptocoremedia.com/qrl-quantum-resistant-ledger-mainnet-has-arrived/">Quantum Resistant Ledger Mainnet Has Arrived</a> — Crypto Core Media</li><li><a href="https://blocktribune.com/new-blockchain-claims-it-is-resistant-to-quantum-computing-attacks/">New Blockchain Claims It Is Resistant To Quantum Computing Attacks</a> — BlockTribune</li><li><a href="https://www.cryptoninjas.net/2018/06/27/quantum-resistant-ledger-launches-new-blockchain-network/">Quantum Resistant Ledger Launches New Blockchain Network</a> — CryptoNinjas</li><li><a href="https://www.newsbtc.com/2018/06/27/qrl-foundation-claims-its-new-blockchain-can-defy-quantum-computing-attacks/">QRL Foundation Claims Its New Blockchain Can Defy Quantum Computing Attacks</a> — NewsBTC</li><li><a href="https://edgylabs.com/whats-the-quantum-resistant-ledger-according-to-adam-koltun">Quantum Resistant Ledger COuld Make Current Blockchain Models Obsolete</a> — EdgyLabs</li><li><a href="https://www.the-blockchain.com/2018/06/29/qrl-launches-quantum-resistant-blockchain/?utm_campaign=BCN%20Twitter&amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;utm_source=twitter">QRL Launches Quantum Resistant Blockchain </a>— BlockchainNews</li><li><a href="https://altcointoday.com/can-a-new-blockchain-counter-the-quantum-computing-threat/">Can A New Blockchain Counter The Quantum Computing Threat</a> — AltcoinToday</li></ul><h3>Coming Up</h3><p>Over the next handful of weeks, look for more information regarding our additional audits, the role the QRL Foundation will be undertaking, as well as more on our evolving roadmap and what is in store next for our network. We are very glad to those of you who have been with us from the beginning, and happy to meet the new people joining our community every day. As I have said before, everything up to the actual launch of our network was preamble.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=cf7fb47f0c" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-start-of-a-journey-cf7fb47f0c">The Start of a Journey</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL March 26 — April 1]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-march-26-april-1-1494c781829e?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/1494c781829e</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qip]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 19:43:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-04-01T19:43:28.112Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL March 26 — April 1</h3><p><em>What went on last week</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*tEy81NY-zdCuXROPuRmIWw.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Today is April Fool’s Day in those parts of the world that celebrate the holiday. This blog will be free of hoaxes and practical jokes, however. This past week at QRL saw</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*bE4JAmqL83F6QKTWM8tBNQ.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>Block-explorer: </strong>Fix search box on mobile</li><li><strong>api.theqrl.org: </strong>3 minor fixes</li><li><strong>docs.theqrl.org: </strong>Remove dev notice for QRL Ledger Application</li></ul><h3>QIP 6: Implement dPoW</h3><p>Recently, QRL user “Machin” on Discord created a <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips">QRL Improvement Proposal (QIP)</a> on GitHub —<a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/blob/master/1.Ideas/qip-000/6%20Implement%20dPoW.md"> QIP 6: Implement dPoW</a>. As always, we highly encourage everyone to go read the QIPs in full for themselves. Here is the abstract:</p><blockquote>Purpose of this QIP is to implement a dPoW mechanism to strengthen QRL protection against attacks like 51%</blockquote><p>We are very excited to see another QIP on the GitHub, even more so because this one was originated wholly from a community member. We see the greatest potential for the QIP system when QIPs are not coming exclusively or primarily from the team, but rather the community. By continuing to decentralize elements of development, even indirect ones like a QIP, the general QRL ecosystem is strengthened. Hopefully, QIPs will pop up in these blogs much more regularly moving forward.</p><h3>Community</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*6QS7rKSOVnrHoZDU5wp0ew.png" /></figure><p>We are happy to announce that Discord user Machin is March’s QRL Community Nomination Winner! We asked Machin to tell us a bit about themselves and their relationship to the QRL:</p><blockquote>I am a French UX Designer with a technical background, working for a Telco company. I started to get interested in crypto and blockchain towards the end of 2015, and I bought a few ETH at the beginning of 2016. I really start to spend more time to understand the overall crypto world only in mid-2017, when I decided to diversify my portfolio. A part of my research was to understand risks of this technology. Thanks to my understanding of computer security, the first idea which came to me was the quantum computer threat.</blockquote><blockquote>I started to look for a crypto solution which could address that risk. The only project I found with a real ambition on this subject was QRL. This was in June 2017. Then I contributed to the QRL project during summer 2017 by providing some VPS to the dev team for a few months. In addition, I wrote some technical documentation to explain how to install and manage a QRL node on a Raspberry pi. I really appreciated being able to work with Kaushal/Cyyber during this period. Also, I would have liked to have been able to help out more on the UX Design but unfortunately, I did not have enough spare time to do it.</blockquote><blockquote>I must admit that my motivation and rate of contribution lessened when the team decided to move to PoW. But I kept an eye on the project and I was very happy to see that the team manage to develop the Ledger App. I decided to initiate a QIP after recent discussions regarding risk of 51% attacks. I would hope the dev team and overall QRL community works to find the best solution to mitigate the risk until a long-term solution is found.</blockquote><p>As always, we <em>highly </em>encourage anyone with interest to submit a QIP. It remains one of the most direct ways to contribute to the QRL ecosystem, as well as the most direct way to make your desires regarding the continued development of QRL known.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=1494c781829e" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-march-26-april-1-1494c781829e">Last Week in QRL March 26 — April 1</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Communication and Structure]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/communication-and-structure-ea697177d0ce?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/ea697177d0ce</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 20:25:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-03-26T20:25:35.244Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR — QRL has and will continue to evaluate its communication strategy and overall structure to best address the needs of the project as they continue to evolve.</em></p><h3>Communication</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/498/1*C5d6GQeQIANKC7YbsNK7Cw.png" /><figcaption>A:“Can you hear me?” B:“I can see you!”</figcaption></figure><p>Communication, broadly, is the imparting of data from one or more parties to another. Humanity&#39;s ability to communicate in a highly specific, wildly diverse manner is one of the things that has accelerated the evolutionary development of our species. Blockchain has revolutionary implications in various areas of our lives, and it is perhaps at its most revolutionary when it comes to data, and imparting it from one party to another.</p><p>When it comes to software development, communication is something of a new curiosity. When a car company unveils their new vehicle to be released the following year, the car is already built. When a company unveils its new app or service, to be launched in a few weeks/months, it is probably built, or at least going through final testing. With Blockchain, networks are being launched, and development is continuing, while the network is live. There is at times the feeling of repairing and improving a car as it is hurtles down the road.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*4RHTV8to6H6UPupm2wQJ1w.jpeg" /><figcaption>“Can you imagine if this was moving?”</figcaption></figure><p>Consequently, our communication strategy has necessarily evolved over the lifetime of this project. Some of this has been due to the needs of the project as it has moved from an ERC20, to an ERC20 with a test network, to a fully launched blockchain, and all the development that has gone on in the ~9 months since launch. We have also been mindful of the successes and failures we have witnessed in the broader blockchain market. Finally, we always try to take feedback from what we try; to expand that which works, and to restrict or abandon entirely that which does not.</p><h3>Evolving Communication</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/960/1*iXsGAhrafsPkTBkhWkgs0w.png" /></figure><p>The QRL Whitepaper was the first significant communication of the QRL project. It was like the Declaration of Independence — it proclaimed a notion, and spoke into existence an idea, whose promise was later fulfilled. Many of the ideas espoused in the Declaration were a bit different upon delivery to the real world (in the form of the Constitution). Similarly, the way a blockchain is described in its whitepaper, is usually a bit different to how it appears following its genesis block (let alone after its first hard fork). Our blockchain, and how we talk about it, is like many others in this regard.</p><p>When I first started with QRL in September of 2017, it was in the midst of a bull-run that was about to go parabolic. In that crowded field of ERC20s, Bitconnect drama, and the ongoing fallout from the Bitcoin Cash fork, the name of the game was distinguishing ourselves from a crowded field. Simple things, like name recognition and a basic understanding that quantum computing existed, were still lacking in the space. The accelerated pace of public appearances at conferences, expos, etc in 2018 was in no small part our effort to jump-start awareness.</p><p>As a reminder, our 2018 appearances were:</p><ul><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/event-blockdelhi-conference-february-21st-3a15fe318302">BlockDelhi 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/apac-blockchain-conference-2018-3817679b45b">APAC Blockchain 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/global-blockchain-expo-2018-next-week-77afb5a9c61c">Global Blockchain Expo 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-dc-finances-high-tech-family-office-meetings-b7fe8067d40d">DC Finance’s New York High Tech Family Office Meeting</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/consensus-conference-next-week-63f206bd0641">Consensus 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-my-evening-with-the-financial-services-club-in-london-573d5713f001">Financial Services Club of London</a></li><li>Crypto Valley Conference 2018</li><li>New York FinTech Week</li><li>Voice of Blockchain 2018</li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/discover-blockchains-conference-next-week-dab6e0b8651b">Discover Blockchains</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/crypto-block-conference-this-week-1a8f4d1d0cc4">CryptoBlockCon Las Vegas</a></li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/640/1*HEiyBL5dPNItRJhgkoFUjA.png" /></figure><p>We were on 4 continents, 5 countries, and 8 cities. We spoke to a variety of audiences with different levels of technical education, and were happy to note that, as the year went on, a growing portion of those we met at conferences had already heard of the project. Increasingly, people we spoke with at events were even aware of the inevitable intersection of blockchain and Quantum Computing. This was, of course, due to more than just our outreach efforts, as QC had been in the news, and in the news connected to blockchain, more in 2018 than in 2017. We expect that trend to continue through 2019.</p><h3>Structural Needs</h3><p>The needs of the QRL project, like any software development endeavor, has changed over time, and will continue to change moving forward. Our development staff has increased, and decreased, as the needs of the project have changed. One of the engines of decentralization long-desired by the project (and many in the community), is the QRL Foundation. As <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-january-29-february-4-2019-93abe4d5a886">previously noted</a>, the foundation is located in Switzerland, where it currently sits in a sort of probationary period. We will have a dedicated blog on it when that period is concluded, and we might more freely discuss it.</p><p>One question we have received in various forms through multiple channels is, “What role will the QRL Foundation play?” — as previously noted, there is a limit to the amount of detail that we can go into regarding this currently. However, it is no secret that the QRL Foundation is there to help ensure the greater decentralization, and overall health, of the QRL network. More generally, it is also there to potentially be a resource for any other organization associated with, or connected to, the QRL network. It is impossible to proclaim unilaterally how this will manifest, but it is our goal to have the QRL Foundation provide utility to those associated with the network.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/640/1*aTkwjKvism6D_Oxh1on82A.jpeg" /></figure><p>When a building is constructed, everyone can see the broad progress being made. When a blockchain network is developed, everyone can see the public progress on GitHub. One major difference, of course, is that it does not take an expert in construction to recognize when a building has added on a few floors, or put in the windows. However, it does take a more-than-moderate understanding of coding, and blockchain networks, to even be able to understand most of what is in any given project’s GitHub. Furthermore, any work that goes into features, fixes, or other elements that ultimately, for whatever reason, are not integrated into the main project, goes entirely unnoticed. This is all before one can evaluate whether or not the work that is in a given project’s GitHub is even functional, unique, or relevant to what the project is trying to ostensibly achieve.</p><p>Even work that does end up in the codebase, but which is more “under the hood” change than visible change (like converting repositories to different languages, for example), can go largely unnoticed, but oftentimes represents a significant amount of time and effort.</p><h3>Moving Forward</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/960/1*B7PaF2B785Heps6u4cY28A.jpeg" /></figure><p>As previously articulated, one of the goals of the QRL project is to decentralize as many aspects of the network, its maintenance, and its development as is reasonable. We have never lost sight of that goal, and one of the milestones on the road to achieving it has always been the QRL Foundation.</p><p>It has been intimated in this blog, and elsewhere, but to state it again; the full arrival of the QRL Foundation will not be an isolated event. Rather, it will reverberate out into the QRL ecosystem, in beneficial and productive ways. Patience is a virtue not often found in the blockchain space, and with good reason; the majority of people in the space have witnessed unprecedented growth, and want to see its return. We are trying to not rush anything, because nothing makes a trip take longer than having to retrace one’s steps.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=ea697177d0ce" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/communication-and-structure-ea697177d0ce">Communication and Structure</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL March 19–25, 2019]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-march-19-25-2019-a53b77d1601f?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/a53b77d1601f</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 17:54:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-03-25T17:54:54.934Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>What went on at QRL the previous week</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*N8C-3wo52jWHtfkBSZjj0g.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>This week’s blog will be slightly shorter than usual. The past week at QRL was just as productive as ever — however there was less than usual that we can talk about in real time. We can say that we had some discussions this week about the future shape of the blockchain ecosystem that were very thought provoking. We hope to be able to announce the fruits of such discussions in the coming months, but for today, here’s what we can talk about.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*B9uOpbTTjyn3PNrW29fflA.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>Mobile Wallet: </strong>Solved issue showing Sent (instead of Received) for multiple outputs transactions</li><li><strong>Mobile Wallet: </strong>Fixed app crashing on transaction send issue</li><li><strong>Mobile Wallet: </strong>Remove the refresh button on the Send/Receive screen</li><li><strong>theqrl.org:</strong> Added “Academia” section</li></ul><h3>Decentralization</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*663Xv2kT-QqbYmx2abIeLw.png" /></figure><p>Decentralization is one of the core concepts of blockchain technology. Whether it is a public chain or a private one, decentralization is one of the unique (and valuable) features of blockchain. The ability to have all data on a given network in every node, such that any given node can reconstruct the entire network, is in many ways an evolution of the network tenacity first demonstrated by the Internet. As we are all aware, decentralization is more than just a technological perspective in the blockchain/cryptocurrency space; it is a perspective on all types of organization.</p><p>Cryptocurrency users, generally, want all things decentralized. The first blockchain, Bitcoin, is an excellent (if not terribly imitable) example of decentralization. With an anonymous founder that has remained silent for the overwhelming majority of the life of the chain, no official central authority, and a worldwide community of developers, Bitcoin has set the bar high. For most projects, replicating Bitcoin’s decentralization identically is not an option. That does not stop decentralization from being a good and proper goal; it just means that it must come in different forms for different projects in different contexts.</p><p>At QRL, decentralization has been something that we have had as a commitment from the very outset of the project; and it is something that we are still striving towards today. Some of the more recent changes to the website reflect this, such as the <a href="https://theqrl.org/#contributors">Contributors</a> section. Other changes will be coming later on, but we wanted to reiterate our commitment to decentralization here, and make it clear that it still a priority of the project, and will remain so going forward.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=a53b77d1601f" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-march-19-25-2019-a53b77d1601f">Last Week in QRL March 19–25, 2019</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL March 12–18 2019]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-march-12-18-2019-4e5c48d32651?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/4e5c48d32651</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 19:55:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-03-18T19:55:58.765Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>What went on at QRL the past week</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*MgU5w0qWpXVVKjOi5GvKJQ.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Here in North America, Daylight Savings Time has come and gone once more, signalling for many the near-arrival of spring. However, in much of the rest of the world, DST does not arrive for another few weeks. In the meantime, we are double-checking our schedules whenever we have to meet to ensure we do not miss one another. As always, there was much activity behind the scenes. Below is a bit of what we can talk about right now.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/640/1*VomS0Va6MmuqPFU2u_fuTA.png" /></figure><ul><li><strong>Go QRL:</strong> Now receives unconfirmed transactions</li><li><strong>Vote_Tx: </strong>Planning for this transaction type discussed</li><li><strong>Block Explorer: </strong>Additional desirable features discussed (e.g. token type-ahead in search) — input welcomed from wider QRL community</li></ul><h3>Website Update</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/433/1*-nnNOdcZSDDLz_xx5_03EA.png" /><figcaption>What the new site might look like on mobile</figcaption></figure><p>In the coming weeks, you will notice some changes to the website. At QRL, we believe in regularly checking in with and updating our website. With new sections, some new content, and a new emphasis on QIPs, we hope that the website update will be an improvement. As always, we have and will continue to utilize user and community feedback. The best way to effect change is to make your opinion known to us, preferably through opening a <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/QRL/issues">GitHub issue</a>, where they can be tracked and followed up on more easily.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=4e5c48d32651" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-march-12-18-2019-4e5c48d32651">Last Week in QRL March 12–18 2019</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL March 5–11]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-march-5-11-c7a094f2eca5?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/c7a094f2eca5</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-x]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-s]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 21:42:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-03-12T18:52:24.340Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Some of the highlights from QRL the past week</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*RDck70DrnwYTl5zR1zLM9Q.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Last week was a big one for QRL; our Ledger application fully launched! The day that many on the team (and even more in the community) had been waiting for finally arrived, and went very smoothly. Aside from that, there’s been the normal focus on development, outreach, etc.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Az6ChygHN7sHr5B2phxANg.png" /></figure><ul><li><strong>Wallet:</strong> v1.1.1 of wallet released with full cross platform support</li><li><strong>Python Node:</strong> Separate address state for multisig created</li><li><strong>Go-QRL:</strong> Unit test for multisig_create complete</li><li><strong>Mobile: </strong>Sending Tx with insufficient funds exception now correctly caught</li></ul><h3>Ledger App Launch</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/600/1*ovAgpb6Kzi0HIWAXXaeFcA.jpeg" /></figure><p>As we <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-app-launched-3a8323d2de8f">happily reported last week</a>, the QRL Ledger App has launched! We have <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-nano-s-or-x-simple-instructions-49d864c570a5">step-by-step instructions</a>, as well as a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NL_u9biLy1g">how-to video</a> for anyone that is interested. So far we are happy to report that there have been no complaints regarding the application.</p><p>As always, if you have any questions or concerns regarding the QRL Ledger App, you can email <a href="mailto:support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a>, ask a question on our Discord, or message us on Twitter <a href="https://www.twitter.com/QRLedger">@QRLedger</a>.</p><h3>Automatic Migration</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*QJkYxWkZvQ1r7EwZ1Nqiog.jpeg" /></figure><p>Token migration has been quite a journey for the QRL community. From our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-token-migration-begins-b0d5b53f697f">blog announcing its start in April of 2018</a>, to the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/bittrex-exchange-migration-proper-liquidity-secured-for-the-qrl-df41045497e3">Bittrex Exchange Migration in late 2018</a>, to our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-app-update-eb89bcc5e657">more recent update</a>, and of course the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-app-launched-3a8323d2de8f">Ledger App launch </a>last week, Ledger support has been something on the minds of many in our community as a necessary element before they would feel comfortable migrating. Now that it is here, <strong>automatic migration will close on June 15th, 2019.</strong></p><p>As we have stated previously (and will continue to state moving forward), the end of automatic migration is not the end migration entirely. However, it <em>is </em>the end of our current process, and the start of a new one. Again, the process articulated below will only start after <strong>automatic migration closes on June 15th, 2019.</strong></p><p><strong>The QRL Foundation strongly encourages any and all users who still have QRL ERC20s to migrate them BEFORE the closure of automatic migration on June 15th, 2019.</strong></p><p>As is, the current process is <strong>automatic, anonymous</strong>, and <strong>almost immediate.</strong></p><p>After <strong>June 15th, 2019</strong>, the process for migrating ERC20s will be <strong>manual, semi-anonymous, </strong>and may take an<strong> indeterminate amount of time. </strong>Additionally,<strong> </strong>The QRL Foundation reserves the right to evaluate each manual migration on a <strong>case-by-case basis.</strong></p><p>The new process will look like:</p><ul><li>A QRL User will email <a href="http://support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a> with a QRL mainnet address the user created (QRL addresses that start with a Q)</li><li>The QRL Foundation (via <a href="http://support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a>) will respond to the User with an ETH ERC20 burn address</li><li>User will send QRL ERC20s to the ETH burn address sent via email</li><li>QRL address provided by User will be sent Quanta at a 1:1 ratio to ERC20s burnt</li><li>User will now have 1 Quanta in their QRL address for every 1 ERC20 they sent to their burn address</li></ul><p>As always, if you have any questions, comments or concerns about this process, or any other process, please do not hesitate to reach on Discord, Twitter, or send an email to <a href="http://support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a></p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=c7a094f2eca5" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-march-5-11-c7a094f2eca5">Last Week in QRL March 5–11</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ledger App Launched!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-app-launched-3a8323d2de8f?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/3a8323d2de8f</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-x]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-s]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 21:29:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-03-05T21:29:41.638Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR — The QRL Ledger app has been fully approved and launched. You can download, install, and run the application on Ledger Nano S or X today!</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*PqEllAcBIH74HXMBt_1dVQ.jpeg" /></figure><h3>How Do I Use It?</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/805/1*aBt1eqQKWOoHj0ykDC-C_A.jpeg" /></figure><p>As excited as we are to have the application finally launched, we are even more excited for people to actually download, install, and use it on their Ledger devices. The easiest way to do that is to go to <a href="https://www.ledger.com/pages/ledger-live">Ledger Live</a>, download it, and then select QRL’s application from the available options. If you would like a more detailed explanation, we have a separate, dedicated <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-nano-s-or-x-simple-instructions-49d864c570a5">How To blog</a>.</p><h3>A Developmental Triumph</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*xHVUe2hQ5ZhY6xJo3vaOrw.jpeg" /></figure><p>Given the uniqueness of our signature scheme (XMSS), we at QRL could not imitate or attempt to replicate any other project’s Ledger application. As has often been the case, our developers had to design a specific solution that fit the unique needs of our blockchain. While I am not the right person to pen an in-depth explanation of what went into that (though someone else may well do that in a later blog), I would be remiss to neglect to mention their tireless efforts.</p><h3>Auto Migration Post-Ledger Integration</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/429/1*rbHJPM08b8gP0PSYSOVJ0Q.png" /></figure><p>As we have indicated previously, we have been holding off on announcing an exact date for the closing of the auto-migration portal, waiting on Ledger integration. As a reminder, even after the auto-migration portal is closed, users will still be able to migrate their un-burnt ERC20s to main network Quanta. The process will simply no longer be automatic. Details on when exactly the auto-migration portal will be closed, and what the new system will look like, will be in an upcoming blog. The date announcement will also be echoed throughout our social media channels, with regularly scheduled reminders leading up to the day the portal closes.</p><h3>What This Means For QRL</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/200/1*XZt6vF_VdysWmnja_kE0qQ.png" /></figure><p>As we have discussed in previous blogs, Ledger integration has been an important milestone for the project — Ledger is the most used hardware wallet in the space, as well as the leader in hardware wallet technology. It is an important milestone for the community — one of the most dedicated and vocal segments of our user base are Ledger users. We have long heard their calls, and are very happy we can now provide them with the solution to storing Quanta on their Ledger Nano S or X.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=3a8323d2de8f" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-app-launched-3a8323d2de8f">Ledger App Launched!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ledger Nano S or X: Simple Instructions]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-nano-s-or-x-simple-instructions-49d864c570a5?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/49d864c570a5</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-x]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-s]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 21:28:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-03-05T21:32:10.877Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Ledger Nano: Installation Instructions</h3><p>There’s a full instructional video coming, and extensive full text-instructions with pictures already on our <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/wallet/ledger-nano-s/">documentation site</a>, but for those that want the TL;DR of installing QRL on your ledger device, this is for you.</p><p>If you already have setup Ledger Live before and are all updated, you will want to skip straight to <a href="#8897">step 3</a>.</p><h3>Setup and installation</h3><h4>1. Install Ledger Live</h4><p>The easiest way to install QRL on your ledger device is through <a href="https://www.ledger.com/pages/ledger-live">Ledger Live</a>. If you already have Ledger Live, ensure you install the latest firmware update.</p><h4>2. Setup your Ledger device</h4><p>If you’ve already done so, you can skip to step 3, otherwise follow the instructions on the <a href="https://support.ledger.com/hc/en-us/articles/360006395233-Take-your-first-steps">Ledger documentation website: first-steps</a></p><h4>3. Connect and unlock your Ledger device</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1004/1*W0hwfGE48qRyj3HhOhzZqg.jpeg" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1002/1*iqEVtF3xss5rYjdr1LX4hw.jpeg" /></figure><h4>4. Go to Manager and search for QRL</h4><p>After you have connected your device, search for QRL in the manager and click install. Follow any prompts.</p><p><em>Note: Ledger Live just enables easy installation of the QRL app on your ledger device, you will not be able to add or manage your QRL account from there.</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1006/1*sjp6Kuu4pwc_O2QOiC8Igg.jpeg" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*5utJw10OXSHcyUbgaGRz2w.jpeg" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1003/1*NVGxWmIGu26-0dSML6pFHA.jpeg" /></figure><h4>5. Initialising the QRL App</h4><p>Open the QRL app on your ledger device and scroll down to where it says <strong>Init Device</strong> and press <em>both buttons</em>. This will generate 256 keys (note: be patient, this takes about half an hour). After you are done, your device will be say <strong>QRL READY rem:256. </strong><a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/wallet/ledger-nano-s/#initialising-the-qrl-app">More details</a></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*1Ebyx6JDkUMEBEwHsuA7OQ.jpeg" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*uaDbR9jU7mK885ExJRVHbw.jpeg" /></figure><h3>Using your device</h3><h4>1. Make sure your device is unlocked (you don’t need Ledger Live for this) and the QRL app is open to “QRL READY”</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*uaDbR9jU7mK885ExJRVHbw.jpeg" /></figure><h4>2. Open the webwallet in explorer and Goto open wallet</h4><p>Direct link <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org/open">here</a>.</p><h4>3. Select from the dropdown “Ledger Nano S” or “Ledger Nano X” and click “Open Ledger Nano S” or “Open Ledger Nano X”</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*AP8Q-OWvVR1fBan6NEXnEw.jpeg" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*FAzPqyA1XH9qeKn-04Bblw.jpeg" /></figure><h4>4. Done</h4><p>Congratulations, you have successfully installed the QRL app and connected it to the wallet for secure transfers!</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*y_hv2WnQeh9TKADA1QKT7A.jpeg" /></figure><p>For a usage demonstration when it’s connected, Scott Donald has created a video which can be seen below</p><iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FNL_u9biLy1g%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DNL_u9biLy1g&amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FNL_u9biLy1g%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;key=d04bfffea46d4aeda930ec88cc64b87c&amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;schema=youtube" width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><a href="https://medium.com/media/43eaedbd6040b4e280addd9df5a4279e/href">https://medium.com/media/43eaedbd6040b4e280addd9df5a4279e/href</a></iframe><h3>Extra</h3><p>As a reminder, this is just a brief overview, if you want more information you can always head over to our extensive documentation page on the <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/wallet/ledger-nano-s/">Ledger Nano</a> or ask any questions you may have on <a href="https://reddit.com/r/QRL">Reddit</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/QRLedger">Twitter</a>, <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">Discord</a>, or email <a href="mailto:support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a>.</p><p>For those that are a bit more patient, we also have a video in the works covering this process.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=49d864c570a5" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-nano-s-or-x-simple-instructions-49d864c570a5">Ledger Nano S or X: Simple Instructions</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>