<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Cryptography with longevity. A post-quantum secure blockchain featuring a stateful signature scheme and unparalleled security. - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 20:04:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/the-quantum-resistant-ledger" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL Feb 5–Feb 11]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-feb-5-feb-11-4ffe424d4e7a?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/4ffe424d4e7a</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl-wallet]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:02:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-02-11T19:18:53.698Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*NVLCuh6b5zRlDMBsO-O2-Q.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>This is the final week of preparation before <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/">Developer Week 2019</a> next week. We will have a “Last Week in QRL” blog like normal on the 18th, then Adam and James will be heading out to Oakland the following morning. Both the seasonal and crypto winter have continued to slog on, but unlike the bear (both literal and figurative), we are not content to hibernate our way through. Progress continues, and below are some of the highlights that we can talk about.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*v7jfETYh3a3L0BU5KXSPsQ.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>Block Explorer:</strong> Fix search box on mobile</li><li><strong>Ledger:</strong> Fix nodejs comm names</li><li><strong>Wallet:</strong> Many changes, see QRL Wallet section below</li></ul><h3>QRL Wallet</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*l1AhaetbiZWOHuuk8Fg1iA.png" /></figure><p>The QRL Wallet has had a huge week of changes, so much so that we figured we should break it out into its own</p><ul><li>Supports Ledger Nano S in Web and Desktop apps across Mac, Windows and Linux (Ubuntu tested).</li><li>Desktop app now has installers (DEB for Linux, DMG for Mac, MSI for Windows)</li><li>Improved build process for Electron Desktop app</li><li>Improved desktop app closure process (resolve hanging node.js process)</li><li>Update Meteor 1.8.0.1 to 1.8.0.2</li></ul><h3>Upcoming Conference</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/600/1*XN3dz5ajWVr1xNjmFX8tUA.png" /></figure><p>Only 9 days until <a href="https://developerweek2019.sched.com/speaker/adam_koltun.1yz9ak9c">Adam speaks at DeveloperWeek 2019</a> — if you are still interested in attending a meetup somewhere nearby in Oakland, please reach out via Discord DM, Twitter, or Reddit. So far we have seen some interest, but not yet enough to justify a meetup. We will announce the meetup (if there is one) in our official preview blog of the conference (coming later this week).</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=4ffe424d4e7a" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-feb-5-feb-11-4ffe424d4e7a">Last Week in QRL Feb 5–Feb 11</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL January 29 — February 4 2019]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-january-29-february-4-2019-93abe4d5a886?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/93abe4d5a886</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[fintechtime]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-s]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 20:40:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-02-05T02:35:51.080Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL January 29 — February 4 2019</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Ld8-83XE3Rc3mhTPeCYI8w.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Some of what is in this blog might seem somewhat truncated — that is because we are only able to share so much on certain subjects, and are of the opinion that a brief preview is better than silence on an issue. As we continue to move into 2019, we will continue to provide these regularly scheduled updates, as well as other updates for specific events.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*2G80AfvYyqpjO-1pMfyRhg.png" /></figure><ul><li><strong>API:</strong> Updated address verification documentation</li><li><strong>Ledger: </strong>Adding Ledger Nano S Documentation for QRL App</li><li><strong>Offline Wallet Generator:</strong> Nearing release, new UI/UX (more below)</li><li><strong>Mobile wallet: </strong>Code QA underway, CI/Automated test suite planned</li><li><strong>Website: </strong>Website multilingual support and Polyglot integration in development</li><li><strong>Python node:</strong> OTS bit counter being removed and being replaced with paginated key counter</li><li><strong>MongoDB: </strong>2 hours to sync address state to MongoDB</li></ul><h3>Publicity</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/574/1*5ITCQIlnPRRnEffMSKQT_g.png" /></figure><p>A few weeks ago, we were approached by a writer from The Fintech Times, Matthew Dove. He sent us over a handful of questions related to Quantum Computing and its variable applications, both as a constructive tool, and as a breaker of encrypted systems. You can read more about it in the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/stepping-outside-our-bubble-the-fintech-times-quantum-leap-4260dec59b4a">blog we wrote on it</a>, or just <a href="https://thefintechtimes.com/quantum-leap-1/">read the article itself</a>. It was exciting to be approached by a publication that is non-endemic to the blockchain industry, and being the only representative of our industry in the article was very fulfilling.</p><h3>Ledger App</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/449/1*aO1bGLiWLcy6CGs2aHGgBw.png" /></figure><p>Our Ledger app is now complete (pending full release from Ledger)! It can now be found (along with installation instructions) at the <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/wallet/ledger-nano-s/">QRL Documentation</a> site. As always, DO NOT USE THIS APP ON A LEDGER WITH ACTUAL FUNDS IN ITS CURRENT STATE.</p><p>There is no penalty to waiting for the full release of the Ledger app. However, we have received word from some within the community that they wanted to test out the application (again, NOT ON A LEDGER WITH ACTUAL FUNDS), so we decided to provide the opportunity, for those interested and able.</p><h3>Offline Wallet Generator</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/919/1*5pndiSPltfzFki7t16wWbA.png" /></figure><p>As we discussed in our previous <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-jan-22-jan-28-2019-23cfdbb15e18">Last Week in QRL blog</a> — a great deal of progress has been made in the development of the QRL Offline Wallet Generator. We are happy to show off the above screenshot of the UI (as with anything, subject to change) of our Offline Wallet Generator. Being able to generate one’s own wallet, on one’s own machine, with no connection to the internet required, achieves both greater security and greater variety for our users.</p><p>At QRL we are always working towards giving the greatest diversity of reasonable options to our users, and we are happy to see this additional element coming to fruition. If you would like to follow along with the development progress more closely, you can watch the <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/offline-wallet-generator">relevant GitHub repo</a> at your leisure.</p><h3>Community</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*d65j1PcQVrdBPTyMTinCPQ.png" /></figure><p>We are happy to announce that Discord user Cingulate is January’s QRL Community Award Winner! Cingulate has been a constructive member of the community for awhile now, and has also been very helpful in our community insider’s group in advancing meaningful discussions and providing useful insights.</p><p>We asked Cingulate how they became acquainted with The Quantum Resistant Ledger, “I heard someone mention quantum computing in relation to crypto last October, and then did my own research, and found QRL. The rest is history. Came for the unique use-case, stayed for the intelligent and engaging community.”</p><h3>Facebook</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*7DDT7zIuqNylApVQGUOhwg.png" /><figcaption>Our new Facebook page</figcaption></figure><p>As most of you are aware, our central community hubs are Discord and Reddit. Discord is where the most lively and consistent conversations happen, and Reddit is where an avenue where conversations that take place over greater periods of time can sometimes be easier to have.</p><p>Our Facebook page has never been the center of our social media strategy, but it is a component nonetheless. We have recently updated our Facebook page, and are happy to show it off now. <a href="https://www.facebook.com/The-Quantum-Resistant-Ledger-492163101309701/">Link to the page</a></p><h3>Looking Forward</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/326/1*VKaWpkExV_9rzvzQ1PBJlg.png" /></figure><p>As many of you have already noticed, there is a new addition to the footer of theqrl.org — The QRL Foundation! From the outset, this project has had the goal of setting up a foundation to handle all manner of things in a responsible and effective manner. More info to come on this (in the form of a dedicated blog), but since we already have it up on the website, we figured we would illuminate the reason as to why (with, again, more details to come later). Those details may be a few months in the making, as there is a basic probationary period in Switzerland for these things, but make no mistake, when we can be more verbose on the subject, we will be.</p><p>We are always happy to check off a box that is still with us from 2017, and at this point, there are precious few remaining.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=93abe4d5a886" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-january-29-february-4-2019-93abe4d5a886">Last Week in QRL January 29 — February 4 2019</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stepping Outside Our Bubble: The Fintech Times’ “Quantum Leap”]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/stepping-outside-our-bubble-the-fintech-times-quantum-leap-4260dec59b4a?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/4260dec59b4a</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[tft]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-computing]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[the-fintech-times]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 17:32:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-02-04T17:32:33.939Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR — We were approached a few weeks ago by </em><a href="https://thefintechtimes.com/"><em>The Fintech Times</em></a><em> writer Matthew Dove, who asked us for our opinions on a number of Quantum Computing related issues. We provided quotes, some of which made it into today’s cover story for TFT, </em><a href="https://thefintechtimes.com/quantum-leap-1/"><em>“Quantum Leap”</em></a></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/574/1*5ITCQIlnPRRnEffMSKQT_g.png" /></figure><p>At QRL, we pride ourselves on two things, primarily; our work ethic, and our ability to collaborate effectively as a team. Increasingly, our ability to act as an ambassador and advocate for not just blockchain technology, but also, for lack of a better term, for greater quantum computing awareness, has made that list. We have been approached in the past for quotes on various blockchain and quantum computing related issues. Some of these end up in articles, including, recently, being asked by BlockTribune.com to give some <a href="https://blocktribune.com/blockchain-and-cryptocurrency-predictions-vol-ix/">predictions for blockchain in 2019</a>.</p><p>However, we have never found ourselves being asked to contribute to an article that stretches as far out of our little niche of blockchain (and into a larger niche, that of fintech), while still addressing what the fundamental relationship between network technologies and quantum computers is likely to be in the near future, and what we need to do to prepare for it.</p><p>We are humbled to have been the only blockchain project represented in the article, and we feel that we represented our point of view well; not engaging in fear-mongering, nor dismissing the very real disruptive potential of this emerging technology.</p><p>We recognize that as the first fully functional blockchain network secured by a quantum-resistant signature scheme, we have to both act as trailblazer, representative, and advocate if we are to help raise the awareness of the inevitability of quantum computing, and all that must be done now to protect our future networks from it.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=4260dec59b4a" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/stepping-outside-our-bubble-the-fintech-times-quantum-leap-4260dec59b4a">Stepping Outside Our Bubble: The Fintech Times’ “Quantum Leap”</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL: Jan 22-Jan 28 2019]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-jan-22-jan-28-2019-23cfdbb15e18?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/23cfdbb15e18</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[developerweek]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 19:58:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-01-28T19:58:48.471Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*RoFTLZHpTA8qnle-pSnALQ.png" /></figure><p><strong>Introduction</strong></p><p>As snow blankets much of the global north, and we get ready to enter the shortest month of the year, we at QRL are still hard at work trying to get a jump on 2019. This week’s blog will be slightly shorter than some in the past. As always, the length/depth of these blogs is only representative of those efforts of ours that are fit to be shared. As the old saying goes, “Still waters run deep.”</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/556/1*F7QDPyig4qBV4WNrekTALw.png" /></figure><ul><li><strong>Android:</strong> Solved issue related to the wrong amount transferred in mobile wallet</li><li><strong>iOS:</strong> Solved issue related to the QRL wallet address not updating after QR code was scanned in for</li><li><strong>Mobile Wallet:</strong> App stores submission processes to begin next week</li><li><strong>API:</strong> Pagination near completion — to be launched into devnet</li><li><strong>Offline Wallet Generator:</strong> Basic styling, end-to-end testing added to printout</li><li><strong>GO-QRL Node:</strong> Added MongoDB authentication support and updated unit tests</li><li><strong>Ledger:</strong> Code review underway by Ledger team</li></ul><h3>Liquidity</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*smrhDQ8haodyGdIB6BuuQQ.jpeg" /></figure><p>As you are already aware, Liqui delisted the QRL ERC20 token back in November. At the time we described it as largely inconsequential, as there was no significant volume on Liqui, we are a fully-fledged blockchain, and the ERC20 is just a leftover from the time before we launched. As a sort of follow up to that story, it now appears that Liqui will be closing its doors for good. <a href="https://liqui.io/">Per their website</a>, “Liqui is no longer able to provide liquidity for the Users left. We also do not see any economic point in providing you with our services. However, we do not want to return to where we were a month ago. Hence, we decided to close all accounts and stop providing our services,” the statement also says, “You will be able to withdraw your Digital Assets through our website within 30 days after this message was sent.” The message was posted to Liqui on January 28th, 2019.</p><p>We encourage any QRL users who may have any cryptocurrencies on Liqui, to immediately move your funds, as in 30 days they may be unreachable. Events such as this remind us that while, from a user’s perspective, exchanges may seem incredibly similar, if not indistinguishable, that there is still a significant degree of diversity, and that not all exchanges are created equal.</p><h3>Community</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*1mdVsD-puBnskbjau-dBmw.jpeg" /><figcaption>Neil Armstrong next to the X15 rocket-powered aircraft after a research flight</figcaption></figure><p>As we wrote in a <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-at-qrl-jan-15th-21st-7307be422bc9">previous-blog</a>, we are still on the lookout for interested community members to fill out our test pilot program, and anyone interested should fill out the google form we have for test pilots — <a href="https://goo.gl/forms/OPWoEoEVOtxYjEhB3">https://goo.gl/forms/OPWoEoEVOtxYjEhB3</a></p><p>Additionally, stay tuned — next week we will be announcing January’s Community Award Winner! In the meantime, our group of community insiders has continued to be a very useful sounding board and internal reference as we continue to develop documents for the FAQQ site, which we outlined in a <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-jan-7-jan-14-2019-aba7bb87dd38">different-but-also-previous-blog</a>.</p><h3>Upcoming Conference</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/600/1*XN3dz5ajWVr1xNjmFX8tUA.png" /></figure><p>Flights are booked, schedules are coalescing, and the final tune-up is being done on <a href="https://developerweek2019.sched.com/speaker/adam_koltun.1yz9ak9c">Adam’s presentation</a> for <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/">Developer Week 2019</a>. As always, if you are going to be in attendance, or just in the area, and would have interest in a QRL meetup, please reach out to us on <a href="https://discord.gg/zbAJ9YV">Discord</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/QRLedger">Twitter</a>, or via email, and if there is sufficient interest, we will post meetup details at a later date.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=23cfdbb15e18" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-jan-22-jan-28-2019-23cfdbb15e18">Last Week in QRL: Jan 22-Jan 28 2019</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week at QRL: Jan 15th-21st]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-at-qrl-jan-15th-21st-7307be422bc9?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/7307be422bc9</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[crypto-beadles]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-computing]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 20:40:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-01-21T20:40:45.405Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*AnwA9ARquAacQLl83cpbvg.png" /></figure><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*BEtsF7yj-LE0yQhaZkCpWw.jpeg" /></figure><h4>qrllib v1.0.4 (and v1.0.2, v1.0.3)</h4><p>QRL Lib v1.0.4 adds a build output from emscripten to instantiate the WebAssembly from base64 encoded qrllib: this allows for the use of qrllib in serverless environments (e.g. offline wallet generation). Which leads to the next advancement to the QRL ecosystem</p><h4>Offline Wallet Generator</h4><p>While it’s possible to generate a wallet <em>offline</em> with our current web and desktop wallets, an initial connection to a server is made. <em>Soon</em> it will be possible to load a few files (currently &lt;5 mb in size) on a USB Flash drive and generate wallets on an airgapped machine, negating the need to even instantiate a connection.</p><p>The work is done, it just needs to be cleaned up and put out for preliminary testing among our TestPilots (more below)</p><h4>QRL Mobile Wallet</h4><p>The QRL mobile wallet for iOS and Android has successfully gone through the initial round of community testing! As there were quite a few bugs squished and UI/UX improvements, there will be another round for our TestPilots to break in the coming week(s).</p><h4>QRL Faucet</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/846/1*i1zcVDZsvHVD0JQD7dgM4A.png" /></figure><p>The QRL Faucet, a <em>much</em>-requested feature, has been built! It has passed through an initial, internal test, and is currently undergoing additional, external testing from our group of community ‘TestPilots’ before being given wider release.</p><p>This faucet will function on both the test network and main network. It will issue tiny amounts of QRL in exchange for a brief browser PoW calculation, and is overall rate limited, to prevent over-eager users from draining the faucet balance too quickly. For those interested in seeing how our blockchain works, we hope that this will act as a pleasant introduction to our ecosystem.</p><h3>Community</h3><h4>QuantumFAQ/FAQQ Updates</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/788/1*IeGSNUriu2SgAYHGOnMfmA.png" /></figure><p>As we covered in our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-jan-7-jan-14-2019-aba7bb87dd38">last blog</a>, QuantumFAQ is an initiative to collect, articulate, and easily reference common misconceptions people have about blockchain and quantum computing.</p><p>One of the first changes was a name-change from QuantumFAQ to FAQQ (Frequently asked quantum questions) which was suggested by the community and voted in by a landslide. This means it also lives in a slightly different location: <a href="https://jackalyst.github.io/faqq/">https://jackalyst.github.io/faqq/</a></p><p>Other changes are:</p><ul><li>A “Footnotes” section so that all of our statements are sourced.</li><li>Separation between assertive statement FAQ’s and FAQ’s that’s geared towards misconceptions &amp; clarifications: “Quantum computers are coming” vs “Bitcoin will just hardfork”</li><li>A better table of contents that should be more effective at guiding people.</li></ul><p>There is still a lot of work to do filling things out and getting the language top notch but continuous progress is being made. If you see any errors, or if there are any misconceptions you would like to see covered, let us know through one of our channels!</p><p>As a note, FAQ’s that pertain to QRL will still live at <a href="https://theqrl.org/faq/">https://theqrl.org/faq/</a>. FAQQ is more of a community initiative geared towards Quantum Computing and Blockchain in general.</p><h4>The QRL TestPilot Program</h4><p>We now have a test pilot program! This is a <strong><em>discord only</em></strong> program and involves being part of the initial round of testing of a variety things before they go out to the wider community.</p><p>The general release overview is:</p><ol><li>Development/production</li><li>QRL Team Review (Round 1, 2, …): Catches initial show stopping bugs and reveals possible security considerations.</li><li><strong>QRL Test Pilot Review (Round 1, 2, …): Catches more show stopping bugs through device variability. Also highlights user interaction issues.</strong></li><li>Where applicable, a 3rd party audit.</li><li>General Release.</li></ol><p>While right now there are 7 excellent people that’s part of the test pilot program, and we’d like to expand this to achieve more test coverage.</p><p>If you’re interested please fill out our lovely google form: <a href="https://goo.gl/forms/BCFM1RYUC4S6DrCz1">https://goo.gl/forms/BCFM1RYUC4S6DrCz1</a></p><h4>December Community Award — 0xFF</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*S_9FKunWUpeukHCUbYeRHQ.png" /></figure><p>Our community award goes to 0xFF for contributing to community spirit with excellent puzzles, and for helping to spearhead a larger puzzle initiative that will be announced in the future.</p><h3>In the media</h3><iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FPKe6Q6bIl7k%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DPKe6Q6bIl7k&amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FPKe6Q6bIl7k%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;key=a19fcc184b9711e1b4764040d3dc5c07&amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;schema=youtube" width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><a href="https://medium.com/media/4b79dd45198d2fbaf9ea38c92e0a5386/href">https://medium.com/media/4b79dd45198d2fbaf9ea38c92e0a5386/href</a></iframe><p>Adam Koltun had a productive interview with the folks over at CryptoBeadles that went live this past week. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCcE2GkGcKxHjZoMVM7tjmyA">CryptoBeadles is a YouTube channel</a> with over 70,000 subscribers, dozens of videos, and has been covering the blockchain/cryptocurrency scene since 2017. Adam was able to talk about QRL in an accessible, down-to-earth manner, and we can safely assume that a number of people were hearing about QRL for the first time during this interview.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=7307be422bc9" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-at-qrl-jan-15th-21st-7307be422bc9">Last Week at QRL: Jan 15th-21st</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ledger App Update!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-app-update-eb89bcc5e657?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/eb89bcc5e657</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-s]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledgerwallet]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:30:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-01-18T00:30:17.306Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR — Ledger app is complete, awaiting final review. Automatic migration will close 3 months after Ledger app goes live. Instructional video on YouTube. More tech details to follow in a later blog.</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*cQFoUJ7L0whRF8SFLYvXyw.png" /></figure><h3>Development Progress</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*mE3FbEKaBZFMc6hVNv_TbQ.jpeg" /></figure><p>As we have previously communicated, the development of the Ledger app is complete. All that remains now is for Ledger to internally review it, give it their stamp of approval, and add our application to the list of approved applications for Ledger hardware.</p><p>We do not have any specific dates or timelines available to us, but rest assured that as soon as we have any actionable knowledge, we will share that on all social media (and probably write a blog about it as well).</p><p>More detailed information of everything that went into the development of this app will be forthcoming in a blog by our own developer Scott Donald.</p><h3>Automatic Migration</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/960/1*IEvy90uMhHVDz6y4Ywwe0Q.jpeg" /></figure><p>We are aware that there are many in the community that have been waiting on the completion and deployment of the Ledger application before migrating their ERC20s. As Ledger goes, so they go.</p><p>With that in mind, we have decided to peg the closure of the <a href="https://migration.theqrl.org/">automatic token migration app</a> to the launch of the Ledger app, as to do otherwise would run the risk of people who were waiting for Ledger not being able to access automatic migration if they wished. <strong>The automatic token migration app will be closed 3 months after the launch of the Ledger app.</strong></p><p>As we have stated previously, <strong>even after automatic token migration closes, users will still be able to migrate their coins.</strong> The migration will no longer be <em>automatic</em>, but it will still be <em>possible</em>. This ensures greater oversight and security of the later migrations, without leaving anyone out in the cold that ends up wanting to migrate their ERC20s into mainnet Quanta at a later date.</p><h3>How To Video</h3><iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FNL_u9biLy1g%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DNL_u9biLy1g&amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FNL_u9biLy1g%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;key=a19fcc184b9711e1b4764040d3dc5c07&amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;schema=youtube" width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><a href="https://medium.com/media/43eaedbd6040b4e280addd9df5a4279e/href">https://medium.com/media/43eaedbd6040b4e280addd9df5a4279e/href</a></iframe><p>The above video was recorded by QRL’s own Scott Donald, and shows how one can easily access their wallet and move funds using their Ledger Nano. We wanted to provide users with this information ahead of time, so that when the application goes live on Ledger, there is no gap waiting for instructions.</p><p>We know that Ledger integration has been a top priority for a portion of our community since before we even launched the blockchain. We are very excited at how close we are to being able to say that the Ledger application is functional, live, and available.</p><p>Thank you for your patience.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=eb89bcc5e657" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-app-update-eb89bcc5e657">Ledger App Update!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL: Jan 7 — Jan 14, 2019]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-jan-7-jan-14-2019-aba7bb87dd38?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/aba7bb87dd38</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 21:00:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-01-14T21:00:40.032Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL: Jan 7 — Jan 14, 2019</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*8Y6iR9cQr9tiO-NTYciuuQ.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>After a few abnormal weeks and multiple-week blogs, we are back on our weekly blogging schedule (for now). As always, the length and presentation of these blogs will adjust slightly as the content changes (not all weeks are equally dense in terms of sharable developments).</p><h3>Development Updates</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*g6BbCqnh8GLL-k00cwZwcg.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li>Support for MongoDB Processor in GO-QRL has almost finished, including fork recovery.</li><li>Unit tests for MongoDB have been 80% completed.</li><li>Added <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/developers/knownIssues/">known issues section</a> to documentation site.</li><li>QuantumFAQ site coming (more on that below)</li></ul><h3>QuantumFAQ site</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*7OWx6YmB6TOWSp30ls6DHg.gif" /></figure><p>Those in the community will know the very common responses that come up when speaking to people in the wider cryptocurrency community about Quantum Computing — and maybe they have had these questions themselves.</p><p><a href="https://jackalyst.github.com/quantumfaq/">QuantumFAQ</a> is a site (in alpha) designed as a resource to be linked to and confidently digested with the attention span people have today (seconds). Common responses will be curated underneath to guide people through their curiosities, where all answers should be satisfied in no more than 2 minutes of time. Other thoughts in the future involve more predictive responses and links to more resources.</p><p>The site can be reached at: <a href="https://jackalyst.github.com/quantumfaq/">https://jackalyst.github.com/quantumfaq/</a></p><p>Github repository: <a href="https://github.com/jackalyst/quantumfaq">https://github.com/jackalyst/quantumfaq</a></p><h3>Marketing/Outreach Updates</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/254/1*W0GO5jefz7RKjq84rpaEcw.png" /><figcaption>What a marketing job sometimes feels like</figcaption></figure><p>With the holidays and the start of the new year, we have been hard at work reaching out across the industry to try and spread the good word of QRL. We had an interview this past week that had to be rescheduled, but when it eventually takes place we think it might offer something slightly different from our normal interview fare.</p><p>We were approached by a well-known financial technology publication to give quotes regarding quantum computers. We submitted our quotes, and are hoping to be able to show them off to you in the coming days/weeks as a part of an article they are creating. Stay tuned!</p><h3>Liquidity Update</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/400/1*KDYO4etAzPDSLtuktvKeVA.gif" /></figure><p>On March 1st, Coinexchange.io will be delisting the QRL ERC20 token from its markets. CoinExchange never migrated the few ERC20s on its platform, so it is in possession of 0 mainnet Quanta.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*1fMKxI33etl-6R2xjHeJDg.png" /><figcaption>Statement on CoinExchange’s delisting page</figcaption></figure><h3>Community Updates</h3><p>As we’ve stated <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-s-in-qrl-december-4th-17th-2018-e7f744845075">previously</a>, we have changed format for the Community Nominations, and will now be conducting them <em>monthly</em>, for a prize of 750 Quanta. We expect to have our first winner announced in the next “Last Week in QRL” blog.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=aba7bb87dd38" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-jan-7-jan-14-2019-aba7bb87dd38">Last Week in QRL: Jan 7 — Jan 14, 2019</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No, IBM’s Quantum Computer won’t break Bitcoin, but we should be prepared for one that can.]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/no-ibms-quantum-computer-won-t-break-bitcoin-but-we-should-be-prepared-for-one-that-can-cc3e178ebff0?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/cc3e178ebff0</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-computing]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ibm]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 19:25:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-01-15T15:08:28.364Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Quantum computing that can break blockchain is coming, and it’s time the blockchain community accepts it — so we can prepare ourselves.</h4><p>The Verge said it best with “<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/8/18171732/ibm-quantum-computer-20-qubit-q-system-one-ces-2019">IBM’s new quantum computer is a symbol, not a breakthrough.</a>”. It’s important to expand on that and what it means to Bitcoin, and blockchain in general. What we <em>shouldn’t</em> do is turn a blind eye.</p><h3>Contents</h3><ul><li><a href="#aea9">Primer</a></li><li><a href="#8931">IBM’s Commercial Quantum Computer</a></li><li><a href="#1a57">When do we need to worry, anyway?</a></li><li><a href="#8b16">The importance of preparation</a></li></ul><h3>Primer</h3><p>Anytime there’s an advancement in Quantum Computing, like <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/tech-talk/computing/hardware/intels-49qubit-chip-aims-for-quantum-supremacy">Intel’s 49 qubit chip at <em>last year’s</em> 2018 CES show</a>, or this years CES show with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/8/18171732/ibm-quantum-computer-20-qubit-q-system-one-ces-2019">IBM’s 20 qubit commercial quantum computer</a>, blockchain news outlets are always there to assuage worries, with <strong>“No, [<em>this</em>] Quantum Computer won’t break bitcoin”</strong>, often accompanied by the sentiment that the looming quantum computing threat is being blown right out of proportion.</p><p>What they usually fail to note is that, once again, quantum computing is passing metrics ahead of schedule. Previously quantum computing was relegated to something that would not reach a commercial application until the mid to late-2020s. That is not to say quantum computers have only ever outpaced expectations, but rather to contextualise the strength of today’s quantum computers not just against a static metric of being able to break ECDSA, but also a development curve.</p><p>While it is <em>true </em>that IBM’s commercial quantum computer won&#39;t break Bitcoin, this is <strong>not</strong> the mindset we want to have with the underlying cryptographic fundamentals of something that underpins <em>billions</em> of dollars worth of value (in just cryptocurrency alone)— and hopefully <strong><em>much</em></strong> more in the future.</p><p>To put a visual metaphor to waiting until it’s too late: A ballistic may not penetrate your fortress today, one will someday, <em>a thought secured by recent developments, </em>makes it<em> </em>prudent to fortify sooner and be <em>proactive</em>, rather than <em>reactive</em>. Being <em>reactive</em> means your fortress will be compromised, or in the case of blockchain, your private keys stolen, and what’s the point of fortifying then?</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/498/1*ehnsou-cfieKcYyPi0niDA.gif" /></figure><p>In this way, the frame of the conversation needs be proactive, rather than reactive. Decentralized networks, by their very nature, are censorship resistant, and while that means many wonderful things for end-users generally, in terms of security it means that it can be very difficult/impossible to functionally undo transactions. Therefore, we cannot afford to be <em>reactive</em>, we must be <em>proactive</em> in order to meaningfully prevent negative, irreversible security outcomes.</p><h3>IBM’s Commercial Quantum Computer</h3><p>At CES, <a href="https://newsroom.ibm.com/2019-01-08-IBM-Unveils-Worlds-First-Integrated-Quantum-Computing-System-for-Commercial-Use#assets_115:1612">IBM announced a commercialised version</a> of its 20 qubit computer which could be shipped out to institutions and businesses looking to start building on real quantum computers.</p><h4>How powerful is it?</h4><p>Unlike bits on your computer which are binary and scale linearly, qubits scale exponentially, which means that every qubit added to a system doubles its computational power. For a 20-qubit system, we’re looking at 2²⁰. To give some context, this is something that your average powered notebook can simulate perfectly well and is exactly what Microsoft does for its <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/quantum/development-kit">Quantum Development Kit</a>. The breakdown is:</p><ul><li>2²⁰ Laptop: Commercially, we’re here!</li><li>2³⁰ Desktop</li><li>2⁴⁰ Cloud compute service (For Microsoft, this is Azure)</li></ul><h4>If it’s not so powerful yet, who is it for?</h4><p>IBM’s commercial quantum computer is demonstration that they can produce a <em>reliable</em>, upgrade-able commercial quantum computer. Clients who purchase a 20-qubit system today, could upgrade their systems down the line, having already familiarised themselves with IBM’s commercial quantum computer. This would appeal to researchers in particular, as having a QC on-hand would increase uptime for experiments, and help decrease system downtime.</p><h4>What does this mean for blockchain</h4><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/8/18171732/ibm-quantum-computer-20-qubit-q-system-one-ces-2019">As aptly penned by The Verge</a>, this is a symbolic development to mean that NISQ era quantum computers are here, commercialised, <em>today</em>, and with <a href="https://newsroom.intel.com/press-kits/quantum-computing/">Intel</a>, <a href="https://www.research.ibm.com/ibm-q/">IBM</a>, <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-ca/quantum/">Microsoft</a>, <a href="https://ai.google/research/teams/applied-science/quantum-ai/">Google</a>, <a href="https://newsroom.intel.com/tag/quantum-computing/">Intel</a>, <a href="https://www.lockheedmartin.ca/ca/what-we-do/emerging-technologies/quantum-computing.html">Lockheed Martin</a>, <a href="https://www.rigetti.com/">Rigetti</a>, and <a href="https://quantumcomputingreport.com/players/public-companies/">more</a>, all in the ring competing, it’s clearly not <em>just</em> in the lab.</p><p>The blockchain community needs to accept that quantum computers are here, today. While the timeline for when they can threaten blockchain security is uncertain, <em>whether</em> that day will come is no longer a matter of debate. No one wants to see a catastrophic event where large swaths of the cryptocurrency ecosystem is wiped out, but that is sadly a possibility if we do not act in a timely manner.</p><h3>When do we need to worry, anyway?</h3><p>This isn’t an easy thing to answer, but working off of our “how many qubits” list from above we can expand on it and get a number to run Shor’s algorithm.</p><ul><li>2⁵⁰ Average supercomputer: We have already passed this! Currently, the largest stable QC in the world is 2⁷²</li><li>2⁸⁰ Quantum Supremacy: Quantum Computers are faster than the fastest supercomputer with a synthetic test. A milestone Microsoft is anticipating to pass this year.</li><li>2³⁰⁰⁰ Quantum Computers can run Shor’s algorithm: Shor’s can break ECDSA 256 (what Bitcoin uses): <strong>We want to upgrade <em>well</em> before this point.</strong></li></ul><p>Looking back, we can take the development trajectory of the number of qubits a system has had over the last 4 years and attempt to extrapolate:</p><ul><li>2015: 4-qubits</li><li>2016: 9-qubits (IBM)</li><li>2017: 17-qubits (Intel), 50-qubits (IBM)</li><li>2018: 49-qubits (Intel), 72-qubits (Google)</li></ul><p>This indicates a 5.5x/1yr — 18x/4yr increase, or, assuming a similar trajectory, it will be between 2.2 and 5.3 years until we hit 3000 qubits. However, there is more work to do than just stacking up qubits. There is the lingering issue of error-correction, which currently stands as a barrier to proper, accurate calculations. There is also the issue of scaling, which is being addressed in a number of ways, but has not been solved.</p><p>On the other side, Shor’s Algorithm is merely the first quantum algorithm to usher in an interest in quantum computing. There continue to be advances towards breaking Elliptic Curve Cryptography on a variety of levels through newer, more efficient algorithms that can <a href="https://quantumcomputingreport.com/news/zapata-develops-potential-alternative-to-shors-factoring-algorithm-for-nisq-quantum-computers/">run on our non error-corrected quantum computers.</a></p><p>Those are pretty big variables, which is why you’ll see everything from 2 to 30 years before ECDSA P-256 is broken. In some ways this range doesn’t matter, <em>but there’s no question</em> that we want to have everything secure well ahead of it.</p><h3>The importance of preparation</h3><p>If you’ve ever dealt with keeping systems secure in any capacity, it’s important to keep up to date. Generally, this means following Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE) notices and other security bulletins, and checking to see the state of your hash functions and cipher suites.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*qGNmQ9d_Xw_Tnat1Hs0xDQ.png" /></figure><p>What becomes very evident over time is that not everything lasts forever. You harden your systems, and others find ways to weaken them. The cryptographic methods you used as a kid just aren’t going to cut it today. One signature scheme that’s held out for a <em>remarkably </em>long time is ECDSA.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*zwpeoTZ5o9iHdsPgkp6liQ.png" /><figcaption>Looking at the chart, we’re somewhere around “Minor weakness discovered” and “Serious weakness discovered”</figcaption></figure><p>This is the cadence security and cryptography has had for thousands of years since the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caesar_cipher">Ceasar cipher</a> and continues to have to this day. Some would say it’s echoed in the fabric of nature itself between parasites and hosts.</p><h4>Proactive blockchain design for an adversarial future</h4><p>Proactive security is a core value for The QRL — something we think should be of paramount importance for any network that caries substantial value.</p><p>We are using XMSS as recommended by <a href="https://pqcrypto.org">pqcrypto</a> to secure our accounts and transactions. XMSS gives complete peace of mind from the emerging black swan of quantum computing, with reusable addresses, provable security and minimal security assumptions.</p><p>This is a <em>proactive</em> step against Quantum Computing, but as the cadence goes, it’s important to be proactive against new developments as well, some which may be harder to predict.</p><p>We went to great lengths to <em>also</em> design a foundation that allows for variable key heights and signature space to ensure compatibility with potential new cryptographic schemes that may be developed in the future. Our blockchain includes the possibility to upgrade signature schemes (XMSS, SPHINCS, + future) and through an address format update, support different cryptographic hash functions (SHA2_256, SHAKE_128, SHAKE256 etc). You can read more about on <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/developers/address/">our documentation</a> site.</p><p>We hope that blogs like these help illuminate some of the complicated relationship between blockchain and quantum computers. We know that we must act as an educator in this space, and are happy to rise to the occasion.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=cc3e178ebff0" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/no-ibms-quantum-computer-won-t-break-bitcoin-but-we-should-be-prepared-for-one-that-can-cc3e178ebff0">No, IBM’s Quantum Computer won’t break Bitcoin, but we should be prepared for one that can.</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week(s) at QRL: Dec 18–Jan 6]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-s-at-qrl-dec-18-jan-6-87f2b17c8c94?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/87f2b17c8c94</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledgerwallet]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 18:16:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-01-08T18:16:13.246Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*OGirdELd8Xkc8YjwCbAVOw.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>It has been a little while since our last “Last Week in QRL” blog. So in honour of this being the first blog of 2019, “Happy New Year!”</p><p>Obviously this blog will have closer to just one week’s worth of content in it, despite covering two weeks, as both Christmas (check out our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/12-days-of-xmass-e787fd958d2c">12 days of XMaSS blog</a>) and New Year’s occurred during those weeks. As always, life in a startup project can be very hectic, and everyone enjoyed the opportunity to be able to spend some quality time with their families, and perhaps reflect upon the past year.</p><p>As we have stated elsewhere, 2018 was obviously a disappointing year across the cryptocurrency market, in terms of price. However, we believe that both within our project, and across the wider blockchain ecosystem, that some very important and meaningful work has been completed this year. 2018 saw QRL go from an ERC20 to a fully-realised, fully-functional blockchain network. The close of 2018 had QRL as a mineable PoW coin, with liquidity secured, robust documentation and API sites, and many exciting features on the horizon. Given where we were at the start of 2018, we cannot help but look at it as a success.</p><p>Hopefully, as time goes on, the overall prices across the blockchain ecosystem begin to more meaningfully reflect the hard work and real progress being made behind the scenes.</p><h3>GO-QRL</h3><p>Go-QRL has been running stable for around a month now running QRL mainnet. While stable, there’s still components required to bring it up to feature parity with the Python implementation — and beyond. Over the holidays, Kaushal continued his perseverance and added a Public API, makefile support, with a new JSON-based backend infrastructure in progress.</p><p>The JSON-based backend will make it easier for people to interact with the API without requiring the setup and maintenance of our wallet daemon, walletd.</p><h3>Block Explorer</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/488/1*v1io_xyLgIhMdT1dkrhdEw.gif" /><figcaption>Dark and Light Theme</figcaption></figure><p>From the outset, we at QRL have recognised that a piece of software is only as good as the user’s ability to utilise it. To that end, we have never stopped making improvements to our UI/UX. The latest of these improvements, adding a dark theme to our wallet and block explorer, have been another step in that process. This was met with much applause, and some disdain from the community lamenting the disappearance of a light theme.</p><p>Based on this feedback, as the above GIF should show, the <a href="https://explorer.theqrl.org/">QRL Block Explorer</a> will soon have a button to toggle the theme from Light to Dark, and vice versa. We believe this will help make our block explorer experience more pleasant and useful.</p><h3>Mobile Wallet Testing</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*_1tj04T7JUzIsbu7DvkpQA.png" /></figure><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-s-in-qrl-december-4th-17th-2018-e7f744845075">When we last checked in</a> on our mobile app on iOS and Android, we were finishing up internal testing and getting ready to move on to a first round of testing to a select group in the community.</p><p>We are happy to report that this has taken place, and that the testing so far has been both productive and encouraging. We recognise that a mobile wallet app is an element that, along with the release of our Ledger app, many in our community have been waiting for.</p><p>After some fixes and tweaks take place, we’ll be opening this up to the wider community to test in the next few weeks.</p><h3>Ledger Nano S</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/971/1*JOUTMbvrI1VFrYGMi7E4HQ.png" /></figure><p>Speaking of the Ledger App, we have more news. As we stated in our previous “Last Week” blog, we had a release-candidate version of the Ledger app up on our GitHub.</p><p><strong><em>We can now say that we have entirely completed the Ledger integration, and are now awaiting only a full and thorough review from the Ledger team themselves</em></strong>, before the app should be ready for release. Integrating with quality hardware like that which Ledger produces represents a significant achievement on the part of the development team, and we are all very proud of the hard work and long hours it has taken to get to being on this precipice of its materialisation.</p><p>Scott Donald has studiously put together a tech demonstration on how the wallet and the Ledger Nano S works harmonistically together.</p><iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FNL_u9biLy1g%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DNL_u9biLy1g&amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FNL_u9biLy1g%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;key=a19fcc184b9711e1b4764040d3dc5c07&amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;schema=youtube" width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><a href="https://medium.com/media/43eaedbd6040b4e280addd9df5a4279e/href">https://medium.com/media/43eaedbd6040b4e280addd9df5a4279e/href</a></iframe><h4>Ledger Nano X</h4><p>After 1.5 million devices sold, the Ledger team announced the Ledger Nano X, which you can read more about <a href="https://www.ledger.com/pages/ledger-nano-x">here</a>.</p><p>To answer the inevitable question early on as to whether QRL will work on the Ledger Nano X, the answer is the device will work on the QRL wallet, but there’s more work to enable it on the Ledger mobile and desktop apps. We will have more information on this in a separate, Ledger-specific blog.</p><p>Of course, this means more toys for the developers to play with!</p><h3>Confirmed for DeveloperWeek 2019</h3><p>Adam Koltun will be speaking at <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/">DeveloperWeek 2019</a> in Oakland, California on February 20th, at the Oakland Convention Center. <a href="https://developerweek2019.sched.com/speaker/adam_koltun.1yz9ak9c">Link to his speaker bio</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=87f2b17c8c94" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-s-at-qrl-dec-18-jan-6-87f2b17c8c94">Last Week(s) at QRL: Dec 18–Jan 6</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[12 Days of XMaSS]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/12-days-of-xmass-e787fd958d2c?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/e787fd958d2c</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[xmss]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[12-days-of-christmas]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 19:44:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-12-24T19:44:22.044Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR — This is a cheerful, jovial blog meant to take a fun, non-serious look at where the project is at as 2018 comes to a close, but mostly to have some festive fun before the end of the year. Enjoy!</em></p><p>On the first day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>A private key in an (extended) Merkle Tree</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/728/1*-m3M7AyBdz8OQrSUatYVNw.png" /></figure><p>On the second day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>Two Separate Audits</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/599/1*GaVAZkT7xXayfq54ijcSBg.png" /></figure><p>On the third day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><a href="https://theqrl.org/"><strong>Three Different Desktop Wallets</strong></a></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*cakH5GpAQ39JhfnY_vPGhw.jpeg" /></figure><p>On the fourth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me <br><strong>4k Discord Members</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/811/1*se_sPGWwewD6PGzLHo8b8Q.png" /></figure><p>n the fifth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong> 5 Community Members Nominated</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*rC1VxV2hR2aWKkeWGXkJIA.png" /></figure><p>On the sixth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me <br><strong>6 QRL Block Reward</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*_NZ25cqH3Be67uZ920dHug.png" /></figure><p>On the seventh day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>7 Podcast Interviews</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/539/1*cnW4-roIbNHsFwVW07f95A.jpeg" /></figure><p>On the eighth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>8 Presentations Given</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1018/1*YJEsFeL0uuCTq02mIt7T0A.png" /></figure><p>On the ninth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>9 Whitepaper Translations</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/472/1*XndAzJRLUNypXvzznvuZGw.jpeg" /></figure><p>On the tenth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>10 QRL Developers</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ZsLRt1UHh56lG2syshBGFg.jpeg" /></figure><p>On the eleventh day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>11 Conferences Attended</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/768/1*lrlKw5OqQlHg8tVeS2tgkw.png" /></figure><p>On the twelfth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>12+ Team Members!</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/780/1*VNnreXNsnpUaAN-3zMP21Q.png" /></figure><h3>See you all next year!</h3><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=e787fd958d2c" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/12-days-of-xmass-e787fd958d2c">12 Days of XMaSS</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>