<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Cryptography with longevity. A post-quantum secure blockchain featuring a stateful signature scheme and unparalleled security. - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 17:40:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/the-quantum-resistant-ledger" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL June 4–10]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-june-4-10-ebc36409c050?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/ebc36409c050</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[bittrex]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 16:05:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-06-10T16:05:39.872Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Token Migration Reminder, Bittrex US Geofencing</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*NFSCc6BvXoQBC8RaKWa7Cg.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>There is never a dull week in blockchain, and this past one was no exception. Bittrex announced that it was geofencing 32 crypto assets from United States customers Friday (more on this below), and significant progress has been made on further integrating Ledger. This is also the last “Last Week” blog before the end of Automatic Token Migration later this week on <strong>June 15, 2019 3:00 pm UTC-05:00</strong>, so we will have another reminder regarding that at the end of the blog.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*rcLJwEwLoBrJ9Fs95QZKRA.png" /></figure><ul><li><strong>ledger-live: </strong>Work on integration underway (more in <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/dev-meetings/blob/master/2019/06/06.md">dev meeting notes</a>)</li><li><strong>ledger: </strong>New BOLOS app (Nano S/X, multitree) with WebUSB-ready supporting library awaiting review by Ledger</li><li><strong>wallet:</strong> Pagination support underway: discussed adding this to explorer-helpers to allow recycling of code in explorer</li></ul><h3>Community</h3><p>We recognize that between the closure of automatic token migration at the end of the week (check out the <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/tokenmigration/countdown/">countdown</a>), and the recent Bittrex geofencing news (dedicated blog <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/geofencing-of-crypto-assets-b800494f0c6d">here</a>), that a lot of information has been coming at the QRL community. We wanted to thank our community members for being so supportive of one another and quickly stepping up to disseminate information among one another.</p><p>This is probably most evident on Discord, where newcomers are oftentimes given a bevvy of information upon entering the server for the first time and asking some “What’s all this?” type questions. A coin is only ever as strong as its community, and it is encouraging to see so much passion from ours.</p><h3>Bittrex Geofencing of United States Customers</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*zAREr3w_wSv5wAPPZGD8gA.jpeg" /></figure><p>As we wrote in a <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/geofencing-of-crypto-assets-b800494f0c6d">previous blog</a>, Bittrex recently announced that it was geofencing 32 crypto assets, including QRL, from US customers on 2019–06–21.</p><p>Trading for non-US customers will continue unchanged on the Bittrex International platform.</p><p>You can read the full announcement <a href="https://bittrex.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360028996652">here</a>.</p><p>While this will not halt development progress on the project, the near term priority for the project will be procuring an additional listing on a major Asian exchange as soon as is practical.</p><h3>Automatic Token Migration</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*x37t9zJwA4zcg7tH9XvxMg.jpeg" /></figure><p>The current token migration process is <strong>automatic </strong>once you have started the process<strong> </strong>and <strong>almost immediate</strong>.</p><p><em>After</em> <strong>June 15, 2019 3:00 pm UTC-05:00</strong>, however, the process for migrating ERC20s will be <strong>manual,</strong> and may take an <strong>indeterminate amount of time</strong>. <em>Additionally</em>, each manual migration will be evaluated on a <strong>case-by-case basis</strong>.</p><p>It’s <em>strongly</em> recommended that any and all users who still have QRL ERC20’s to migrate them <strong>BEFORE</strong> the closure of automatic migration on June 15th, 2019.</p><p>We have also outlined this on our <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/tokenmigration/countdown/">documentation page</a> to help keep everything in one spot and ensure everyone is on the same page with migration.</p><p>The process of token migration thusfar has been a successful and relatively smooth one. The overwhelming majority of QRL ERC20 tokens have been migrated. There are only a few unmigrated tokens left, and hopefully, there will be hardly any left once automatic token migration closes.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=ebc36409c050" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-june-4-10-ebc36409c050">Last Week in QRL June 4–10</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Geofencing of Crypto Assets]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/geofencing-of-crypto-assets-b800494f0c6d?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/b800494f0c6d</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[bittrex]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 16:49:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-06-08T16:51:45.426Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Bittrex will be geofencing 32 assets, including QRL, in the coming weeks</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*zAREr3w_wSv5wAPPZGD8gA.jpeg" /></figure><p>It has come to our attention that Bittrex will be geofencing 32 crypto assets including QRL from US customers on 2019–06–21. Trading for non-US customers will continue unchanged on the Bittrex International platform.</p><p>Full announcement can be read <a href="https://bittrex.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360028996652">here</a>.</p><p>Whilst we have no more information on this than has been released publicly by Bittrex, we support their efforts in evolving the cryptocurrency ecosystem and hope that their geofencing will be short-lived, especially as the open source QRL ecosystem is now mature and QRL is so widely distributed around the world.</p><p>In the last few days the QRL chain has grown past 500k blocks; a planned hard fork to bring on-chain decentralised governance, numerous iterative improvements and multi-signature wallet support is not far away. Mobile platform support, Keybase integration for identity proofs, and Ledger hardware wallet support have recently been added to the QRL, with Ledger X support, multi-tree support and Ledger Live integration right around the corner.</p><p>We are one of the few projects to take post-quantum security seriously and are proud that the entire ledger is already PQ-secure with a professionally audited codebase. Cryptocurrency should be impervious to technical attack and post-quantum insecurity remains a critical vulnerability in the armor of this nascent asset class.</p><p>Development progress aside, the near term priority for the project will be procuring an additional listing on a major Asian exchange as soon as is practical.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=b800494f0c6d" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/geofencing-of-crypto-assets-b800494f0c6d">Geofencing of Crypto Assets</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[May Community Nomination Award]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/may-community-nomination-award-16294e740d2?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/16294e740d2</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl-communit]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 16:55:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-06-06T16:55:12.326Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*vJoeJvxVUhP1s_fbjsJ1lA.png" /></figure><p>We are pleased to announce that last month’s QRL Community Nomination Award goes to Discord user Mquantum.</p><p>Here’s what Mquantum had to tell us about themselves, and their relationship to QRL:</p><blockquote>Although not working directly in the field of quantum computing, during 2017 I started to realize the growing impact it has in my research field (I am a PhD in quantum physics) and began eagerly reading about it. That was also the time of the last big bitcoin bullrun, when, admittedly curious of the big gains people were making, I started to read about bitcoin and blockchain. The collision between quantum computing and blockchain was quite obvious to me, and the most serious and welcoming place to discuss those things was clearly the QRL community. I was particularly impressed by the Reddit posts by Jackalyst and Dezeyay, and a <a href="https://medium.com/coinmonks/quantum-computers-pose-a-credible-threat-to-the-security-of-bitcoin-4b1dd65944ca">Medium article by Charlie Thompson</a>.</blockquote><blockquote>I do not know if going through the 2018 bear market earns me a veteran medal, anyway I surely won a Basic Whining Token (1 BWT to me), as did many in the Discord server. It is clear now that the QRL community is steadily increasing its impact in the crypto discussion. I love being part of it, and am intrigued by the efforts the QRL team is making in favoring decentralization. The next months are crucial both for the progress of quantum computing and for the QRL building, I believe!</blockquote><p>Mquantum has been a member of the QRL community, as he states, since 2017. We value the diversity of knowledge present in our community highly, and are always glad to have that brought to bear in our community discussions. Mquantum has shown themselves to be a productive, positive member of our community and we are pleased that they are receiving the May Community Nomination.</p><p>Know someone who you think deserves a Community Nomination? Write “nominate [platform] [username]” (example: nominate twitter QRLedger) in the <a href="https://discordapp.com/channels/357604137204056065/357607117412106241/510858891706236929">#butler channel</a> of our <a href="https://discord.gg/zbAJ9YV">Discord server</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=16294e740d2" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/may-community-nomination-award-16294e740d2">May Community Nomination Award</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL May 28th — June 3rd]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-may-28th-june-3rd-d598ed1919c0?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/d598ed1919c0</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[node]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[token-migration]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[erc20]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 14:57:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-06-03T18:51:23.382Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL May 28th — June 3rd</h3><p><em>Development Updates, Community Updates, Token Migration Reminder</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*aUi4DIEPy6zXXUqbC5Fk1g.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Last week saw our mobile wallets get out into the wider community, to wonderful reception. We truly appreciate all of the feedback, from praise to constructive criticism, and have taken it all into proper account as we move forward. This past week has us moving closer towards the closure of automatic token migration (more on this below), as well as the one year anniversary of our blockchain launch! Expect regular reminders about the closure of automatic migration both here, and on our other social channels, over the next 12 days.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*LHGtskpMp3zdQywz_jjicw.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>go-qrl</strong>: Rate limiter added to Go QRL public API</li><li><strong>mobile: </strong>Roadmap agreed for mobile app v2 and v3/beyond</li><li><strong>node: </strong>Python node (master branch) now has additional API function of data directory size (i.e. chain size)</li></ul><h3>Community</h3><p>We will announce the winner of the Community Nomination for May in a separate blog, probably later in the week.</p><h3>Token Migration Reminder</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*NXPaycjJv_7d4RGQBXoKrw.jpeg" /></figure><p><strong>AUTOMATIC TOKEN MIGRATION ENDS JUNE 15, 2019 2000 UTC (</strong><a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/tokenmigration/countdown/"><strong>Countdown</strong></a><strong>)</strong></p><p>As we announced back in April in a <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/automatic-qrl-token-migration-end-date-845f94e3f6d9">dedicated blog</a>, automatic migration will be closed as of <strong>JUNE 15, 2019 2000 UTC.</strong></p><p>This will <strong>not </strong>mark the complete removal of user’s ability to migrate ERC20’s. However, currently the process is <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/tokenmigration/countdown/#migration-steps"><strong>automatic</strong></a><strong> </strong>and can be completed in its entirety by the user on their own. After <strong>JUNE 15, 2019 2000 UTC</strong>, the process will be <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/tokenmigration/countdown/#steps-after-june-15th"><strong>manual</strong></a><strong>,</strong> require interacting with The QRL team in some capacity, and may take an <strong>indeterminate amount of time</strong>. <em>Additionally</em>, each manual migration will be evaluated on a <strong>case-by-case basis</strong>.</p><p>This cannot be stressed enough: every user with ERC20s remaining in their possession, <strong>please</strong> migrate them to main-network Quanta on the QRL blockchain as soon as it is reasonably possible for you to do so.</p><p>We have seen a wonderful showing from users so far, with the number of ERC20’s remaining dwindling by the day. Ensuring that as much of the token population is migrated before <strong>JUNE 15, 2019 2000 UTC </strong>is a priority for the team, so expect more reminders over the next 12 days as we advance towards the end of automatic migration.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=d598ed1919c0" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-may-28th-june-3rd-d598ed1919c0">Last Week in QRL May 28th — June 3rd</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL: May 21st — 27th]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-may-21st-27th-fa8fb1017e02?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/fa8fb1017e02</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[ios]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 17:41:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-05-29T17:39:07.410Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL: May 21st — 27th</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/994/1*YC7mOXZuW6t1w05bsD8tWA.png" /></figure><p>This week, we will be covering our mobile wallet release and some of the amazing feedback that we’ve had and what to expect for our version 2 release.</p><p>Also covered will be Ledger U2F timeout issue, its potential solutions (linked to), and the current workaround.</p><h3>Mobile wallet released</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/752/1*RaBpMhJiT-dBCNLLO9oOiQ.png" /></figure><p>Last week our mobile wallet was released to the world! You can read more about it in our blog <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-mobile-wallet-is-officially-launched-e3014dd79d8e">The QRL Mobile Wallet is Officially Launched!</a> This completes our ecosystem with:</p><ul><li><a href="https://support.ledger.com/hc/en-us/articles/360019184453">Hardware wallet</a> (Ledger Nano)</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/releases">Desktop Wallets</a> (Windows, Mac, Linux)</li><li><a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org">Web wallet</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/offline-wallet-generator/releases">Offline wallet</a></li><li>Mobile wallets (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/qrl-wallet/id1458620542?ls=1&amp;mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.theqrl">Android</a>)</li></ul><p>Since then, there’s been a outpouring of amazing <em>and </em>constructive feedback on the mobile wallet. We can’t emphasize how much <em>constructive </em>feedback means to us, and how important it is to this project as a whole, if we are to improve.</p><p>JP and Adem have been busy working out what issues will be tackled for the next v2 or v3+ release, which can be seen on our <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/milestones">milestones page</a>. Some things <em>most likely</em> slated for our next released are(all subject to change):</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues/63">Ask for PIN when removing wallet</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues/61">Ask pin at every access</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues/57">Allow adding a tag to the wallets</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues/55">Feature request: Add a link to the explorer on transaction details view</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues/54">Feature request: Add a “copy address” button on the wallet details view (when tapping the QR code icon)</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues/50">Feature request: Add option to open existing wallet with mnemonic.</a></li></ul><p>Don’t see your request on either the <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/milestones">milestones</a> or <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues">issues</a> pages? We would love for your to submit it on GitHub directly, or ask a community/team member with access to GitHub to do so on your behalf! Again, big props to the community for such productive feedback to this project over the years.</p><p>Haven’t downloaded the QRL mobile wallet yet? Do so for <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.theqrl">Android</a> or <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/qrl-wallet/id1458620542?ls=1&amp;mt=8">iOS</a>.</p><h3>U2F timeout issue</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/712/1*ulnXyfVdRyMPmNOIlLmGrQ.png" /></figure><p>Ledger devices have been using the U2F protocol for easy and cryptographically secure second factor mechanism with the web browser since 2016.</p><p>Lately, U2F timeouts have been enforced more aggressively — which you may have noticed if you’ve ever experienced a “U2F timeout” warning. Previously, we’ve recommended using another browser or playing browser bingo. <strong><em>The new current recommended action is to use our desktop wallets, which can be found on the </em></strong><a href="https://theqrl.org/"><strong><em>front page of our website</em></strong></a><strong><em> and our </em></strong><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/releases/latest/"><strong><em>github releases page</em></strong></a><strong><em>.</em></strong></p><p>You can read more about the development of U2F tunnel transport for Ledger devices in their blog <a href="https://www.ledger.com/2019/05/17/windows-10-update-sunsetting-u2f-tunnel-transport-for-ledger-devices/">Windows 10 Update: Sunsetting U2F tunnel transport for Ledger devices</a> and read <a href="https://support.ledger.com/hc/en-us/articles/360023518653">troubleshooting advice</a> on their support site.</p><p>As progress is made on this, we will of course keep you abreast of any events.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=fa8fb1017e02" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-may-21st-27th-fa8fb1017e02">Last Week in QRL: May 21st — 27th</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The QRL Mobile Wallet is Officially Launched!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-mobile-wallet-is-officially-launched-e3014dd79d8e?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/e3014dd79d8e</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[ios]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[mobile-wallets]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 18:34:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-05-22T18:34:20.736Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The QRL Mobile Wallet for both Android and iOS is fully released</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/752/1*UUu8LlLskFUhNod53NMgWw.png" /></figure><p>From being the size of a briefcase to the size of a pencil case, the cellphone has gone from literally just a mobile telephone, to today being accurately described as a mobile computer. Given the decentralized, international, internet-based nature of cryptocurrency, it is no surprise that people want easy and secure access to their cryptocurrency wallets, wherever they are. That dream has now been realized in the form of the QRL mobile wallet.</p><p>At QRL, empowering our users is always on our mind, and a fast, functional mobile wallet interface is a necessary element in the pursuit of that goal. Today, we are happy to announce that the QRL Mobile Wallet is fully launched on both Android and iOS devices. You can find them on the <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/qrl-wallet/id1458620542?ls=1&amp;mt=8">Apple Store</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.theqrl">Google Play Store</a>.</p><p>We cannot emphasize enough the hard work and dedication that Adem, our Mobile Developer, has put into these applications, and we are very thankful for him (you can go thank him yourself at his Twitter account <a href="https://twitter.com/ademcan_net">here</a>).</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1013/1*gOnedxZdCA-hPfwcbN_HHA.png" /></figure><p>As the above images indicate, some of the functionality available to users of the mobile wallet include (but are not limited to):</p><ul><li>Offline wallet creation</li><li>Multiple wallet support</li><li>Send/Receive transactions</li><li>QR code integration</li></ul><p>A Few Notes:</p><ul><li>The QRL Mobile Wallet App is not available in China</li><li>The application may take some time to be added to the search indexes of the Google and Apple stores, respectively. However, you can access them via our links (<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.theqrl">Google</a>) (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/qrl-wallet/id1458620542?ls=1&amp;mt=8">Apple</a>), and they should appear in searches soon.</li></ul><p>Between the <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org/">web wallet</a>, <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/releases/">desktop wallet</a>, <a href="https://shop.ledger.com/pages/ledger-live">Ledger integration</a>, and now the mobile wallet, there is a well-rounded variety of options for any given user to access their Quanta.</p><p>We are always looking to improve our current offerings, as well as to identify and pursue those things we have not yet considered. To that end, we are always appreciative of constructive feedback from our wonderful community of users. Please feel free to let us know on <a href="https://discord.gg/V5ZDUAr">Discord</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/qrledger">Twitter</a>, or <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues">GitHub</a>, how you like the mobile app and if there are any improvements we should consider.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=e3014dd79d8e" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-mobile-wallet-is-officially-launched-e3014dd79d8e">The QRL Mobile Wallet is Officially Launched!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL May 14–20]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-may-14-20-b46c7251fc34?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/b46c7251fc34</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[erc20]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 17:38:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-05-20T17:38:40.049Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development updates, Automatic Migration update</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*JNTI19fdE7AHHJcdLtC1-Q.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>This past week has been a more-positive-than-usual one in the cryptosphere — locally, our integration with Keybase (blog <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-and-keybase-84968003bca2">here</a>) went smoothly, and was well received by our users. More generally, the Consensus conference in NYC as well as some dynamic price action, has had the wider blockchain community aflutter with all sorts of proclamations and predictions. As ever, completing one task at QRL just leaves room to attack the next one. In the (relatively) near future we will be able to announce more fun utility added to the QRL ecosystem. For now, the best of what we can talk about is below.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*gppZaKrYawY4Vgf0I_uJVg.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>qrl-ledger:</strong> Updating app (adding multitree support)</li><li><strong>block-explorer:</strong> Fix for Q/q in route on address page</li><li><strong>block-explorer: </strong>Bump explorer-helpers version</li></ul><h3>Token Migration Update</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*wUksQw4Xu9i1NuyY2ZBRUw.jpeg" /></figure><p><strong>AUTOMATIC TOKEN MIGRATION ENDS JUNE 15, 2019 2000 UTC (</strong><a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/tokenmigration/countdown/"><strong>Countdown</strong></a><strong>)</strong></p><p>As we announced back in April in a <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/automatic-qrl-token-migration-end-date-845f94e3f6d9">dedicated blog</a>, automatic migration will be closed as of <strong>JUNE 15, 2019 2000 UTC. </strong>This will not mark the complete removal of user’s ability to migrate ERC20’s. However, currently the process is <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/tokenmigration/countdown/#migration-steps"><strong>automatic</strong></a><strong> </strong>and can be completed in its entirety by the user. After <strong>JUNE 15, 2019 2000 UTC</strong>, the process will be <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/tokenmigration/countdown/#steps-after-june-15th"><strong>manual</strong></a><strong>,</strong> require interacting with The QRL team in some capacity, and may take an <strong>indeterminate amount of time</strong>. <em>Additionally</em>, each manual migration will be evaluated on a <strong>case-by-case basis</strong>.</p><p>This cannot be stressed enough: every user with ERC20s remaining in their possession, please migrate them to main-network Quanta on the QRL blockchain as soon as it is reasonably possible for you to do so.</p><p>We have already seen a great response from the community, with over half the remaining ERC20s migrated over the past few weeks. We at QRL are very pleased by this, and sincerely hope that migration continues at this rate, leaving little to no ERC20s un-migrated when automatic migration closes (<strong>JUNE 15, 2019 2000 UTC).</strong></p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=b46c7251fc34" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-may-14-20-b46c7251fc34">Last Week in QRL May 14–20</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL May 7–13]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-may-7-13-4f70f54e5333?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/4f70f54e5333</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[keybase]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bci]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 18:04:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-05-13T18:04:35.242Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Keybase Integration, Community Update</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*SoG6s0VdLJBW7uoADHY6RA.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>These blogs are usually intended to be a review of the past week’s activities. Today however, we are also including breaking news that went live this morning!</p><p>We are happy to report that QRL addresses can now be added to your <a href="https://keybase.io/">Keybase Identity</a>. We have been eagerly looking forward to this day for the past few weeks/months, and are very excited to be sharing it with you all.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*SQm5ZwCZdYRLXwz9em5xLA.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>theqrl.org:</strong> Keybase integrations</li><li><strong>ledger-qrl-app:</strong> cleanup nvram handling + small UI tweaks</li><li><strong>qrl-wallet:</strong> Keybase integration release</li></ul><h3>Keybase</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Vfci4Bj4ypsWmXlLwvjkTQ.png" /></figure><p>As our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-and-keybase-84968003bca2">blog earlier this morning</a> announced, you can now add your QRL address to your <a href="https://keybase.io/">Keybase </a>account to help prove your digital identity. For those unaware, Keybase is a catalog of connected identities that utilizes cryptographic proofs to link profiles. For example, you can currently link your GitHub, Twitter, Reddit, Bitcoin or ZCash addresses (along with ~200 other services) currently to prove your identity. Starting today, QRL addresses may also be used in this manner to prove your digital identity. Obviously, if your QRL address is proving your identity, then your identity is also associated with that QRL address, so make sure you are comfortable with that address being publicly known before associating it with your Keybase account.</p><p>Our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-and-keybase-84968003bca2">previous blog</a> has more detailed instructions, but here is a quick rundown:</p><ul><li>In the Keybase app click on the <em>Add more identities </em>button, and select QRL from the list</li><li>Enter your QRL address where it asks for your “username”</li><li>When you submit, it will open a page that looks like this:</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*HA9BQKa6y7U_Yzv1wAW0zg.png" /></figure><ul><li>Do not hit “Submit” on this page yet!! Instead, copy the field marked “Signature Hash”</li><li>Open the QRL web or desktop wallet</li><li>Unlock the same wallet whose address you initially entered</li><li>Select “Tools” from the sidebar</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*2Ea3iO4_qa53KNz_-EYfrw.png" /><figcaption>Tools section</figcaption></figure><ul><li>Select “Keybase id”</li><li>Enter your Keybase username and Signature Hash into the fields, and send the transaction</li><li>Go check that it was successfully broadcast on our <a href="https://explorer.theqrl.org/">Explorer</a></li><li>Once it is visible on our explorer, head back to the QRL &lt;&gt;Keybase page and hit “Submit”</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*xL492bOyywS3WHmrBHvOsQ.png" /><figcaption>Now is the time to hit that button</figcaption></figure><p>Again, there are more detailed instructions in our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-and-keybase-84968003bca2">previous blog</a>, and if you have any questions, please do not hesitate to reach out to us on Twitter, Discord, or at <a href="mailto:support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a></p><h3>Community</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/810/1*tLgB0S7qRop_aCVogPLurQ.jpeg" /></figure><p>While we will use this space to highlight our Community Nomination Winner, to organize meetups, or preview upcoming conferences, we also want to use it to highlight when someone from our own community does something cool and relevant. One of our very own community members, Discord user dr_gonzo, attended the <a href="https://bcisummit.com/summit-2019.html">BCI Summit on May 10 in New York City</a>, whose <a href="https://bcisummit.com/agenda-S2019.html">agenda</a> included a panel on Quantum Computer’s Destruction of Security &amp; Blockchain.</p><p>The BCI Summit members and attendees consisted of major accredited investors and C-suite executives from some of the largest companies around the world, including IBM, Barclays, D-Wave, UBS, and more. The “Quantum Computer’s Destruction of Security &amp; Blockchain” panel consisted of industry heavyweights such as the Quantum Computing Lead for NASA, the head of Symantec Ventures, and a Researcher of Quantum Theory for IBM. While the panel focused primarily on alternative algorithms and mining, it also took questions, including one from dr_gonzo who asked about the vulnerability of ECDSA, and noted that projects like our very own QRL exist to address it.</p><p>It is increasingly clear that quantum computing, and the means to resist it on a cryptographic level, are becoming more mainstream topics for discussion. Major institutional players are waking up to the fundamental threat of quantum computing technology to other cryptocurrencies. Thanks to Discord users dr_gonzo for his attendance, and PQAdvantage for helping facilitate the opportunity.</p><p>We are always happy to hear about the wonderful things our community members are getting up to, and, where appropriate, are happy to highlight them in this space. Please feel free to reach out to us on Discord, Twitter, Reddit, or send an email with your cool story to <a href="mailto:adam@theqrl.org">adam@theqrl.org</a></p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=4f70f54e5333" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-may-7-13-4f70f54e5333">Last Week in QRL May 7–13</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[QRL and Keybase]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-and-keybase-84968003bca2?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/84968003bca2</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The QRL]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 14:07:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-05-13T14:07:18.362Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>A new integration</em></p><p>We’re big fans of what Keybase are doing here at the Quantum Resistant Ledger. Innovation and security are a big part of what we do and we are delighted to announce that you will shortly be able to add your QRL address to your Keybase identity.</p><h3>Keybase</h3><p><a href="https://keybase.io/">Keybase</a> is a catalog of connected identities that utilises cryptographic <em>Proofs</em> to link profiles.</p><h3>Adding QRL address to Keybase profile</h3><p>To add your QRL address to your Keybase profile, in the Keybase app click on the <em>Add more identities </em>button, and enter your QRL address. When you click the <em>Authorize</em> button you’ll be presented with a page like this:</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*9eoHOk0W4yn_9RpgSYfkTg.png" /></figure><p>This contains your Signature Hash, a cryptographic Proof, that needs recording in the QRL blockchain using our message transaction type. The easiest way to achieve this is using the new Keybase tools section of the QRL web wallet at <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org">wallet.theqrl.org</a> or the desktop version downloaded from theqrl.org or Github.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/194/1*2Bta9rl0b4TXk7Y8qOhG0w.png" /><figcaption>The tools icon in the sidebar</figcaption></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Fy_8fC2Ov3IN1YY8lwtLfQ.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*XRCbakDZpZgPg3tK_CN6hw.png" /></figure><p>Enter your keybase username, paste the Keybase signature hash into the box, and click <em>Create Keybase Transaction</em>. When the transaction is complete, you’ll see confirmation:</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*BFX8RX5Bc2zjYEkQcpAvLw.png" /></figure><p>Looking on the <a href="https://explorer.theqrl.org">Explorer</a> you’ll see a record of your Keybase message transaction:</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*f8I9jx0y1mu7zXmwasgmnw.png" /></figure><p>Once this is visible in the Explorer, you’re good to go back to the QRL/Keybase link page and click <em>Submit:</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*-OLYw_kpJY7whbACQ7MuFw.png" /></figure><p>Congratulations! Your QRL address should now be available on your Keybase profile page.</p><h3>What next?</h3><p>Identity is core to financial transactions, and we like how Keybase are approaching this. Going forward, we will be implementing sending via Keybase user ID into our web wallet software and within the explorer.</p><h3>Need help?</h3><p>Our Discord community is active, knowledgable and renowned as one of the best in the space: it’s usually the best place to get a quick answer to anything QRL-related.</p><p>We also have a team of our open-source contributors offering help by email at: support@theqrl.org.</p><p><strong>The QRL Team</strong></p><p><em>Acknowledgement: we’d like to thank the Keybase team for being brilliant to work with.</em></p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=84968003bca2" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-and-keybase-84968003bca2">QRL and Keybase</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[April Community Nomination Award]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/april-community-nomination-award-ac364919ff9f?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/ac364919ff9f</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 16:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-05-08T16:31:00.756Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As we noted in our most recent “Last Week in QRL” <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-april-30-may-6-c4aff5abf8d0">blog</a>, we had not yet received a statement from this month’s award recipient, so we held off on announcing them in our usual manner. Now, without further ado…</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*mxCu4J3xHZt-qgs1L62rHA.png" /></figure><p>We are pleased to announce that this month’s QRL Community Nomination Award goes to <a href="https://github.com/IMac318">GitHub user IMac318</a> (reddit handle: <a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Definitely_Not_IMac">Definitely_Not_IMac</a>)! Here’s what IMac318 had to tell us about themselves and their relationship to the QRL:</p><blockquote>I was someone who got into crypto during the December 2017 hype, because the idea of a trust-less, decentralized financial system seemed like a fascinating and revolutionary idea. Of course, a blockchain’s usefulness is entirely reliant on its security, and while Bitcoin and others seemed virtually impenetrable from classical computing attacks, my background in physics made me wonder how it would stand up to quantum computing attacks.</blockquote><blockquote>It didn’t take very much research to see that nearly all blockchains were vulnerable to quantum computers, but very few people in the space seemed to be aware of this. I figured that any crypto that was serious about being a long-term store of value should be taking this threat seriously, and QRL was the only team that was. Since joining the community, I’ve continued to see future-oriented decisions from the project’s leadership, and it has been exciting to see the progress that has been made in QRL ecosystem. I can’t wait to see what the future holds for this project!</blockquote><p>IMac318 has been a positive member of the QRL community for some time now, and is also the author of <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/tree/master/2.Proposals/1.%20Open/7%20-%20Support%20Tokenization%20of%20Securities">QIP-007: Support Tokenization of Securities</a>. As always, we <em>highly </em>encourage anyone with interest to <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/blob/master/README.md">check out how to submit a QIP</a>. It remains one of the most direct ways to contribute to the QRL ecosystem, as well as the most direct way to make your desires regarding the continued development of QRL known.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=ac364919ff9f" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/april-community-nomination-award-ac364919ff9f">April Community Nomination Award</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>