<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Cryptography with longevity. A post-quantum secure blockchain featuring a stateful signature scheme and unparalleled security. - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 01:16:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/the-quantum-resistant-ledger" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week at QRL: Jan 15th-21st]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-at-qrl-jan-15th-21st-7307be422bc9?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/7307be422bc9</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptobeadle]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-computing]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 20:40:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-01-21T20:40:45.405Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*AnwA9ARquAacQLl83cpbvg.png" /></figure><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*BEtsF7yj-LE0yQhaZkCpWw.jpeg" /></figure><h4>qrllib v1.0.4 (and v1.0.2, v1.0.3)</h4><p>QRL Lib v1.0.4 adds a build output from emscripten to instantiate the WebAssembly from base64 encoded qrllib: this allows for the use of qrllib in serverless environments (e.g. offline wallet generation). Which leads to the next advancement to the QRL ecosystem</p><h4>Offline Wallet Generator</h4><p>While it’s possible to generate a wallet <em>offline</em> with our current web and desktop wallets, an initial connection to a server is made. <em>Soon</em> it will be possible to load a few files (currently &lt;5 mb in size) on a USB Flash drive and generate wallets on an airgapped machine, negating the need to even instantiate a connection.</p><p>The work is done, it just needs to be cleaned up and put out for preliminary testing among our TestPilots (more below)</p><h4>QRL Mobile Wallet</h4><p>The QRL mobile wallet for iOS and Android has successfully gone through the initial round of community testing! As there were quite a few bugs squished and UI/UX improvements, there will be another round for our TestPilots to break in the coming week(s).</p><h4>QRL Faucet</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/846/1*i1zcVDZsvHVD0JQD7dgM4A.png" /></figure><p>The QRL Faucet, a <em>much</em>-requested feature, has been built! It has passed through an initial, internal test, and is currently undergoing additional, external testing from our group of community ‘TestPilots’ before being given wider release.</p><p>This faucet will function on both the test network and main network. It will issue tiny amounts of QRL in exchange for a brief browser PoW calculation, and is overall rate limited, to prevent over-eager users from draining the faucet balance too quickly. For those interested in seeing how our blockchain works, we hope that this will act as a pleasant introduction to our ecosystem.</p><h3>Community</h3><h4>QuantumFAQ/FAQQ Updates</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/788/1*IeGSNUriu2SgAYHGOnMfmA.png" /></figure><p>As we covered in our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-jan-7-jan-14-2019-aba7bb87dd38">last blog</a>, QuantumFAQ is an initiative to collect, articulate, and easily reference common misconceptions people have about blockchain and quantum computing.</p><p>One of the first changes was a name-change from QuantumFAQ to FAQQ (Frequently asked quantum questions) which was suggested by the community and voted in by a landslide. This means it also lives in a slightly different location: <a href="https://jackalyst.github.io/faqq/">https://jackalyst.github.io/faqq/</a></p><p>Other changes are:</p><ul><li>A “Footnotes” section so that all of our statements are sourced.</li><li>Separation between assertive statement FAQ’s and FAQ’s that’s geared towards misconceptions &amp; clarifications: “Quantum computers are coming” vs “Bitcoin will just hardfork”</li><li>A better table of contents that should be more effective at guiding people.</li></ul><p>There is still a lot of work to do filling things out and getting the language top notch but continuous progress is being made. If you see any errors, or if there are any misconceptions you would like to see covered, let us know through one of our channels!</p><p>As a note, FAQ’s that pertain to QRL will still live at <a href="https://theqrl.org/faq/">https://theqrl.org/faq/</a>. FAQQ is more of a community initiative geared towards Quantum Computing and Blockchain in general.</p><h4>The QRL TestPilot Program</h4><p>We now have a test pilot program! This is a <strong><em>discord only</em></strong> program and involves being part of the initial round of testing of a variety things before they go out to the wider community.</p><p>The general release overview is:</p><ol><li>Development/production</li><li>QRL Team Review (Round 1, 2, …): Catches initial show stopping bugs and reveals possible security considerations.</li><li><strong>QRL Test Pilot Review (Round 1, 2, …): Catches more show stopping bugs through device variability. Also highlights user interaction issues.</strong></li><li>Where applicable, a 3rd party audit.</li><li>General Release.</li></ol><p>While right now there are 7 excellent people that’s part of the test pilot program, and we’d like to expand this to achieve more test coverage.</p><p>If you’re interested please fill out our lovely google form: <a href="https://goo.gl/forms/BCFM1RYUC4S6DrCz1">https://goo.gl/forms/BCFM1RYUC4S6DrCz1</a></p><h4>December Community Award — 0xFF</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*S_9FKunWUpeukHCUbYeRHQ.png" /></figure><p>Our community award goes to 0xFF for contributing to community spirit with excellent puzzles, and for helping to spearhead a larger puzzle initiative that will be announced in the future.</p><h3>In the media</h3><iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FPKe6Q6bIl7k%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DPKe6Q6bIl7k&amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FPKe6Q6bIl7k%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;key=a19fcc184b9711e1b4764040d3dc5c07&amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;schema=youtube" width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><a href="https://medium.com/media/4b79dd45198d2fbaf9ea38c92e0a5386/href">https://medium.com/media/4b79dd45198d2fbaf9ea38c92e0a5386/href</a></iframe><p>Adam Koltun had a productive interview with the folks over at CryptoBeadles that went live this past week. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCcE2GkGcKxHjZoMVM7tjmyA">CryptoBeadles is a YouTube channel</a> with over 70,000 subscribers, dozens of videos, and has been covering the blockchain/cryptocurrency scene since 2017. Adam was able to talk about QRL in an accessible, down-to-earth manner, and we can safely assume that a number of people were hearing about QRL for the first time during this interview.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=7307be422bc9" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-at-qrl-jan-15th-21st-7307be422bc9">Last Week at QRL: Jan 15th-21st</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ledger App Update!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-app-update-eb89bcc5e657?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/eb89bcc5e657</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-s]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledgerwallet]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:30:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-01-18T00:30:17.306Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR — Ledger app is complete, awaiting final review. Automatic migration will close 3 months after Ledger app goes live. Instructional video on YouTube. More tech details to follow in a later blog.</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*cQFoUJ7L0whRF8SFLYvXyw.png" /></figure><h3>Development Progress</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*mE3FbEKaBZFMc6hVNv_TbQ.jpeg" /></figure><p>As we have previously communicated, the development of the Ledger app is complete. All that remains now is for Ledger to internally review it, give it their stamp of approval, and add our application to the list of approved applications for Ledger hardware.</p><p>We do not have any specific dates or timelines available to us, but rest assured that as soon as we have any actionable knowledge, we will share that on all social media (and probably write a blog about it as well).</p><p>More detailed information of everything that went into the development of this app will be forthcoming in a blog by our own developer Scott Donald.</p><h3>Automatic Migration</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/960/1*IEvy90uMhHVDz6y4Ywwe0Q.jpeg" /></figure><p>We are aware that there are many in the community that have been waiting on the completion and deployment of the Ledger application before migrating their ERC20s. As Ledger goes, so they go.</p><p>With that in mind, we have decided to peg the closure of the <a href="https://migration.theqrl.org/">automatic token migration app</a> to the launch of the Ledger app, as to do otherwise would run the risk of people who were waiting for Ledger not being able to access automatic migration if they wished. <strong>The automatic token migration app will be closed 3 months after the launch of the Ledger app.</strong></p><p>As we have stated previously, <strong>even after automatic token migration closes, users will still be able to migrate their coins.</strong> The migration will no longer be <em>automatic</em>, but it will still be <em>possible</em>. This ensures greater oversight and security of the later migrations, without leaving anyone out in the cold that ends up wanting to migrate their ERC20s into mainnet Quanta at a later date.</p><h3>How To Video</h3><iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FNL_u9biLy1g%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DNL_u9biLy1g&amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FNL_u9biLy1g%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;key=a19fcc184b9711e1b4764040d3dc5c07&amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;schema=youtube" width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><a href="https://medium.com/media/43eaedbd6040b4e280addd9df5a4279e/href">https://medium.com/media/43eaedbd6040b4e280addd9df5a4279e/href</a></iframe><p>The above video was recorded by QRL’s own Scott Donald, and shows how one can easily access their wallet and move funds using their Ledger Nano. We wanted to provide users with this information ahead of time, so that when the application goes live on Ledger, there is no gap waiting for instructions.</p><p>We know that Ledger integration has been a top priority for a portion of our community since before we even launched the blockchain. We are very excited at how close we are to being able to say that the Ledger application is functional, live, and available.</p><p>Thank you for your patience.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=eb89bcc5e657" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-app-update-eb89bcc5e657">Ledger App Update!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL: Jan 7 — Jan 14, 2019]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-jan-7-jan-14-2019-aba7bb87dd38?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/aba7bb87dd38</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 21:00:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-01-14T21:00:40.032Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL: Jan 7 — Jan 14, 2019</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*8Y6iR9cQr9tiO-NTYciuuQ.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>After a few abnormal weeks and multiple-week blogs, we are back on our weekly blogging schedule (for now). As always, the length and presentation of these blogs will adjust slightly as the content changes (not all weeks are equally dense in terms of sharable developments).</p><h3>Development Updates</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*g6BbCqnh8GLL-k00cwZwcg.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li>Support for MongoDB Processor in GO-QRL has almost finished, including fork recovery.</li><li>Unit tests for MongoDB have been 80% completed.</li><li>Added <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/developers/knownIssues/">known issues section</a> to documentation site.</li><li>QuantumFAQ site coming (more on that below)</li></ul><h3>QuantumFAQ site</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*7OWx6YmB6TOWSp30ls6DHg.gif" /></figure><p>Those in the community will know the very common responses that come up when speaking to people in the wider cryptocurrency community about Quantum Computing — and maybe they have had these questions themselves.</p><p><a href="https://jackalyst.github.com/quantumfaq/">QuantumFAQ</a> is a site (in alpha) designed as a resource to be linked to and confidently digested with the attention span people have today (seconds). Common responses will be curated underneath to guide people through their curiosities, where all answers should be satisfied in no more than 2 minutes of time. Other thoughts in the future involve more predictive responses and links to more resources.</p><p>The site can be reached at: <a href="https://jackalyst.github.com/quantumfaq/">https://jackalyst.github.com/quantumfaq/</a></p><p>Github repository: <a href="https://github.com/jackalyst/quantumfaq">https://github.com/jackalyst/quantumfaq</a></p><h3>Marketing/Outreach Updates</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/254/1*W0GO5jefz7RKjq84rpaEcw.png" /><figcaption>What a marketing job sometimes feels like</figcaption></figure><p>With the holidays and the start of the new year, we have been hard at work reaching out across the industry to try and spread the good word of QRL. We had an interview this past week that had to be rescheduled, but when it eventually takes place we think it might offer something slightly different from our normal interview fare.</p><p>We were approached by a well-known financial technology publication to give quotes regarding quantum computers. We submitted our quotes, and are hoping to be able to show them off to you in the coming days/weeks as a part of an article they are creating. Stay tuned!</p><h3>Liquidity Update</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/400/1*KDYO4etAzPDSLtuktvKeVA.gif" /></figure><p>On March 1st, Coinexchange.io will be delisting the QRL ERC20 token from its markets. CoinExchange never migrated the few ERC20s on its platform, so it is in possession of 0 mainnet Quanta.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*1fMKxI33etl-6R2xjHeJDg.png" /><figcaption>Statement on CoinExchange’s delisting page</figcaption></figure><h3>Community Updates</h3><p>As we’ve stated <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-s-in-qrl-december-4th-17th-2018-e7f744845075">previously</a>, we have changed format for the Community Nominations, and will now be conducting them <em>monthly</em>, for a prize of 750 Quanta. We expect to have our first winner announced in the next “Last Week in QRL” blog.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=aba7bb87dd38" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-jan-7-jan-14-2019-aba7bb87dd38">Last Week in QRL: Jan 7 — Jan 14, 2019</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No, IBM’s Quantum Computer won’t break Bitcoin, but we should be prepared for one that can.]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/no-ibms-quantum-computer-won-t-break-bitcoin-but-we-should-be-prepared-for-one-that-can-cc3e178ebff0?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/cc3e178ebff0</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-computing]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ibm]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 19:25:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-01-15T15:08:28.364Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Quantum computing that can break blockchain is coming, and it’s time the blockchain community accepts it — so we can prepare ourselves.</h4><p>The Verge said it best with “<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/8/18171732/ibm-quantum-computer-20-qubit-q-system-one-ces-2019">IBM’s new quantum computer is a symbol, not a breakthrough.</a>”. It’s important to expand on that and what it means to Bitcoin, and blockchain in general. What we <em>shouldn’t</em> do is turn a blind eye.</p><h3>Contents</h3><ul><li><a href="#aea9">Primer</a></li><li><a href="#8931">IBM’s Commercial Quantum Computer</a></li><li><a href="#1a57">When do we need to worry, anyway?</a></li><li><a href="#8b16">The importance of preparation</a></li></ul><h3>Primer</h3><p>Anytime there’s an advancement in Quantum Computing, like <a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/tech-talk/computing/hardware/intels-49qubit-chip-aims-for-quantum-supremacy">Intel’s 49 qubit chip at <em>last year’s</em> 2018 CES show</a>, or this years CES show with <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/8/18171732/ibm-quantum-computer-20-qubit-q-system-one-ces-2019">IBM’s 20 qubit commercial quantum computer</a>, blockchain news outlets are always there to assuage worries, with <strong>“No, [<em>this</em>] Quantum Computer won’t break bitcoin”</strong>, often accompanied by the sentiment that the looming quantum computing threat is being blown right out of proportion.</p><p>What they usually fail to note is that, once again, quantum computing is passing metrics ahead of schedule. Previously quantum computing was relegated to something that would not reach a commercial application until the mid to late-2020s. That is not to say quantum computers have only ever outpaced expectations, but rather to contextualise the strength of today’s quantum computers not just against a static metric of being able to break ECDSA, but also a development curve.</p><p>While it is <em>true </em>that IBM’s commercial quantum computer won&#39;t break Bitcoin, this is <strong>not</strong> the mindset we want to have with the underlying cryptographic fundamentals of something that underpins <em>billions</em> of dollars worth of value (in just cryptocurrency alone)— and hopefully <strong><em>much</em></strong> more in the future.</p><p>To put a visual metaphor to waiting until it’s too late: A ballistic may not penetrate your fortress today, one will someday, <em>a thought secured by recent developments, </em>makes it<em> </em>prudent to fortify sooner and be <em>proactive</em>, rather than <em>reactive</em>. Being <em>reactive</em> means your fortress will be compromised, or in the case of blockchain, your private keys stolen, and what’s the point of fortifying then?</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/498/1*ehnsou-cfieKcYyPi0niDA.gif" /></figure><p>In this way, the frame of the conversation needs be proactive, rather than reactive. Decentralized networks, by their very nature, are censorship resistant, and while that means many wonderful things for end-users generally, in terms of security it means that it can be very difficult/impossible to functionally undo transactions. Therefore, we cannot afford to be <em>reactive</em>, we must be <em>proactive</em> in order to meaningfully prevent negative, irreversible security outcomes.</p><h3>IBM’s Commercial Quantum Computer</h3><p>At CES, <a href="https://newsroom.ibm.com/2019-01-08-IBM-Unveils-Worlds-First-Integrated-Quantum-Computing-System-for-Commercial-Use#assets_115:1612">IBM announced a commercialised version</a> of its 20 qubit computer which could be shipped out to institutions and businesses looking to start building on real quantum computers.</p><h4>How powerful is it?</h4><p>Unlike bits on your computer which are binary and scale linearly, qubits scale exponentially, which means that every qubit added to a system doubles its computational power. For a 20-qubit system, we’re looking at 2²⁰. To give some context, this is something that your average powered notebook can simulate perfectly well and is exactly what Microsoft does for its <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/quantum/development-kit">Quantum Development Kit</a>. The breakdown is:</p><ul><li>2²⁰ Laptop: Commercially, we’re here!</li><li>2³⁰ Desktop</li><li>2⁴⁰ Cloud compute service (For Microsoft, this is Azure)</li></ul><h4>If it’s not so powerful yet, who is it for?</h4><p>IBM’s commercial quantum computer is demonstration that they can produce a <em>reliable</em>, upgrade-able commercial quantum computer. Clients who purchase a 20-qubit system today, could upgrade their systems down the line, having already familiarised themselves with IBM’s commercial quantum computer. This would appeal to researchers in particular, as having a QC on-hand would increase uptime for experiments, and help decrease system downtime.</p><h4>What does this mean for blockchain</h4><p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/8/18171732/ibm-quantum-computer-20-qubit-q-system-one-ces-2019">As aptly penned by The Verge</a>, this is a symbolic development to mean that NISQ era quantum computers are here, commercialised, <em>today</em>, and with <a href="https://newsroom.intel.com/press-kits/quantum-computing/">Intel</a>, <a href="https://www.research.ibm.com/ibm-q/">IBM</a>, <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-ca/quantum/">Microsoft</a>, <a href="https://ai.google/research/teams/applied-science/quantum-ai/">Google</a>, <a href="https://newsroom.intel.com/tag/quantum-computing/">Intel</a>, <a href="https://www.lockheedmartin.ca/ca/what-we-do/emerging-technologies/quantum-computing.html">Lockheed Martin</a>, <a href="https://www.rigetti.com/">Rigetti</a>, and <a href="https://quantumcomputingreport.com/players/public-companies/">more</a>, all in the ring competing, it’s clearly not <em>just</em> in the lab.</p><p>The blockchain community needs to accept that quantum computers are here, today. While the timeline for when they can threaten blockchain security is uncertain, <em>whether</em> that day will come is no longer a matter of debate. No one wants to see a catastrophic event where large swaths of the cryptocurrency ecosystem is wiped out, but that is sadly a possibility if we do not act in a timely manner.</p><h3>When do we need to worry, anyway?</h3><p>This isn’t an easy thing to answer, but working off of our “how many qubits” list from above we can expand on it and get a number to run Shor’s algorithm.</p><ul><li>2⁵⁰ Average supercomputer: We have already passed this! Currently, the largest stable QC in the world is 2⁷²</li><li>2⁸⁰ Quantum Supremacy: Quantum Computers are faster than the fastest supercomputer with a synthetic test. A milestone Microsoft is anticipating to pass this year.</li><li>2³⁰⁰⁰ Quantum Computers can run Shor’s algorithm: Shor’s can break ECDSA 256 (what Bitcoin uses): <strong>We want to upgrade <em>well</em> before this point.</strong></li></ul><p>Looking back, we can take the development trajectory of the number of qubits a system has had over the last 4 years and attempt to extrapolate:</p><ul><li>2015: 4-qubits</li><li>2016: 9-qubits (IBM)</li><li>2017: 17-qubits (Intel), 50-qubits (IBM)</li><li>2018: 49-qubits (Intel), 72-qubits (Google)</li></ul><p>This indicates a 5.5x/1yr — 18x/4yr increase, or, assuming a similar trajectory, it will be between 2.2 and 5.3 years until we hit 3000 qubits. However, there is more work to do than just stacking up qubits. There is the lingering issue of error-correction, which currently stands as a barrier to proper, accurate calculations. There is also the issue of scaling, which is being addressed in a number of ways, but has not been solved.</p><p>On the other side, Shor’s Algorithm is merely the first quantum algorithm to usher in an interest in quantum computing. There continue to be advances towards breaking Elliptic Curve Cryptography on a variety of levels through newer, more efficient algorithms that can <a href="https://quantumcomputingreport.com/news/zapata-develops-potential-alternative-to-shors-factoring-algorithm-for-nisq-quantum-computers/">run on our non error-corrected quantum computers.</a></p><p>Those are pretty big variables, which is why you’ll see everything from 2 to 30 years before ECDSA P-256 is broken. In some ways this range doesn’t matter, <em>but there’s no question</em> that we want to have everything secure well ahead of it.</p><h3>The importance of preparation</h3><p>If you’ve ever dealt with keeping systems secure in any capacity, it’s important to keep up to date. Generally, this means following Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE) notices and other security bulletins, and checking to see the state of your hash functions and cipher suites.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*qGNmQ9d_Xw_Tnat1Hs0xDQ.png" /></figure><p>What becomes very evident over time is that not everything lasts forever. You harden your systems, and others find ways to weaken them. The cryptographic methods you used as a kid just aren’t going to cut it today. One signature scheme that’s held out for a <em>remarkably </em>long time is ECDSA.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*zwpeoTZ5o9iHdsPgkp6liQ.png" /><figcaption>Looking at the chart, we’re somewhere around “Minor weakness discovered” and “Serious weakness discovered”</figcaption></figure><p>This is the cadence security and cryptography has had for thousands of years since the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caesar_cipher">Ceasar cipher</a> and continues to have to this day. Some would say it’s echoed in the fabric of nature itself between parasites and hosts.</p><h4>Proactive blockchain design for an adversarial future</h4><p>Proactive security is a core value for The QRL — something we think should be of paramount importance for any network that caries substantial value.</p><p>We are using XMSS as recommended by <a href="https://pqcrypto.org">pqcrypto</a> to secure our accounts and transactions. XMSS gives complete peace of mind from the emerging black swan of quantum computing, with reusable addresses, provable security and minimal security assumptions.</p><p>This is a <em>proactive</em> step against Quantum Computing, but as the cadence goes, it’s important to be proactive against new developments as well, some which may be harder to predict.</p><p>We went to great lengths to <em>also</em> design a foundation that allows for variable key heights and signature space to ensure compatibility with potential new cryptographic schemes that may be developed in the future. Our blockchain includes the possibility to upgrade signature schemes (XMSS, SPHINCS, + future) and through an address format update, support different cryptographic hash functions (SHA2_256, SHAKE_128, SHAKE256 etc). You can read more about on <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/developers/address/">our documentation</a> site.</p><p>We hope that blogs like these help illuminate some of the complicated relationship between blockchain and quantum computers. We know that we must act as an educator in this space, and are happy to rise to the occasion.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=cc3e178ebff0" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/no-ibms-quantum-computer-won-t-break-bitcoin-but-we-should-be-prepared-for-one-that-can-cc3e178ebff0">No, IBM’s Quantum Computer won’t break Bitcoin, but we should be prepared for one that can.</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week(s) at QRL: Dec 18–Jan 6]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-s-at-qrl-dec-18-jan-6-87f2b17c8c94?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/87f2b17c8c94</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledgerwallet]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 18:16:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-01-08T18:16:13.246Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*OGirdELd8Xkc8YjwCbAVOw.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>It has been a little while since our last “Last Week in QRL” blog. So in honour of this being the first blog of 2019, “Happy New Year!”</p><p>Obviously this blog will have closer to just one week’s worth of content in it, despite covering two weeks, as both Christmas (check out our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/12-days-of-xmass-e787fd958d2c">12 days of XMaSS blog</a>) and New Year’s occurred during those weeks. As always, life in a startup project can be very hectic, and everyone enjoyed the opportunity to be able to spend some quality time with their families, and perhaps reflect upon the past year.</p><p>As we have stated elsewhere, 2018 was obviously a disappointing year across the cryptocurrency market, in terms of price. However, we believe that both within our project, and across the wider blockchain ecosystem, that some very important and meaningful work has been completed this year. 2018 saw QRL go from an ERC20 to a fully-realised, fully-functional blockchain network. The close of 2018 had QRL as a mineable PoW coin, with liquidity secured, robust documentation and API sites, and many exciting features on the horizon. Given where we were at the start of 2018, we cannot help but look at it as a success.</p><p>Hopefully, as time goes on, the overall prices across the blockchain ecosystem begin to more meaningfully reflect the hard work and real progress being made behind the scenes.</p><h3>GO-QRL</h3><p>Go-QRL has been running stable for around a month now running QRL mainnet. While stable, there’s still components required to bring it up to feature parity with the Python implementation — and beyond. Over the holidays, Kaushal continued his perseverance and added a Public API, makefile support, with a new JSON-based backend infrastructure in progress.</p><p>The JSON-based backend will make it easier for people to interact with the API without requiring the setup and maintenance of our wallet daemon, walletd.</p><h3>Block Explorer</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/488/1*v1io_xyLgIhMdT1dkrhdEw.gif" /><figcaption>Dark and Light Theme</figcaption></figure><p>From the outset, we at QRL have recognised that a piece of software is only as good as the user’s ability to utilise it. To that end, we have never stopped making improvements to our UI/UX. The latest of these improvements, adding a dark theme to our wallet and block explorer, have been another step in that process. This was met with much applause, and some disdain from the community lamenting the disappearance of a light theme.</p><p>Based on this feedback, as the above GIF should show, the <a href="https://explorer.theqrl.org/">QRL Block Explorer</a> will soon have a button to toggle the theme from Light to Dark, and vice versa. We believe this will help make our block explorer experience more pleasant and useful.</p><h3>Mobile Wallet Testing</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*_1tj04T7JUzIsbu7DvkpQA.png" /></figure><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-s-in-qrl-december-4th-17th-2018-e7f744845075">When we last checked in</a> on our mobile app on iOS and Android, we were finishing up internal testing and getting ready to move on to a first round of testing to a select group in the community.</p><p>We are happy to report that this has taken place, and that the testing so far has been both productive and encouraging. We recognise that a mobile wallet app is an element that, along with the release of our Ledger app, many in our community have been waiting for.</p><p>After some fixes and tweaks take place, we’ll be opening this up to the wider community to test in the next few weeks.</p><h3>Ledger Nano S</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/971/1*JOUTMbvrI1VFrYGMi7E4HQ.png" /></figure><p>Speaking of the Ledger App, we have more news. As we stated in our previous “Last Week” blog, we had a release-candidate version of the Ledger app up on our GitHub.</p><p><strong><em>We can now say that we have entirely completed the Ledger integration, and are now awaiting only a full and thorough review from the Ledger team themselves</em></strong>, before the app should be ready for release. Integrating with quality hardware like that which Ledger produces represents a significant achievement on the part of the development team, and we are all very proud of the hard work and long hours it has taken to get to being on this precipice of its materialisation.</p><p>Scott Donald has studiously put together a tech demonstration on how the wallet and the Ledger Nano S works harmonistically together.</p><iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FNL_u9biLy1g%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DNL_u9biLy1g&amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FNL_u9biLy1g%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;key=a19fcc184b9711e1b4764040d3dc5c07&amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;schema=youtube" width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><a href="https://medium.com/media/43eaedbd6040b4e280addd9df5a4279e/href">https://medium.com/media/43eaedbd6040b4e280addd9df5a4279e/href</a></iframe><h4>Ledger Nano X</h4><p>After 1.5 million devices sold, the Ledger team announced the Ledger Nano X, which you can read more about <a href="https://www.ledger.com/pages/ledger-nano-x">here</a>.</p><p>To answer the inevitable question early on as to whether QRL will work on the Ledger Nano X, the answer is the device will work on the QRL wallet, but there’s more work to enable it on the Ledger mobile and desktop apps. We will have more information on this in a separate, Ledger-specific blog.</p><p>Of course, this means more toys for the developers to play with!</p><h3>Confirmed for DeveloperWeek 2019</h3><p>Adam Koltun will be speaking at <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/">DeveloperWeek 2019</a> in Oakland, California on February 20th, at the Oakland Convention Center. <a href="https://developerweek2019.sched.com/speaker/adam_koltun.1yz9ak9c">Link to his speaker bio</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=87f2b17c8c94" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-s-at-qrl-dec-18-jan-6-87f2b17c8c94">Last Week(s) at QRL: Dec 18–Jan 6</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[12 Days of XMaSS]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/12-days-of-xmass-e787fd958d2c?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/e787fd958d2c</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[xmss]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[12-days-of-christmas]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 19:44:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-12-24T19:44:22.044Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR — This is a cheerful, jovial blog meant to take a fun, non-serious look at where the project is at as 2018 comes to a close, but mostly to have some festive fun before the end of the year. Enjoy!</em></p><p>On the first day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>A private key in an (extended) Merkle Tree</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/728/1*-m3M7AyBdz8OQrSUatYVNw.png" /></figure><p>On the second day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>Two Separate Audits</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/599/1*GaVAZkT7xXayfq54ijcSBg.png" /></figure><p>On the third day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><a href="https://theqrl.org/"><strong>Three Different Desktop Wallets</strong></a></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*cakH5GpAQ39JhfnY_vPGhw.jpeg" /></figure><p>On the fourth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me <br><strong>4k Discord Members</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/811/1*se_sPGWwewD6PGzLHo8b8Q.png" /></figure><p>n the fifth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong> 5 Community Members Nominated</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*rC1VxV2hR2aWKkeWGXkJIA.png" /></figure><p>On the sixth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me <br><strong>6 QRL Block Reward</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*_NZ25cqH3Be67uZ920dHug.png" /></figure><p>On the seventh day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>7 Podcast Interviews</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/539/1*cnW4-roIbNHsFwVW07f95A.jpeg" /></figure><p>On the eighth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>8 Presentations Given</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1018/1*YJEsFeL0uuCTq02mIt7T0A.png" /></figure><p>On the ninth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>9 Whitepaper Translations</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/472/1*XndAzJRLUNypXvzznvuZGw.jpeg" /></figure><p>On the tenth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>10 QRL Developers</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ZsLRt1UHh56lG2syshBGFg.jpeg" /></figure><p>On the eleventh day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>11 Conferences Attended</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/768/1*lrlKw5OqQlHg8tVeS2tgkw.png" /></figure><p>On the twelfth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>12+ Team Members!</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/780/1*VNnreXNsnpUaAN-3zMP21Q.png" /></figure><h3>See you all next year!</h3><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=e787fd958d2c" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/12-days-of-xmass-e787fd958d2c">12 Days of XMaSS</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last week(s) in QRL: December 4th — 17th, 2018]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-s-in-qrl-december-4th-17th-2018-e7f744845075?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/e7f744845075</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[last-week-in-qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:54:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-12-18T00:54:55.330Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*BT-HSmeZOIkEl8DbZVI-Nw.png" /></figure><h3>Last Week(s) in QRL: December 4th — 17th, 2018</h3><h3>Ledger Nano S</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*Kv7G47q3znR9TZ4zemMHVQ.jpeg" /></figure><p>We are happy to report that the Ledger app is complete! We just need the web integration to be finished, and testing to commence, before we call ledger-qrl-js v1.0.0 ready for a full release. We will probably have a pre-release version of the app up on our GitHub before New Year’s Eve, for those who cannot wait and want to see our Ledger app in action ASAP.</p><p>We know how long many of you in the community have been waiting for this; it is close to being completely ready!</p><h3>Mobile app</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*klBbafDPyPTSXB3pJiULfw.png" /></figure><p>Mobile app is passing internal testing and should be going out to a hand-picked cohort of community members to do the first round of testing soon for iOS and Android users.</p><p>Features include:</p><ul><li>Transferring a wallet from the desktop to mobile through QR hexseed scanning</li><li>PIN security</li><li>Multiple wallets</li><li>Sending to QR Code address</li><li>Receiving with a QR Code address</li><li>Seeing a history of transactions</li></ul><h3>API &amp; documentation</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*awrKfdtjTwDU-KZ6DWYK9A.png" /><figcaption><a href="https://api.theqrl.org/#qrl-api">https://api.theqrl.org/#qrl-api</a></figcaption></figure><p>New updates to gettotalbalance as a request from upbit is in place. Go-client documentation is in process to help facilitate community testing and those to want to run our <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/go-qrl">go-lang QRL node</a>.</p><h3>Cryptoblockcon</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*6f9_bfwjzuJMR4kN1C7j8g.png" /></figure><p>Jack Matier and Adam Koltun were at <a href="https://www.cryptoblockcon.com/">CryptoBlockCon</a> in Las Vegas, Nevada this week on the 11th and 12th. You can read more about it on the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/crypto-block-conference-this-week-1a8f4d1d0cc4">blog penned by Adam Koltun</a>. But to briefly review; this was the 11th conference attended by QRL this year. QRL name recognition much higher than at start of 2018. Presentation was given on the 2nd day of the conference, video can be found <a href="https://youtu.be/G7K5REE152w">here</a>. CBC was our last conference of 2018.</p><h3>QIP-1 (to CNv1 or CNv2, that is the question)</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/750/1*dhlNj5gdbpQ9vexXD-49hg.jpeg" /></figure><p>Consensus of the team is that migration at this point would not be in the best interests of the project at this time. Reasons cited include:</p><ul><li>It would take time out of progress on other aspects of QRL, including PoS/Consensus upgrade.</li><li>Every consensus upgrade involves backwards portability, meaning support for the life of the project.</li><li>Whether or not ASICS help or hinder the security of a network is still a hot topic with no clear consensus in either direction, as far as security is concerned.</li><li>There’s no firm evidence that there are ASICS in the wild, many of the claims surrounding it are conjecture.</li></ul><p>As this was a discussion technical in nature, we didn’t open the vote up to the public,<strong> QIP-1 has therefore been closed</strong>, though not without some amazing (and respectful) discussion on both sides! You can read the discourse <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/pull/2">here</a>. As with all technical matters, should to context meaningfully change we would be open to resuming discussion with the new context in mind.</p><h3>Nominations</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*DvAHSmqbjjes08TtT8C3Uw.png" /></figure><p>Nominations will be moved from weekly to monthly events with an increased award from 250 Quanta to 750 Quanta. This will be started immediately with the first award being announced by the end of January, 2019.</p><p>However, to wrap up the last two weeks of our Community Nominations we have discord users qrl_dude and Cryptographic for their contributions, insight, and thoughts.</p><h3>Explorer dark mode</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*B3AdBDdKJ3_Y1PGAKYCYjA.png" /></figure><p>JP Lomas has been at work putting together a dark mode to the QRL Explorer, which is currently being implemented and test in devnet, let us know what you think. To note, dark mode would be a <em>new</em> mode and not something available by toggling.</p><p>In addition to this, there will be a select few json methods available in the future available via REST (and curl) requests for easily parsing of data.</p><h3><strong>Bittrex</strong></h3><p>In case it was missed, Bittrex has finished it’s migration of QRL ERC20 tokens to QRL’s mainnet Quanta. This establishes proper liquidity for the QRL ecosystem.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=e7f744845075" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-s-in-qrl-december-4th-17th-2018-e7f744845075">Last week(s) in QRL: December 4th — 17th, 2018</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bittrex Exchange Migration Complete!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/bittrex-exchange-migration-complete-fab674992588?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/fab674992588</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[bittrex]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 22:51:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-12-17T22:51:58.939Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*1QW-t_bHtK3cEonGUQjcEg.png" /></figure><p>We are delighted to announce that <a href="https://bittrex.com"><strong>Bittrex</strong></a> has successfully migrated the QRL ERC20s in their possession and that all QRL markets on Bittrex are now trading the mineable, main network Quanta (while still maintaining the $QRL ticker). Link to <a href="https://bittrex.com/Market/Index?MarketName=BTC-QRL">QRL-BTC Bittrex market</a>.</p><p>As we stated in our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/bittrex-exchange-migration-proper-liquidity-secured-for-the-qrl-df41045497e3">announcement blog</a>, the entire QRL team would like to thank the team at Bittrex for working closely with us to ensure this smooth transition.</p><p>As a reminder The QRL is the first fully post-quantum blockchain ecosystem designed from the ground up with a core of:</p><ul><li>multiple implementations for qrl node (python, go)</li><li>desktop GUI wallet (mac, windows, linux)</li><li>a fantastic <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org/">web-wallet</a> with built in features such as document notarisation and full token support</li><li>CLI Wallet</li><li>our trusty web e<a href="https://explorer.theqrl.org/">xplorer</a></li><li>growing <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org">documentation</a></li><li><a href="https://api.theqrl.org">API</a> — we are easy to build into!</li></ul><h3>Migration deadline</h3><p>Reminder: We have set a deadline (contingent on Ledger release of version 1.5) for <strong>28th February 2019 </strong>for when we will close our automated migration <a href="http://migration.theqrl.org">portal</a>. If you would like to know how to migrate using the current system, we have a handy how-to video on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3YxjMZGxm7A">YouTube</a>. For further help on this process you can always contact the team via <a href="http://support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a> or discuss with the team on <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">Discord</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=fab674992588" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/bittrex-exchange-migration-complete-fab674992588">Bittrex Exchange Migration Complete!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reflecting on CBC 2018]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-cbc-2018-2f039b4b6f8d?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/2f039b4b6f8d</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptoblockcon]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[conference]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 21:39:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-12-17T23:13:19.718Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR — Was in Las Vegas last week with Jack for the Crypto Blockchain Conference</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*6iCdt_MWNmIeO4eN1Ai3GQ.png" /></figure><h3>Met Jack!</h3><p>Last week, Jack and I attended <a href="https://www.cryptoblockcon.com/">CryptoBlockCon</a>. This was my first time working in person with Jack (bringing my total number of QRL team members met to 8, only a few more to go!), and I have to say, while Canadians are supposed to be polite, it is always more impressive in person.</p><h3>Blockchain In The Wider World</h3><p>The event was held at the <a href="https://www.mandalaybay.com/en.html">Mandalay Bay</a> Resort and Casino. In addition to CBC, the <a href="http://www.milb.com/milb/events/winter_meetings/y2018/agenda_events.jsp">MLB Winter Meetings</a>, and a <a href="https://www.nfrexperience.com/">National Finals Rodeo</a> competition was being held nearby, so many of the competitors were staying at Mandalay Bay. Certainly, literal cowboys, baseball executives and blockchain enthusiasts rubbing shoulders made for some interesting juxtapositions. As much as those of us within the industry can sometimes get weary of terms like “adoption” or “mainstream” or “awareness” — moments like these serve as an eloquent reminder, to me, that blockchain/cryptocurrency are still completely unknown to large swaths of American society, at least. It’s useful, I find, to sometimes recognize that for all the drama this space can sometimes produce, that in the long-run, these are minor speedbumps that will be hardly (if at all) remembered by the vast majority of crypto users within the next 10 years.</p><h3>Spreading The Word</h3><p>On the first day of the conference, I sat for an interview with <a href="https://coinstructive.com/category/lab-radio/">LAB Radio</a>, of <a href="https://coinstructive.com/">Coinstructive Consulting</a>. The interview went very well, though at the end of it we discovered that the camera had filled up its memory card part-way through. However, I believe all the audio was salvaged, so it is possible that interview will come out as audio-only. We will tweet out the link to that interview when it is available to us. It was an enjoyable interview, and I am very happy it was not entirely sacrificed to the gods of technological variance.</p><p>Met some individuals who are attempting to help inform the blockchain community more accurately and easily, something in sore need of in this space. <a href="https://blockchainweekly.net/">Blockchain Weekly</a> is, as the name implies, a weekly newsletter delivering various blockchain and cryptocurrency related links, videos, and articles. I cannot wait until there is true, comprehensive coverage of this industry in a reliable and accurate manner. Or at least until there is sufficient competition as to make that a plausible situation. As is, mediocre outlets with no interest in follow-up or fact-checking dominate the space, and sow confusion with every inaccuracy they publish, or quasi-accuracy they fail to properly vet.</p><h3>Made An Impression</h3><p>Over the past year, my speaking times, circumstances, and indeed my presentation itself has shifted and mutated as needed. This time, my speaking slot was at the very end of the last day of the conference. Now, while it might be nice to close out a music festival, functionally closing out a conference is a different matter altogether. After a few long days inside an at-times labyrinthine building like the Mandalay Bay Resort and Casino (which was made more confusing by 3 separate conferences all being held inside it at once), people are tired. To be blunt; speaking first or last on the last day of a conference can be tough — people are tired, they may have already seen many of the booths available, and the disinterest is sometimes real.</p><p>Which is why I was so pleasantly surprised that, after my presentation was over, I was excitedly approached by a professor from a university in America who was interested in potentially collaborating with us, or at the very least exchanging information in a hopefully mutually beneficial way. I am leaving this description purposefully vague at this time as we are not sure what this potential relationship may or may not blossom in to.</p><p>If you would like to view a video of my presentation at CBC, here is a <a href="https://youtu.be/G7K5REE152w">link </a>to it on our <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZl6N10P9LNpYkrMwWYtK1w">YouTube page.</a></p><h3>Looking Forward</h3><p>CBC was our last conference of the year. It was also our 11th. I had the opportunity and pleasure of attending 10 of them (only one I missed was the Crypto Valley Conference), and can honestly say that while they were not all created equal, they all brought slightly different visions of what a blockchain/cryptocurrency conference could/should be.</p><p>To review, our 2018 appearances were:</p><ul><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/event-blockdelhi-conference-february-21st-3a15fe318302">BlockDelhi 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/apac-blockchain-conference-2018-3817679b45b">APAC Blockchain 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/global-blockchain-expo-2018-next-week-77afb5a9c61c">Global Blockchain Expo 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-dc-finances-high-tech-family-office-meetings-b7fe8067d40d">DC Finance’s New York High Tech Family Office Meeting</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/consensus-conference-next-week-63f206bd0641">Consensus 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-my-evening-with-the-financial-services-club-in-london-573d5713f001">Financial Services Club of London</a></li><li>Crypto Valley Conference 2018</li><li>New York FinTech Week</li><li>Voice of Blockchain 2018</li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/discover-blockchains-conference-next-week-dab6e0b8651b">Discover Blockchains</a></li><li>CryptoBlockCon Las Vegas</li></ul><h3>One Final Note</h3><p>One of the highlights of my conference tour in 2018 were those rare and precious moments when I got to interact with community members. These were all informal (mostly in the context of a bar/pub) meetups; we shared a drink (or two), and got to talk and get to know one another. Meeting the people that use QRL always fills me with a sense of optimism and opportunity. I know that this protocol, and its ecosystem, will continue to blossom in 2019, as it has in 2018.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=2f039b4b6f8d" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-cbc-2018-2f039b4b6f8d">Reflecting on CBC 2018</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crypto Block Conference This Week!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/crypto-block-conference-this-week-1a8f4d1d0cc4?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/1a8f4d1d0cc4</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[las-vegas]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[crypto-block-conference]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 19:43:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-12-09T19:43:39.473Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*qelVD0Rgu1BBcFsNIUVcag.jpeg" /></figure><p><em>TL;DR — Who/What/Where/When/Why of CryptoBlockCon 2018</em></p><h3>Who</h3><p>CryptoBlockCon 2018 will be attended by:</p><ul><li>Adam</li><li>Jack</li></ul><h3>What</h3><p>CryptoBlockCon is a conference series that convenes four times a year, everywhere from Las Vegas to London, to discuss the future benefits &amp; possibilities of blockchain technology &amp; crypto assets. The traveling event serves to showcase companies who are using blockchain, educate current and future industry participants on blockchain technology, and serve as a platform for industry participants to network with one another.</p><h3>Where</h3><p><a href="https://www.mandalaybay.com/en.html">Mandalay Bay Resort and Casino,</a> Las Vegas</p><h3>When</h3><p>December 11–12, 2018</p><h3>Why</h3><p>When we were approached with the opportunity to present at CBC 2018, we had to consider the various factors that make a given conference appearance worth it or not. We had to consider travel distance, the length and prominence of our presentation slot, what we would be presenting, and of course, weigh that against overall cost, both in time and money. When we looked at all of these factors, it made sense to seize this opportunity, and try to maximize it.</p><p>As always, if you will be in Las Vegas this week, whether you are there for the conference or not, and would like to meet up with us, please do not hesitate to reach out. It is always tons of fun to meet users and community members out in the real world. Barring an unforeseen event, this will be our last conference of 2018 — so this will be your last, best chance to see us in person before next year.</p><p>To review, our 2018 appearances were:</p><ul><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/event-blockdelhi-conference-february-21st-3a15fe318302">BlockDelhi 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/apac-blockchain-conference-2018-3817679b45b">APAC Blockchain 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/global-blockchain-expo-2018-next-week-77afb5a9c61c">Global Blockchain Expo 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-dc-finances-high-tech-family-office-meetings-b7fe8067d40d">DC Finance’s New York High Tech Family Office Meeting</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/consensus-conference-next-week-63f206bd0641">Consensus 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-my-evening-with-the-financial-services-club-in-london-573d5713f001">Financial Services Club of London</a></li><li>Crypto Valley Conference 2018</li><li>New York FinTech Week</li><li>Voice of Blockchain 2018</li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/discover-blockchains-conference-next-week-dab6e0b8651b">Discover Blockchains</a></li><li>CryptoBlockCon Las Vegas</li></ul><p>We are all looking forward to an even more productive 2019!</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=1a8f4d1d0cc4" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/crypto-block-conference-this-week-1a8f4d1d0cc4">Crypto Block Conference This Week!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>