<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Cryptography with longevity. A post-quantum secure blockchain featuring a stateful signature scheme and unparalleled security. - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 16:01:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/the-quantum-resistant-ledger" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL June 25 — July 1]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-june-25-july-1-6bed4d1ba772?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/6bed4d1ba772</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-x]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 22:19:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-07-01T22:19:18.822Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL June 25 — July 1</h3><p><em>Development Updates, QRL on Ledger Nano X, QRL Community Q&amp;A</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*2SUCK3v7e-pjW-FirnveOQ.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>This past week, as many are in blockchain, a busy one. We had the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-blockchain-is-one-year-old-119c78664040">one year anniversary</a> of launching the QRL blockchain, QRL is now on <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/wallet/ledger-nano-s/">Ledger Nano X</a>, and we had our first QRL Community Q&amp;A. We will be announcing the recipient of July’s QRL Community Nomination Award in a blog later this week.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*S4oe0LrU6kHk_GulfFNXVQ.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>qrl-wallet:</strong> WebUSB/Nano X support in web wallet</li><li><strong>go-qrl:</strong> Added missing return for updateChainState</li><li><strong>mobile-wallet: </strong>Improvements based on mobile wallet v2</li></ul><h3>QRL on Ledger Nano X</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/956/1*lJ9JZ9y6hKIv6WnvL12rYQ.jpeg" /></figure><p>As you may have already seen on our <a href="https://twitter.com/QRLedger/status/1144613300573020162">Twitter</a>, QRL is now available on the Ledger Nano X. Previously, QRL was available on the Ledger Nano S, and we are happy to report that our compatibility has expanded. We always strive to ensure that our users have a functional and attractive suite of utility, and one of the key elements to that is a good option for a hardware wallet. Ledger continues to be the industry standard in the hardware wallet space, and we are happy to be able to offer that compatibility to our users. You can see our guide on using the Ledger Nano S or X <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/wallet/ledger-nano-s/">here</a>.</p><h3>QRL Community Q&amp;A</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*y0tjQyU2ZnhN1UaIp233zQ.jpeg" /></figure><p>Today, on the <a href="https://discord.gg/zbAJ9YV">QRL Discord server</a>, the first QRL Community Q&amp;A occurred. You can go check it out in the #qrl channel of the server yourself (for reference: it started today, July 1st, at 1800 UTC). We will also be cleaning up the questions, answers, follow-ups and responses, and putting them in an easy-to-access place. This should be available in a few days.</p><p>The Q&amp;A consisted of questions from the community, both sent in previously, as well as asked in the moment. Members from the team answered questions, as well as responded to comments as they occurred, while offering their opinions on a variety of matters. Moving forward, we will try to hold similar Q&amp;As, with some probably being more generalized, like today, with others potentially being more focused on a specific topic or cluster of topics.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=6bed4d1ba772" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-june-25-july-1-6bed4d1ba772">Last Week in QRL June 25 — July 1</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The QRL Contributors]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-contributors-ed7abd73ab1?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/ed7abd73ab1</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl-contributors]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 15:38:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-06-28T17:02:14.884Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Contribution is the backbone of any opensource project like The QRL, and is emergent from the community that surrounds it.</p><p>In this way it’s important to keep things not only accessible and open, but simple, enticing, guided, cohesive, and malleable to the changing needs of both the project and how it fits into the wider cryptocurrency space.</p><p>With this in mind, we’d like to announce <strong>The QRL Contributors</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/956/1*hCwi5dq-C-nJc2TlccDwZQ.png" /></figure><p>This is a project that aims to open up discussions and bring in both the core and community contributors alike, and is part of our path for decentralising The QRL <em>community</em> network.</p><p>Practically speaking, this will allow people (QRL contributors) to work in the QRL project by collaborating on different aspects of the ecosystem from coding to design and outreach in an organised collaborative fashion. For those who aren’t contributors, the more open transparency will make it easier to follow along.</p><p>Right now, it’s open to the core contributors as well as a select group of community contributors as we squash some bugs that may arise, but we’re excited about opening this up to the wider community in the future.</p><h4>Sections</h4><ul><li><a href="#5cd4">Objectives</a> (Primary Goals, Secondary Goals)</li><li><a href="#9751">Overview</a> (technical, in practice)</li></ul><h3><strong>Objectives</strong></h3><h4><strong>Primary goals</strong></h4><ol><li><strong>Accessible</strong>: Where possible, the team and contributors should be reachable and act as ambassadors.</li><li><strong>Open</strong>: Discussions and the general development of materials should be a public process that’s transparent.</li></ol><h4><strong>Secondary goals</strong></h4><ol><li><strong>Enticing</strong>: Creating an incentive scheme that is appealing, sustainable, and produces results.</li><li><strong>Guided</strong>: Structure is important to establishing a common vision within which to work. Additionally so is outlining proper scope and tracking long-term tasks for coordinating people from each working group.</li><li><strong>Cohesive</strong>: Everybody has their own skillset(s) to contribute, and should be encouraged and endorsed for self-electing the way in which they’d like to participate. However, each working group should be formed with the innate ability and desirability to work cohesively with every other working group. This may be an important enough goal to have a group all on its own, as it presents special usability and tooling challenges.</li><li><strong>Malleable</strong>: It’s important to remain flexible so that significant overhead is not incurred to make necessary changes.</li><li><strong>Resilient</strong>: Permissions and tasks should be set up and documented in such a way that any working group or person can walk away from the project with no warning and not meaningfully negatively impact efforts.</li></ol><h3>Overview</h3><h4>On a technical level</h4><p>The requirements for The QRL Contributors is a system that has <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Role-based_access_control">Role Based Access Control (RBAC)</a>, specifically with the ability to have read-only environments for all visitors. Additional functionality, though not a strict requirement, is the ability to communicate and flag certain roles through mentioning them.</p><p>Right now, much of the community (and the core contributors) is in Discord, which also fills these roles, so we are hosting the QRL Contributors on Discord initially. It should be noted however, that these requirements are system agnostic so it’s possible to change platforms, should the need or desire arise.</p><h4>In practice</h4><p>The structure is kept as simple and potent as possible to keep onboarding a relatively light endeavor.</p><p><strong>Visitors</strong> are able to view discussions, but not add to them. Through viewing the discussions at play, as well as any outstanding tasks that need to be done, a visitor might want to apply to take on a bigger role <em>as a contributor</em>.</p><p>Once accepted as a <strong>Contributor</strong>,<strong> </strong>they can self-assign<strong> </strong>one or more <strong>roles</strong>. These roles can be seen as specialisations that a person has. Some examples would be ‘developer’, ‘designer’, ‘writer’, and ‘marketer’. Roles are something that’s taggable, as in practice, another contributor might need some insight or help from members of the team that have a specific specialisation.</p><p>Along with roles, also self-assigned are <strong>Working Groups (WG)</strong>’s, which can be seen as committees that come together to achieve specific ongoing goals. Often a working group is similar to the role or specialisation (ie. ‘wg-marketing’), but not always (ie. ‘wg-documentation’, ‘wg-website’).</p><p>For things that are temporary in nature, but are large enough to warrant a committee of their own, there’s also <strong>Projects</strong> which are elected and can be self-assigned. Some examples of projects might be for videos and the organisation of events.</p><p>While the core contributors and a select group of community contributors utilise this system, it’s possible some of the above structure will change before the public release. What is described is how it is now, as of this writing.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=ed7abd73ab1" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-contributors-ed7abd73ab1">The QRL Contributors</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The QRL Blockchain is One Year Old!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-blockchain-is-one-year-old-119c78664040?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/119c78664040</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 17:04:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-06-26T17:04:10.772Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*8OCgQ2N25a6aHSQALC5Kxg.jpeg" /></figure><h3>Where We’ve Been</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*0DG5s0m8sX9BhGWge04xUw.jpeg" /></figure><p>One year ago today, on June 26th, 2018, the QRL blockchain was released to the world.</p><p>With the words, “The sleeper must awaken” and 34.679 KB of data, the first block was put into place. For those unfamiliar with the origin of the quote, it is from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dune_(1984_film)">1984 film adaptation</a> of Frank Herbert’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dune_(novel)">“Dune</a>” The full line that it draws from is:</p><blockquote>A person needs new experiences. It jars something deep inside, allowing them to grow. Without change something sleeps inside us, and seldom awakens. The sleeper must awaken.</blockquote><p>Ultimately, blockchain technology has the potential to change the world. If millions of people did not believe that across the globe, we would not have seen the wonderful explosion of development and activity over the past 10+ years of the technology’s existence. Passion is a necessary ingredient when starting any significant endeavor, all the moreso when that endeavor seeks to bring into this world something that has not existed previously. The status quo seldom leads to meaningful change, and our world needs changing.</p><p>Below are a few statistics (at the time of writing) regarding the network:</p><ul><li>Current block height: 525,000+</li><li>Number of wallets with funds in them: 58,000+</li><li>Total number of transactions: 875,000+</li><li>Shortest block time: 1 second</li><li>Largest amount of total Quanta transferred in 1 day: 19,046,451</li><li>Quanta population: ~65% (68,364,000+)</li></ul><h3>What We’ve Built</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*QboS1rxNN3ckt2XjLrQmrQ.jpeg" /></figure><p>Since hiring began at QRL in 2017, a little over 2 years has passed. In those 2 years, the time has been spent roughly in equal measure creating the network, and improving it. The past year has been spent entirely on improving the network, and we are proud to say that the QRL blockchain today has much more utility than it did at launch.</p><p>Some of the highlights of the past year of development:</p><ul><li>Mobile Wallet for <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/qrl-wallet/id1458620542?ls=1&amp;mt=8">iOS</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.theqrl">Android</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-and-keybase-84968003bca2">Keybase Integration</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/step-by-step-what-weve-been-up-to-f6cd800e0a63">PQ-Notarization</a></li><li><a href="https://support.ledger.com/hc/en-us/articles/360019184453">Ledger Integration</a></li><li><a href="https://explorer.theqrl.org/">Updated Explorer</a></li><li><a href="https://theqrl.org/">Updated Desktop Wallets</a></li><li><a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/">Documentation Site</a></li></ul><p>Certainly, over 2018, the phrase, “To win the game, you must be in the game” came to mind somewhat frequently. Over the course of the so-called ‘crypto winter’ somewhere over 1,000 blockchain/cryptocurrency projects failed, exit-scammed, or were closed due to regulatory malfeasance. In any market, the best ability is availability, and a combination of tireless development work, passionate community support, and responsible financial management has allowed us to continue to work and iterate, when so many others have chosen to, or been forced to, close their doors.</p><h3>Where We’re Going</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*7r_QrTmNVu1jqLn7h033pA.jpeg" /></figure><p>Moving forward, the main objective continues to be creating the most secure, compelling, and interesting blockchain we can, all the while continuing our efforts to decentralize the project, as is appropriate. The <a href="https://qrl.foundation/">QRL Foundation</a>, which is still in its infancy, will help support the growth and maintenance of the network, as well as acting as an umbrella under which various development, research, outreach and educational efforts can be coordinated.</p><p>More generally, software development, in blockchain as elsewhere, is a balancing act. This is true both in terms of committing resources (both human and financial), as well as choosing directions, and making prioritizations. The QRL blockchain that launched last June was not the exact same as the first version of the whitepaper in 2016 described it, nor should it have been. Things were discovered along the way that needed changing, or re-thinking, or completely scrapping.</p><p>As we have moved forward from launch, that calculation has changed in part, but the balancing act remains. As we continue to consider what features to pursue, and what development objectives to prioritize, we will continue to bring the same forward-oriented perspective to development that we have so far. We appreciate the understanding that our community of users has demonstrated thus far, and we are very happy at how the QIP system has furthered this communication. We are looking forward to another year of exciting work on the QRL blockchain!</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=119c78664040" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-blockchain-is-one-year-old-119c78664040">The QRL Blockchain is One Year Old!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WARNING: Fake QRL wallet in Microsoft Store]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/warning-fake-qrl-wallet-in-microsoft-store-a96f8318af1f?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/a96f8318af1f</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[open-source]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[microsoft-store]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The QRL]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 13:59:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-06-26T13:59:27.341Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/640/1*wFmSrjP0jCXfsPFOsP5gkg.jpeg" /></figure><p>We would like to warn users of a fake QRL wallet in the Microsoft app store.</p><p>This application has not been developed or authorised by the QRL Foundation or any QRL contributors and there is a high likelihood that our open source software may have been altered in order to steal funds.</p><p>All genuine QRL apps and services are linked from our <a href="https://theqrl.org">theqrl.org</a> homepage where the genuine version of our wallet for Windows can be found.</p><p>We have reached out to Microsoft for intervention.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=a96f8318af1f" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/warning-fake-qrl-wallet-in-microsoft-store-a96f8318af1f">WARNING: Fake QRL wallet in Microsoft Store</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL June 18–24]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-june-18-24-7c0726ef3d0c?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/7c0726ef3d0c</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 16:12:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-06-24T16:51:37.271Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, One Year Anniversary Coming Soon, Market Availability Update</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*dC5OUM-K2vX7GaNevvJMkw.png" /></figure><h3>One Year Anniversary</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ept5R8Evq0wtVXQ6WXQOuA.jpeg" /></figure><p>In the world of blockchain it is said that a day feels like a week, a week feels like a month, and every season feels like a new year. This is perhaps doubly true when it is the first year of a blockchain’s existence. In many ways, it feels both longer <em>and </em>shorter than a year, but sure enough this Wednesday, June 26th, it will be the one year anniversary of the launch of the QRL blockchain. We will have a dedicated blog on the day of recounting some of the accomplishments of the past year. We would like to thank everyone who has been with us on the journey so far, and we are very excited for what the next year holds both for us and the wider blockchain industry.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*OhNo_CFeqF8VKdMcG2hfwg.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>go-qrl:</strong> Deadlock fixes for peer + Code simplification</li><li><strong>wallet-helpers: </strong>Increase test coverage to 100%</li><li><strong>docs.theqrl.org: </strong>Post automatic token migration updates</li></ul><h3>Market Availability Update</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*1grthy0mA7x06j7iFn5Q8g.png" /></figure><p>At the tail end of last week, there was the additional geofencing of 42 digital assets by Bittrex (read their announcement <a href="https://bittrex.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360029523891-Market-Availability-Changes-for-U-S-Customers-6-28-19">here</a>). This brings up the current total to 74, and underlines the need for more regulatory clarity in the United States. As always, the QRL Foundation supports regulatory clarity, and legislation that helps further innovation. We will continue to try and stay as informed on these topics as we can be and will report as much as we are able to, when we are able to. For now, know that market availability is something that the project recognizes as a priority, and we understand the role it plays in facilitating the overall health of the ecosystem.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=7c0726ef3d0c" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-june-18-24-7c0726ef3d0c">Last Week in QRL June 18–24</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL June 11–17]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-june-11-17-3228fedb56b8?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/3228fedb56b8</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[token-migration]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 18:53:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-06-17T18:53:28.034Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Automatic Token Migration Officially Closed</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*4VaOiIb07ao_DFgn40dFBg.png" /></figure><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*e6qih6FrQ8a63a5n7_Aviw.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>go-qrl: </strong>Updated Balance datatype to string in PlainBalance</li><li><strong>js-api-bridge:</strong> Added support for more APIs + Added QrlAddressValidator</li><li><strong>hw-app-qrl:</strong> add getAddress with expected LLD outputs</li><li><strong>wallet-helpers:</strong> Add QRLAddressFromEPKHex method</li></ul><h3>Automatic Token Migration Closed</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*NIBC_49JalGTPM8YDVymzA.jpeg" /></figure><p>On June 15th, 2019, automatic token migration closed for the QRL ERC20 token (dedicated blog <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/automatic-token-migration-complete-689c34a56686">here</a>). Overall, automatic token migration ran for ~12 months, and saw the successful transfer of around 90% of the ERC20 population. During those 12 months, there were a number of somewhat predictable flurries of activity; the start of migration, shortly before/after the blockchain launched, and as we approached the final deadline for automatic token migration.</p><p>During the entire run, there were no reported instances of tokens being lost in migration. Support requests were relatively few and far between, which is a positive indication of the robustness of the process. We would first like to credit our developers for their diligent work in creating, managing, and supporting the automatic token migration application. Without them, automatic migration never would have been possible, and without their attention to detail, it could have been a truly ugly mess.</p><p>We would also like to thank our community; not only was the response to our calls for migration significant, but we regularly witnessed community members spreading the word about migration and helping others (particularly in Discord) who were confused about the process. Thank you for helping to ensure that token migration has so far been such an effective endeavor.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=3228fedb56b8" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-june-11-17-3228fedb56b8">Last Week in QRL June 11–17</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Automatic token migration complete!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/automatic-token-migration-complete-689c34a56686?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/689c34a56686</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[migration]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 02:38:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-06-16T02:49:31.127Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On June 26th, 2018, we launched our QRL mainnet network and opened up our automatic token migration which has operated successfully and without a single incident reported.</p><p>This is thanks to the software that’s been written, and vetted, by several members of the QRL team. In addition, the diligent oversight of every migration that’s come through has ensured that the process has been smooth.</p><p>There came a time, however, for automatic token migration to end, and manual token migration to begin. As of today, June 15th, 2019, automatic token migration is closed.</p><p>This is the first step before ending migration completely.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*zT-9cr4qr_CZ1Wz09kQmYA.jpeg" /><figcaption>Migration is now manual — from pixabay user <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/leoleobobeo-1487549/">leoleobobeo</a></figcaption></figure><h3>Common questions</h3><h4>“I forgot/procrastinated/missed the memo to migrate! Is it too late?”</h4><p>If you still haven’t migrated your QRL ERC20 tokens to mainnet, you will need to follow these steps for manual migration:</p><ul><li><strong>Step 1</strong>: A QRL User will email <a href="mailto:support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a> with a QRL mainnet address the user created (QRL addresses that start with a Q).</li><li><strong>Step 2</strong>: Support (via <a href="mailto:support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a>) will respond to the user with an ETH ERC20 burn address.</li><li><strong>Step 3</strong>: User will send QRL ERC20s to the ETH burn address sent via email.</li><li><strong>Step 4</strong>: QRL address provided by user will be sent Quanta at a 1:1 ratio to ERC20s burnt.</li><li><strong>Step 5</strong>: User will now have 1 Quanta in their QRL address for every 1 ERC20 they sent to their burn address.</li></ul><p>While this guide is current, it may at some point become out of date. An up-to-date guide lives at our documentation site: <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/tokenmigration/newguide/">https://docs.theqrl.org/tokenmigration/newguide/</a> (note: link not currently active and is just undergoing review)</p><h4>I have QRL on Bittrex, is it migrated/when will they migrate?</h4><p>The QRL on Bittrex is our mainnet coin as they have already performed the QRL migration last year.</p><p>There is no need to migrate these coins.</p><h4>What will happen to the QRL ERC20 tokens and reserved Quanta after the final migration end-date?</h4><p>At no point in time will the Quanta be accessible to the Foundation. Anyone that still has non-migrated QRL ERC20 tokens will still have them, of course.</p><h3>Thank you</h3><p>This automatic token migration couldn’t have happened without you!</p><p>If there’s any other questions you might have you can email us at support@theqrl.org or reach us on <a href="https://reddit.com/r/QRL/">Reddit</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/qrledger">Twitter</a>, or <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">Discord</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=689c34a56686" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/automatic-token-migration-complete-689c34a56686">Automatic token migration complete!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL June 4–10]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-june-4-10-ebc36409c050?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/ebc36409c050</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[bittrex]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 16:05:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-06-10T16:05:39.872Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Token Migration Reminder, Bittrex US Geofencing</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*NFSCc6BvXoQBC8RaKWa7Cg.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>There is never a dull week in blockchain, and this past one was no exception. Bittrex announced that it was geofencing 32 crypto assets from United States customers Friday (more on this below), and significant progress has been made on further integrating Ledger. This is also the last “Last Week” blog before the end of Automatic Token Migration later this week on <strong>June 15, 2019 3:00 pm UTC-05:00</strong>, so we will have another reminder regarding that at the end of the blog.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*rcLJwEwLoBrJ9Fs95QZKRA.png" /></figure><ul><li><strong>ledger-live: </strong>Work on integration underway (more in <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/dev-meetings/blob/master/2019/06/06.md">dev meeting notes</a>)</li><li><strong>ledger: </strong>New BOLOS app (Nano S/X, multitree) with WebUSB-ready supporting library awaiting review by Ledger</li><li><strong>wallet:</strong> Pagination support underway: discussed adding this to explorer-helpers to allow recycling of code in explorer</li></ul><h3>Community</h3><p>We recognize that between the closure of automatic token migration at the end of the week (check out the <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/tokenmigration/countdown/">countdown</a>), and the recent Bittrex geofencing news (dedicated blog <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/geofencing-of-crypto-assets-b800494f0c6d">here</a>), that a lot of information has been coming at the QRL community. We wanted to thank our community members for being so supportive of one another and quickly stepping up to disseminate information among one another.</p><p>This is probably most evident on Discord, where newcomers are oftentimes given a bevvy of information upon entering the server for the first time and asking some “What’s all this?” type questions. A coin is only ever as strong as its community, and it is encouraging to see so much passion from ours.</p><h3>Bittrex Geofencing of United States Customers</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*zAREr3w_wSv5wAPPZGD8gA.jpeg" /></figure><p>As we wrote in a <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/geofencing-of-crypto-assets-b800494f0c6d">previous blog</a>, Bittrex recently announced that it was geofencing 32 crypto assets, including QRL, from US customers on 2019–06–21.</p><p>Trading for non-US customers will continue unchanged on the Bittrex International platform.</p><p>You can read the full announcement <a href="https://bittrex.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360028996652">here</a>.</p><p>While this will not halt development progress on the project, the near term priority for the project will be procuring an additional listing on a major Asian exchange as soon as is practical.</p><h3>Automatic Token Migration</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*x37t9zJwA4zcg7tH9XvxMg.jpeg" /></figure><p>The current token migration process is <strong>automatic </strong>once you have started the process<strong> </strong>and <strong>almost immediate</strong>.</p><p><em>After</em> <strong>June 15, 2019 3:00 pm UTC-05:00</strong>, however, the process for migrating ERC20s will be <strong>manual,</strong> and may take an <strong>indeterminate amount of time</strong>. <em>Additionally</em>, each manual migration will be evaluated on a <strong>case-by-case basis</strong>.</p><p>It’s <em>strongly</em> recommended that any and all users who still have QRL ERC20’s to migrate them <strong>BEFORE</strong> the closure of automatic migration on June 15th, 2019.</p><p>We have also outlined this on our <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/tokenmigration/countdown/">documentation page</a> to help keep everything in one spot and ensure everyone is on the same page with migration.</p><p>The process of token migration thusfar has been a successful and relatively smooth one. The overwhelming majority of QRL ERC20 tokens have been migrated. There are only a few unmigrated tokens left, and hopefully, there will be hardly any left once automatic token migration closes.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=ebc36409c050" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-june-4-10-ebc36409c050">Last Week in QRL June 4–10</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Geofencing of Crypto Assets]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/geofencing-of-crypto-assets-b800494f0c6d?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/b800494f0c6d</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[bittrex]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 16:49:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-06-08T16:51:45.426Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Bittrex will be geofencing 32 assets, including QRL, in the coming weeks</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*zAREr3w_wSv5wAPPZGD8gA.jpeg" /></figure><p>It has come to our attention that Bittrex will be geofencing 32 crypto assets including QRL from US customers on 2019–06–21. Trading for non-US customers will continue unchanged on the Bittrex International platform.</p><p>Full announcement can be read <a href="https://bittrex.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360028996652">here</a>.</p><p>Whilst we have no more information on this than has been released publicly by Bittrex, we support their efforts in evolving the cryptocurrency ecosystem and hope that their geofencing will be short-lived, especially as the open source QRL ecosystem is now mature and QRL is so widely distributed around the world.</p><p>In the last few days the QRL chain has grown past 500k blocks; a planned hard fork to bring on-chain decentralised governance, numerous iterative improvements and multi-signature wallet support is not far away. Mobile platform support, Keybase integration for identity proofs, and Ledger hardware wallet support have recently been added to the QRL, with Ledger X support, multi-tree support and Ledger Live integration right around the corner.</p><p>We are one of the few projects to take post-quantum security seriously and are proud that the entire ledger is already PQ-secure with a professionally audited codebase. Cryptocurrency should be impervious to technical attack and post-quantum insecurity remains a critical vulnerability in the armor of this nascent asset class.</p><p>Development progress aside, the near term priority for the project will be procuring an additional listing on a major Asian exchange as soon as is practical.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=b800494f0c6d" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/geofencing-of-crypto-assets-b800494f0c6d">Geofencing of Crypto Assets</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[May Community Nomination Award]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/may-community-nomination-award-16294e740d2?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/16294e740d2</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl-communit]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 16:55:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-06-06T16:55:12.326Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*vJoeJvxVUhP1s_fbjsJ1lA.png" /></figure><p>We are pleased to announce that last month’s QRL Community Nomination Award goes to Discord user Mquantum.</p><p>Here’s what Mquantum had to tell us about themselves, and their relationship to QRL:</p><blockquote>Although not working directly in the field of quantum computing, during 2017 I started to realize the growing impact it has in my research field (I am a PhD in quantum physics) and began eagerly reading about it. That was also the time of the last big bitcoin bullrun, when, admittedly curious of the big gains people were making, I started to read about bitcoin and blockchain. The collision between quantum computing and blockchain was quite obvious to me, and the most serious and welcoming place to discuss those things was clearly the QRL community. I was particularly impressed by the Reddit posts by Jackalyst and Dezeyay, and a <a href="https://medium.com/coinmonks/quantum-computers-pose-a-credible-threat-to-the-security-of-bitcoin-4b1dd65944ca">Medium article by Charlie Thompson</a>.</blockquote><blockquote>I do not know if going through the 2018 bear market earns me a veteran medal, anyway I surely won a Basic Whining Token (1 BWT to me), as did many in the Discord server. It is clear now that the QRL community is steadily increasing its impact in the crypto discussion. I love being part of it, and am intrigued by the efforts the QRL team is making in favoring decentralization. The next months are crucial both for the progress of quantum computing and for the QRL building, I believe!</blockquote><p>Mquantum has been a member of the QRL community, as he states, since 2017. We value the diversity of knowledge present in our community highly, and are always glad to have that brought to bear in our community discussions. Mquantum has shown themselves to be a productive, positive member of our community and we are pleased that they are receiving the May Community Nomination.</p><p>Know someone who you think deserves a Community Nomination? Write “nominate [platform] [username]” (example: nominate twitter QRLedger) in the <a href="https://discordapp.com/channels/357604137204056065/357607117412106241/510858891706236929">#butler channel</a> of our <a href="https://discord.gg/zbAJ9YV">Discord server</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=16294e740d2" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/may-community-nomination-award-16294e740d2">May Community Nomination Award</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>