<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Cryptography with longevity. A post-quantum secure blockchain featuring a stateful signature scheme and unparalleled security. - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:47:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/the-quantum-resistant-ledger" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Exchange Listing — Biteeu]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/new-exchange-listing-biteeu-3d00fd8fbedf?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/3d00fd8fbedf</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[crypto-exchange]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[biteeu]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:17:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-09-20T15:17:16.435Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>New Exchange Listing — Biteeu</h3><p><em>QRL is now trading on Biteeu</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*mRFcim9GR1MdKrJG7jHuqw.png" /></figure><h3>What is Biteeu?</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/910/1*g-gk3GyyIM_uhP5MEELbrg.png" /></figure><p>Biteeu is an exchange based in Estonia, a member of the European Union. Biteeu is a partner of Bittrex.</p><p>From the Biteeu website:</p><blockquote>BITEEU DCX OÜ was founded in 2019 in the Republic of Estonia by professionals with solid experience in banking sector, stock market and international public companies. It is a fully licensed and compliant virtual currency exchange in the European Union. We highly value integrity, safety and security. Therefore, we have developed our anti-money laundering and know your customer policies in accordance with the strict requirements of local laws and International acts.</blockquote><p>Regarding their collaboration with Bittrex:</p><blockquote>BITEEU DCX OÜ in collaboration with Bittrex uses its advanced technology to offer our customers safe, reliable and comfortable trading experience. Our platform supports several languages including English, Russian and Chinese. It provides round-the-clock customer service and ensures the safety of your assets and data.</blockquote><p>CEO of Bittrex Bill Shihara had this to say about Biteeu:</p><blockquote>The Biteeu platform will provide customers in Estonia and the region with a reliable, secure, and advanced trading option along with liquidity and the world’s most innovative blockchain projects. That is a combination that excites us as we continue to expand our partner network and increase adoption of this revolutionary technology. We are always looking to drive the blockchain revolution forward and in Biteeu we have a new partner who shares that same vision!</blockquote><h3>How Do I Access QRL On Biteeu?</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/512/1*MoV_Z0Q4TtlJqDc7c2N58w.png" /></figure><p>With over 50 digital assets available on its platform, against three base pairs (BTC, ETH, USDT), Biteeu has quickly expanded following receiving licenses from the Republic of Estonia earlier this year. It currently holds the following licenses:</p><ul><li>Providing a virtual currency wallet service (FRK000660)</li><li>Providing services of exchanging a virtual currency against a fiat currency (FVR000760)</li></ul><p>To access QRL on Biteeu, first you will need to <a href="https://trade.biteeu.com/sign-up">make an account with Biteeu</a>. You can also <a href="https://trade.biteeu.com/search">check out their markets</a> before you sign up if you’d like. There is a light/dark mode for those with specific UI preferences.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=3d00fd8fbedf" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/new-exchange-listing-biteeu-3d00fd8fbedf">New Exchange Listing — Biteeu</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL September 10–16]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-10-16-ff1065770b7a?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/ff1065770b7a</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[mobile-wallets]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ios]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 22:13:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-09-16T22:22:01.695Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Thanks to Beta Testers, New Exchange Listing Coming</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*i3I9iGSFw8J8qPDDEs2XCA.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>As we move further into September, there are many exciting things on the horizon. Recently, Proof-of-Stake has been discussed more internally, as have greater attempts to involve our passionate community, and we are nearing the release window for Mobile Wallet v2. Additionally, we are happy to announce that there is another exchange listing on the horizon (more on this below).</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*fY_2YroVG0hzMHFJGjqCxA.png" /></figure><ul><li><strong>mobile-wallet:</strong> Preparing Release 2.0</li></ul><p>As a reminder, here is a general list of the features/changes coming to Mobile Wallet 2.0</p><ul><li>User can open existing wallet with mnemonic (only hexseed was supported so far)</li><li>User can choose the OTS key index, just tap the OTS key index in the send view</li><li>New settings page</li><li>User can change the node (and port) to connect to. If not connected to a specific node (we can decide which one, the default will be mainnet-*) a small warning icon is presented next to the Settings menu.</li><li>The user can turn on/off the PIN security. If turned on, the app will always ask for the PIN when the user switches back to the wallet</li><li>PIN is required if the user leaves the app for more than 15 seconds (I can change it if too short/long)</li><li>Deleting a wallet has a better warning and asks for the PIN</li><li>User can give a name to the wallets</li><li>Corrected the QR code generated on the wallet section</li><li>Date and Time are shown according to users’ general timezone preferences</li><li>Additional UI/UX improvements</li></ul><h3>Thank You Mobile Beta Testers</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*-vzkIxIj_Cs1hoMYLidS5A.jpeg" /></figure><p>The QRL Team would like to extend our thanks to all the beta testers who have participated in testing the upcoming mobile wallet 2.0. In any technological endeavor, testing is important, but for a project our size, having a group of passionate beta testers who can look at our mobile wallet in various operating systems, screen sizes, etc helps us in our efforts to develop the best QRL ecosystem possible.</p><h3>New Exchange Listing Incoming</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/637/1*ezTHk5Wuv02yk94FZ8ckTg.jpeg" /></figure><p>While we usually use these blogs as an opportunity to review what has happened in the wide world of QRL over the past week, on occasion we will also look to the future. Given the priority of conversation that exchange listings have taken in our community of late, we thought it reasonable to let our users know that there is another exchange listing coming.</p><p>For obvious reasons, we cannot be explicit in the details at this time in terms of what exchange it is, and exactly when we will be listing. However, we did not want to remain entirely silent in the face of the continuing conversation regarding liquidity availability for our users. Look for a dedicated blog, as well as dedicated social posts, regarding this development once the listing day arrives.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=ff1065770b7a" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-10-16-ff1065770b7a">Last Week in QRL September 10–16</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL September 3–9]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-3-9-d6ac1eef7a64?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/d6ac1eef7a64</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 18:49:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-09-09T18:49:41.923Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Community Nomination Blog Incoming</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*dr3gyjnrK8iE89_uqMNT2Q.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>September is upon us, and with it the first inklings of Autumn crispness ready to drive out the Summer heat. At QRL, there has been a flutter of activity both within the team itself, as well as in our interactions with outside organizations/individuals. Unfortunately, a significant portion of this activity cannot be discussed in detail yet. The best of the rest is below.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*eVmEIQjTsrj7O-ziaxQhXg.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>mobile-wallet:</strong> Release v0.2.6-beta</li><li><strong>theqrl.org:</strong> Added a standards body (nist/IETF) section to highlight documents/etc</li><li><strong>block-explorer:</strong> Wallet address changed — herominer</li></ul><h3>August Community Nomination Award</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*UnmlJxDvSBsLOXxfMx9MPQ.png" /></figure><p>This month’s Community Nomination Award was not included in last week’s or today’s blog because there has been a slight delay in confirming the recipient. A separate blog on the August Community Nomination Award recipient should be forthcoming in the next week or so.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=d6ac1eef7a64" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-3-9-d6ac1eef7a64">Last Week in QRL September 3–9</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL — August 27th to September 2nd]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-august-27th-to-september-2nd-6dc285d3927b?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/6dc285d3927b</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-computing]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[app-development]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 21:43:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-09-03T16:11:13.461Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*gWIJsu0HPzqtTy5A53eFWQ.png" /></figure><h3>Last Week in QRL — August 27th to September 2nd</h3><h4>Mobile Wallet v2: Testers Needed! and API’s and spotlights: Apps wanted!</h4><h3>Mobile Wallet version 2: Testers Needed!</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*pRbo9beNhPFGXbeF2_CywA.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*CbM90ui0EsEwp1FuR5X63w.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*iCyd8O1cnvyUaHCO-QDtJQ.png" /><figcaption>Sneak peak.</figcaption></figure><p>Our iOS/Android version 1 wallet came with the ability to manage multiple wallets, send/receive Quanta, view your balance/transaction history, set a lock-screen, and instantiate a wallet from our web-wallet through a QR Code.</p><p>Since then, there’s been many feature requests that’s been segmented into <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues?q=is%3Aopen+is%3Aissue+milestone%3Av2">version 2</a> and <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/milestone/2">version 3 and beyond</a>.</p><p>We’re pleased to announce that version 2 is ready for beta testing with the following updates:</p><ul><li>User can open existing wallet with mnemonic (only hexseed was supported so far)</li><li>User can choose the OTS key index, just tap the OTS key index in the send view</li><li>New settings page</li><li>User can change the node (and port) to connect to. If not connected to a specific node (we can decide which one, the default will be mainnet-*) a small warning icon is presented next to the Settings menu. If you want to try, for the test version the default node (the one without a warning) is: <a href="http://testnet-4.automated.theqrl.org">testnet-4.automated.theqrl.org</a></li><li>The user can turn on/off the PIN security. If turned on, the app will always ask for the PIN when the user switches back to the wallet</li><li>PIN is required if the user leaves the app for more than 15 seconds (I can change it if too short/long)</li><li>Deleting a wallet has a better warning and asks for the PIN</li><li>User can give a name to the wallets</li><li>Corrected the QR code generated on the wallet section</li><li>Date and Time are shown according to users’ general timezone preferences</li><li>Additional UI/UX improvements</li></ul><p>Before we release it to the general public however, proper testing is required.</p><h4>TestPilots required!</h4><p>We have gone through internal testing, now we need your help!</p><p><strong>iOS users: </strong>There is nothing you need to do, granted that you are already enrolled in the beta test through the apple store. Once the latest version hits the Apple store you will have the ability to update to the latest version.</p><p>If you would like to enroll in the iOS beta test, please send a DM to ‘@adem’ on Discord with the email address associated with your App store account.</p><p><strong>Android users:</strong> Please send a <strong>DM</strong> to @adem on Discord with your <strong>GMAIL Address</strong> associated with your play store account so he can add you to the testing group in the play store. This will allow the same functionality as the apple store, pushing the latest changes to your device.</p><p><strong><em>As a reminder, this is a BETA test!!</em></strong></p><ul><li>The beta wallet uses our <strong>Testnet</strong>, no actual funds are used for this test.</li><li><em>OTS keys </em><strong><em>MUST</em></strong><em> never be re-used. Using the same wallet for </em><em>mainnet and </em><em>testnet is dangerous. Generate a new test wallet and don’t reuse across networks.</em></li><li>Things may break or become un-reliable while we update and make changes.</li><li>You can’t use two different applications on your phone at the same time. If you’re planning on removing your current v1 application and installing the beta,<strong> be sure to backup your current wallet and make sure you can recover it!!! We will not be responsible for lost funds.</strong></li><li>If you need some <strong>Testnet</strong> funds, put out a message on one of our social media platforms with your testnet address and someone we’ll send you some.</li></ul><p><strong>What We Expect Of You</strong></p><p>Try and break things! Hack them if you can, or simply think like a beginner. Can your parents/grandparents/kids/friends use this application? Is it easy? What could be improved?</p><p>Feedback and issues should be directed over at github, so we can keep things organized and track the changes requested: <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues">https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues</a></p><p>Please include this information GitHub for any issues you have found.</p><pre>Action:<br>Expected Result:<br>Actual Result:<br>Android/iOS version:<br>Android/iOS handset model:</pre><p>For feedback in the form of feature requests, check to see if it already exists and then write it as an issue, freeform. Be sure to use a descriptive title!</p><p>No feedback is bad feedback!</p><h3>APIs and Spotlights</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*osqj_ihls3BJylOML6BIIA.png" /></figure><p>We now have 5 different ways to work off of The QRL, with another on its way explicitly for EMS:</p><ul><li><a href="https://api.theqrl.org/#qrl-api">QRL API</a>: Organized around GRPC which uses <a href="https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers/docs/overview">protocol buffers</a> for serializing structured data. If you’re working on an integrated application, this is what you want.</li><li><a href="https://api.theqrl.org/#explorer-api">Explorer API</a>: Great for quickly getting QRL address balances, population, and other such data.</li><li><a href="https://api.theqrl.org/#wallet-api">Wallet API (requires node)</a>: If you’re working with wallets (ie. exchanges and other services), this is recommended.</li><li><a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/wallet/wallet-cli/">qrl command line (requires node)</a>: Comes equipped with the python node, offers simpler functionality to the wallet API.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-cli">qrl-cli</a>: Executable with mac, linux, and osx binaries, for interacting with the QRL blockchain via scripts and applications without requiring a full node.</li></ul><h4>Apps Wanted!</h4><p>The above functionality should be plenty to start developing your post-quantum secure blockchain application!</p><p>For those building QRL applications and wanting to showcase them, it’s encouraged to request to put them in our <a href="https://github.com/theqrl-community">theqrl-community</a> github, which will allow projects to get some spotlight from the QRL community.</p><p>Need an idea? Head over to <a href="https://discord.gg/KAg5fAm">#qrl-app-ideas</a> in our Discord and pick one. Stuck? Post in our <a href="https://discord.gg/AmG7659">#development</a> channel for any help you may need, and finally, don’t forget our <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/">documentation</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=6dc285d3927b" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-august-27th-to-september-2nd-6dc285d3927b">Last Week in QRL — August 27th to September 2nd</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Exchange Listing — Cryptofacil]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/new-exchange-listing-cryptofacil-18519842153c?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/18519842153c</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[crypto-exchange]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptofacil]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 16:38:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-08-29T16:38:52.514Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>New Exchange Listing — Cryptofacil</h3><p><em>QRL is now trading on Cryptofacil</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*4ONZdAvc_jE_ut4wJHKkGQ.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>As we wrote in our most recent <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-august-20-26-142d9af2835f">blog</a>, we at QRL are always looking for new opportunities to expand the reasonable coverage area for liquidity for our users. We are also looking to deepen that coverage where and how it can serve the greater good. We are happy to announce that both of those ends are properly pursued with the listing of QRL on the Cryptofacil trading platform.</p><h3>What Is Cryptofacil?</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*BvRPPTUfVpU5t8bt9je0Mg.png" /></figure><p>Cryptofacil is an exchange that is primarily targeted at the Latin American market. It’s name, Cryptofacil, means “easy crypto” in Spanish and Portugese, and the exchange aims to bring large numbers of digital assets to the Latin American and Caribbean markets. Founded in 2018, Cryptofacil has developed a digital asset trading platform in Spanish, Portuguese and English.</p><p>Regarding their partnership with Bittrex, Andres Szafran, Cryptofacil’s co-founder stated:</p><blockquote>“This partnership with Bittrex positions Cryptofacil as a leader in the Latin America and Caribbean digital asset markets, with an offering of more than 270 token pairings. With a unique user interface, our platform will allow our customers to manage trades in a simple way, with premium services and competitive market fees. We developed Cryptofacil to focus on basic customer requirements: a simple and easy to use cryptocurrency platform with superior customer support and value-added services in a safe and secure environment. Our goal is to become the crypto exchange of record and the most reputable platform in Latin America and the Caribbean.”</blockquote><p>Cryptofacil, along with exchanges like UpBit and Rain, create a large international network of exchanges partnered with Bittrex. Bittrex CEO Bill Shihara:</p><blockquote>“Bittrex works every day to advance blockchain technology and this partnership with Cryptofacil will further drive its worldwide adoption. Cryptofacil and Bittrex will provide Latin American and Caribbean customers a reliable, fast and secure trading platform that also offers access to some of the world’s most innovative blockchain projects. As we continue expanding our global footprint, it is partnerships like this one that will serve to not only support the blockchain industry, but also to incubate innovative projects using this revolutionary technology.”</blockquote><h3>How Do I Access QRL on Cryptofacil?</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/608/1*hk_e7W6T5tsAIE2ytLI2AA.png" /></figure><p>With over 250 digital assets available on its platform, Cryptofacil is one of the largest exchanges in the Latin American, a region with around 640,000,000 people. You can also buy QRL with a credit card, indirectly. Cryptofacil made it easy to <a href="https://cryptofacil.com/comprar-bitcoin-btc-tarjeta-visa-mastercard">buy bitcoin with a credit card (Visa and Mastercard)</a>. Your bitcoin will be deposited on your Cryptofacil account, where you’ll be able to trade it for QRL. You can head over to their website to <a href="https://cryptofacil.com/sign-up">make an account today</a>. Or, if you already have an account, you can trade the <a href="https://cryptofacil.com/trading-view/167/BTC-QRL">BTC/QRL pair right now</a>.</p><p>We are very excited for this new market, and are happy to report that QRL now has readily available liquidity on 5 continents!</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=18519842153c" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/new-exchange-listing-cryptofacil-18519842153c">New Exchange Listing — Cryptofacil</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL August 20 — 26]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-august-20-26-142d9af2835f?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/142d9af2835f</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cointiger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 20:45:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-08-26T20:45:04.533Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL August 20 — 26</h3><p><em>Development Updates, New Exchange Listing</em></p><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Over the course of last week, we saw QRL integrated into the CoinTiger trading platform. While we are still looking for more liquidity for our users, we are happy to have added another option at this time. We wrote a blog on it — you can check that out <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/cointiger-trading-is-live-today-ad65d741c3be">here</a>. This week was slightly lighter on development than most, as a few developers were out of town.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*fJuyiylFc6FOZsiBPJg5-w.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>mobile-wallet:</strong> Beta release of v2</li><li><strong>theqrl.org: </strong>Search engine optimization — SEO</li></ul><h3>New Exchange Listing — CoinTiger</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*8tI1WGxsPY-Xv3JW1zUD3Q.png" /></figure><p>CoinTiger is the latest exchange to list QRL, bringing the liquidity options for QRL users to <a href="https://bittrex.com/Market/Index?MarketName=BTC-QRL">Bittrex</a>, <a href="https://upbit.com/exchange?code=CRIX.UPBIT.BTC-QRL">UpBit</a>, and <a href="https://www.cointiger.com/en-us/#/trade_pro?coin=qrl_btc">CoinTiger</a>. Deposits went live the 21st, Trading the 22nd, and Withdrawals on the 23rd. We want to assure users that we are not resting on our laurels — we are still looking for more liquidity options.</p><p>CoinTiger is based in Asia, and should afford users both within and outside of Asia a new opportunity to trade QRL should they desire. CoinTiger is a crypto-to-crypto exchange that offers pairs against their 3 base currencies — BTC, BitCNY, and USDT. Their website also comes in a variety of languages, including English, Simplified Chinese, Japanese, Vietnamese, and Russian. We are excited to see what this additional market brings to the QRL ecosystem.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=142d9af2835f" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-august-20-26-142d9af2835f">Last Week in QRL August 20 — 26</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CoinTiger Trading is Live Today!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/cointiger-trading-is-live-today-ad65d741c3be?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/ad65d741c3be</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cointiger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 18:12:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-08-22T18:12:09.859Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Deposits went live 8/21, Trading is live 8/22, Withdrawals live 8/23</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*F3lPPhKLcWQY0SpK1S67Sg.png" /></figure><p>As the above graphic illustrates, yesterday, today, and tomorrow QRL will be integrated into the <a href="https://www.cointiger.com/en-us/#/login">CoinTiger</a> exchange platform. As you can see on their <a href="https://medium.com/@cointiger/cointiger-will-list-quantum-resistant-ledger-qrl-at-16-00-on-22-8-2019-utc-8-100k-qrl-token-5335ad9816cf">Medium post</a> announcing the integration, and our <a href="https://twitter.com/QRLedger/status/1164458435330469888">subsequent tweet</a> at 8:00am UTC this morning, QRL is now live to be <a href="https://www.cointiger.com/en-us/#/trade_pro?coin=qrl_btc">traded on CoinTiger</a>. CoinTiger will be running a few promotions, including a trading competition, over the first week following the listing. You can find details on all that <a href="https://support.cointiger.one/hc/en-us/articles/360034680493-CoinTiger-Will-List-Quantum-Resistant-Ledger-QRL-at-16-00-on-22-8-2019-UTC-8-100K-QRL-Token-to-Give-Away-">here</a>.</p><p>Liquidity has always been seen by the QRL team as a necessary component for a healthy, functioning, low-friction ecosystem. We are also keenly aware that acquiring more liquidity options for our users has been one of the top discussed issues in our <a href="https://discord.gg/zbAJ9YV">Discord server</a>, as well as one of the top requested additions to the ecosystem across all our social media.</p><p>Speaking more generally, liquidity is a balancing act. If a given asset is available to be traded on many platforms, but those platforms themselves are largely distinct and unconnected from one another, then issues of low liquidity, an unrepresentative amount of volatility, and even arbitrage can occur. Conversely, to have all of one’s liquidity eggs in one basket may pool volume, but it obviously exposes an asset to the potential of having its liquidity massively affected should that singular exchange be hacked, or shut down. Even less extreme events, like if it were to change trading minimums, deposit/withdrawal minimums, and/or fee schedules can affect its trading environment.</p><p>We are all excited about this new liquidity opportunity for our users and would like to thank the CoinTiger team for its help in integration.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=ad65d741c3be" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/cointiger-trading-is-live-today-ad65d741c3be">CoinTiger Trading is Live Today!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL August 13–19]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-august-13-19-87e441bcc5e1?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/87e441bcc5e1</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[tipbot]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 18:27:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-08-19T18:27:06.095Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Ephemeral Messaging System, Tip Bot</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*4vNUqueeRkGfLcKmui3B5Q.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>We are now almost through with the dog days of Summer (July 12 — August 20 this year). The team has had some very productive conversations around ways we can optimize some of our resources lately (such as SEO with the website). We are excited to implement some of these changes, and indeed the background work on many of them has already begun. Below is the best of what we can discuss from the past week at QRL.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ElH1TzAM8c0S2OegFB2XoQ.jpeg" /></figure><p>Note: It has been slightly more quiet a development week as many folks are on vacation, taking some well-earned rest during some of the hottest times of the year.</p><ul><li><strong>theqrl.org:</strong> Search engine optimization - SEO</li><li><strong>theqrl.org:</strong> Update papers.yml</li><li><strong>ephemeral:</strong> Final draft of EMS whitepaper</li></ul><h3>Ephemeral Messaging System — Whitepaper</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/922/1*DXhmyldlPrk7qK-cX-ERmQ.png" /></figure><p>As indicated above, the final draft of the Ephemeral Messaging System (EMS) whitepaper has been <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/ephemeral/blob/dc6165642a23e2cc3569d996a69edaba7461c88c/EMS_whitepaper_v1.pdf">posted to our GitHub</a>. We are very happy to see what the community thinks of it, and to continue to advance the EMS, which has been a feature we have wanted to add to the chain since its inception.</p><p>As a brief review, the Ephemeral Messaging System is meant to be a means by which QRL users can leverage the security of the network, while sending messages that are not themselves stored on the network (hence the name Ephemeral — which means “ lasting for a very short time”). We are very excited at the potential of EMS to meaningfully add utility to the QRL ecosystem.</p><h3>Tip Bot</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*de4c63Mfvyo0EeU2uS_9YQ.png" /></figure><p>Various bots have been under discussion since the earliest days of QRL as potential ways to both build out the functionality of the chain, as well as help connect the various elements of our online presence. A favorite topic of discussion has been a Tip Bot. We are happy to report that progress has been made on this front, with Discord, Reddit, and Twitter being identified as the initial 3 platforms on which it will operate.</p><p>Aside from that, there is always the helpful QRL Discord Butler-Bot (and his somewhat less useful but nonetheless entertaining 3rd party cohort, MathBot), which anyone who has spent time in the <a href="https://discord.gg/zbAJ9YV">QRL Discord</a> should be somewhat familiar with. I’d like to personally highlight the efforts of James (Fr1t2 on Discord) and <a href="https://medium.com/u/17213e804a43">Jack Matier</a> (Jackalyst on Discord) on the Tip Bot and Butler-Bot respectively — without them, we would not have achieved the progress on this front that we have.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=87e441bcc5e1" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-august-13-19-87e441bcc5e1">Last Week in QRL August 13–19</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL August 6–12]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-august-6-12-538368c2e141?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/538368c2e141</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 18:24:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-08-12T18:24:56.779Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Updates to FAQQ.info</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*r_nkQQqnPHLHs2eqXs9hTA.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Following the highly productive QRL Developer’s Summit at the start of the month, the team has been abuzz with ideas, both those brought up at the Summit, as well as others that were inspired in its aftermath. We have also updated the <a href="https://faqq.info/">FAQQ.info</a> (more information on that below), as we continue to try to fight ignorance surrounding the subject of quantum computing and blockchain technology.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*jcQ1cHGTQ08md1POKyNN8Q.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>go-qrl: </strong>Fix - Disconnection caused by Fetch Block request from other peer</li><li><strong>docs.theqrl.org:</strong> Fixes to Node document and typo in Ledger Document</li><li><strong>qrl-cli: </strong>Adding descriptions to commands</li></ul><h3>FAQQ.info</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*w7E1HYE7wMjL50-tQ9CVrw.png" /></figure><p>One of the most productive contributions from the QRL community so far is <a href="https://faqq.info/">FAQQ.info </a>(Frequently Asked Quantum Questions). As its title implies, it is an FAQ for questions dealing with the intersection of quantum computing and blockchain. Given the unfortunate regularity with which we still continue to encounter otherwise educated individuals for whom quantum computing is a blind spot, FAQQ.info addresses a very real need in the market; education. The site has continued to be iterated upon, and has recently added information to a few sections, including:</p><ul><li><a href="https://faqq.info/bitcoin-has-plans-for-this/">Bitcoin has plans for this</a></li><li><a href="https://faqq.info/but-bitcoin-will-hardfork/">Bitcoin will hardfork</a></li><li><a href="https://faqq.info/but-bitcoin-will-softfork/">Bitcoin will softfork</a></li><li><a href="https://faqq.info/not-reusing-addresses-not-a-solution/">Reusing addresses</a></li><li><a href="https://faqq.info/quantum-computing-is-coming/">QC is far away</a></li><li><a href="https://faqq.info/quantum-computing-will-affect-bitcoin/">It’s going to affect Bitcoin</a></li><li><a href="https://faqq.info/what-about-banks/">What about the banks</a></li></ul><p>As always, you can track the changes made to the site on our <a href="https://github.com/theqrl-community/faqq/pull/2">QRL Community GitHub</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=538368c2e141" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-august-6-12-538368c2e141">Last Week in QRL August 6–12</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL: July 30th — August 5th]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-july-30th-august-5th-9ebeff44d981?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/9ebeff44d981</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 21:46:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-08-07T07:24:24.148Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/994/1*JxvmwlHQ448uxZcmb3r9XQ.png" /></figure><h3>Last Week in QRL: July 30th — August 5th</h3><h4>A review of the QRL core developer meetup summary, a launch of the QRL community github, and the July QRL community nomination.</h4><h3>Developer Meetup</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*A-IGUW98UyLZOkXvOeN6jA.jpeg" /></figure><p>The QRL core developers met in the UK on the 3rd and 4rth of August. In attendance was:</p><ul><li><strong>JP Lomas </strong><br>Core / Full stack developer</li><li><strong>Leon Groot Bruinderink</strong><br>PhD student Post-quantum Cryptographer</li><li><strong>Peter Waterland</strong><br>Core developer</li><li><strong>James Gordon </strong><br>Technical Writer</li><li><strong>Kaushal Kumar Singh</strong><br>Core developer<br>note: attended virtually.</li></ul><p>Previous blog can be found <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-developer-meetup-6ef3189a6da1">here</a>. Discussed was a wide variety of developer related topics from the next Hard fork, to PoS, to NIST Signature Schemes, and Ephemeral messaging. A full breakdown will be found in future blog(s), a <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/dev-meetings/blob/master/2019/08/03-04.md">few highlights of the development meeting</a> are below.</p><h4>Ephemeral messaging</h4><p>A draft of the Ephemeral Message paper was put together for circulation to a limited audience for feedback and review.</p><h4>Hard Fork status</h4><p><strong>The decision has been made to proceed with a hard fork following a code audit. </strong>This will allow the creation of the Ephemeral Message Layer applications.</p><p>In addition to this, the hard fork will include:</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/pull/5">Deterministic addresses</a> (QIP003)</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/pull/7">Multisignature addresses</a> (QIP004)</li><li>On-chain voting/polls (QIP in draft)</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/pull/8">Extended message transaction functionality</a> (QIP005)</li></ul><p>Feedback is still welcome on many of these QIPS!</p><h4>Proof-of-Stake</h4><p>Future potential PoS schemes were discussed in detail with the evolution of our previous protocol. <strong>A separate PoS/EMS testnet will be created.</strong></p><p>Quantum Resistant Verifiable Random number Function (QR-VRF) research ongoing and undertaken in parallel with consensus algorithm implementation with XMSS. QR-VRF is important as at the heart of PoS is the ability to fairly choose ‘winners’ at random.</p><h4>Development roadmap</h4><p>Existing development roadmap reviewed. Core team expansion to facilitate new plans discussed.</p><p>Know golang? Get in touch at jobs@theqrl.org — full job description below. We’re initially seeking those inside the QRL community who are familiar with the project, however, will expand our search should candidates not be found.</p><p><strong>Job description</strong></p><p>We’re seeking two golang developers that think they’re able to fit the description below. If you’re interested but <em>don’t fit</em> every specification, don’t let that shy you away, it is a <em>wishlist</em> afterall.</p><p>What you will do:</p><ul><li>Write industrial grade open source code that will be the backbone of a quantum resistant network.</li><li>Occasionally interact with the community in a polite and conductive manner.</li></ul><p>What we wish you to be:</p><ul><li>You have a graduate degree or higher in computer science or affiliated field.</li><li>You have written high-performance and concurrent applications.</li><li>You have been part of the QRL Community for some time.</li><li>You have p2p implementation experience</li><li>You are familiar with cryptography</li><li>You have a genuine desire to ensure all code is tested through writing unit and integration tests Compensation</li></ul><p>Competitive based on capability and experience To apply, please send an email to jobs@theqrl.org</p><h4>More</h4><p>There’s more covered in the meeting summary over at github. <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/dev-meetings/blob/master/2019/08/03-04.md">Give it a read,</a> or wait for more content to be drafted and published on our blog.</p><h3>The July QRL community nomination award</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*emHST_KJ1CljJJEYUoMGHg.png" /></figure><p>July’s nomination goes to discord user ‘Strike Attack’, who has been instrumental and gone above and beyond in The QRL Contributors. He has this to say:</p><blockquote>I had first heard about a QC (Quantum Computer) in 1997 while speaking with a colleague. I found the concept fascinating. Conceptually, the theoretical premise of being able to harness the power of nature in order to perform a mathematical function felt visceral and compelling.</blockquote><blockquote>Several years ago, I started to become aware of the accelerating progress being made with quantum computers. After some research, it was not difficult to correlate an existential threat quantum computers presented to existing encryption with blockchain, which has been undergoing undeniable growth. From this, I began researching to see if anyone was addressing this problem ahead of time and came across the QRL Foundation in early 2018, of which a purpose-built solution was already in development. I found the team members professional, knowledgeable, and passionate about the project.</blockquote><p>As an extension to the above statement, he’s written a blog that outlines his full story about how he came to know about quantum computers and QRL in more detail. It’s <a href="https://medium.com/@MichaelStrike1978/i-had-first-heard-about-a-qc-quantum-computer-in-1997-while-speaking-with-a-colleague-8cadc4b16924">well worth a read</a>.</p><p>If you know someone that’s contributed to the QRL ecosystem who you’d like to nominate, you can do so by going to The <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">QRL Discord</a> and nominating in the #butler channel.</p><h3>The QRL Community github</h3><p>Right now there’s theQRL github repository which has strict guidelines. The <a href="https://github.com/theqrl-community">QRL community github</a> is for QRL community related projects that may be a bit “edgier” and might be less tested. Presently, there’s three projects:</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theqrl-community/faqq">faqq.info</a>: Frequently Asked Quantum Questions aims to give an overview of some of the thoughts on quantum computing and blockchain.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theqrl-community/qrlbutler">qrlbutler</a>: The modular bot that is in our discord</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theqrl-community/QCcalc">qccalc</a>: A MATLAB project that generates a probability distribution for the likelihood that 256-bit ECDSA signatures will be ‘broken’ by quantum computer over the course of the coming years.</li></ul><p>Have a project that you’d like to see here or would like to host, get in touch on our <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">discord</a>!</p><h3>The QRL Contributors public release</h3><p>As an update, while no final date has been set for the grand opening, it should be within the next 30 days.</p><p>As a reminder, this is a project that aims to open up discussions and bring in both the core and community contributors alike, and is part of our path for decentralising The QRL <em>community</em> network.More can be read on our blog at: <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-contributors-ed7abd73ab1">https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-contributors-ed7abd73ab1</a></p><p>Stay tuned!</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=9ebeff44d981" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-july-30th-august-5th-9ebeff44d981">Last Week in QRL: July 30th — August 5th</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>