<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Cryptography with longevity. A post-quantum secure blockchain featuring a stateful signature scheme and unparalleled security. - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 07:44:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/the-quantum-resistant-ledger" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL August 6–12]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-august-6-12-538368c2e141?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/538368c2e141</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 18:24:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-08-12T18:24:56.779Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Updates to FAQQ.info</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*r_nkQQqnPHLHs2eqXs9hTA.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Following the highly productive QRL Developer’s Summit at the start of the month, the team has been abuzz with ideas, both those brought up at the Summit, as well as others that were inspired in its aftermath. We have also updated the <a href="https://faqq.info/">FAQQ.info</a> (more information on that below), as we continue to try to fight ignorance surrounding the subject of quantum computing and blockchain technology.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*jcQ1cHGTQ08md1POKyNN8Q.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>go-qrl: </strong>Fix - Disconnection caused by Fetch Block request from other peer</li><li><strong>docs.theqrl.org:</strong> Fixes to Node document and typo in Ledger Document</li><li><strong>qrl-cli: </strong>Adding descriptions to commands</li></ul><h3>FAQQ.info</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*w7E1HYE7wMjL50-tQ9CVrw.png" /></figure><p>One of the most productive contributions from the QRL community so far is <a href="https://faqq.info/">FAQQ.info </a>(Frequently Asked Quantum Questions). As its title implies, it is an FAQ for questions dealing with the intersection of quantum computing and blockchain. Given the unfortunate regularity with which we still continue to encounter otherwise educated individuals for whom quantum computing is a blind spot, FAQQ.info addresses a very real need in the market; education. The site has continued to be iterated upon, and has recently added information to a few sections, including:</p><ul><li><a href="https://faqq.info/bitcoin-has-plans-for-this/">Bitcoin has plans for this</a></li><li><a href="https://faqq.info/but-bitcoin-will-hardfork/">Bitcoin will hardfork</a></li><li><a href="https://faqq.info/but-bitcoin-will-softfork/">Bitcoin will softfork</a></li><li><a href="https://faqq.info/not-reusing-addresses-not-a-solution/">Reusing addresses</a></li><li><a href="https://faqq.info/quantum-computing-is-coming/">QC is far away</a></li><li><a href="https://faqq.info/quantum-computing-will-affect-bitcoin/">It’s going to affect Bitcoin</a></li><li><a href="https://faqq.info/what-about-banks/">What about the banks</a></li></ul><p>As always, you can track the changes made to the site on our <a href="https://github.com/theqrl-community/faqq/pull/2">QRL Community GitHub</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=538368c2e141" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-august-6-12-538368c2e141">Last Week in QRL August 6–12</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL: July 30th — August 5th]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-july-30th-august-5th-9ebeff44d981?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/9ebeff44d981</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 21:46:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-08-07T07:24:24.148Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/994/1*JxvmwlHQ448uxZcmb3r9XQ.png" /></figure><h3>Last Week in QRL: July 30th — August 5th</h3><h4>A review of the QRL core developer meetup summary, a launch of the QRL community github, and the July QRL community nomination.</h4><h3>Developer Meetup</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*A-IGUW98UyLZOkXvOeN6jA.jpeg" /></figure><p>The QRL core developers met in the UK on the 3rd and 4rth of August. In attendance was:</p><ul><li><strong>JP Lomas </strong><br>Core / Full stack developer</li><li><strong>Leon Groot Bruinderink</strong><br>PhD student Post-quantum Cryptographer</li><li><strong>Peter Waterland</strong><br>Core developer</li><li><strong>James Gordon </strong><br>Technical Writer</li><li><strong>Kaushal Kumar Singh</strong><br>Core developer<br>note: attended virtually.</li></ul><p>Previous blog can be found <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-developer-meetup-6ef3189a6da1">here</a>. Discussed was a wide variety of developer related topics from the next Hard fork, to PoS, to NIST Signature Schemes, and Ephemeral messaging. A full breakdown will be found in future blog(s), a <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/dev-meetings/blob/master/2019/08/03-04.md">few highlights of the development meeting</a> are below.</p><h4>Ephemeral messaging</h4><p>A draft of the Ephemeral Message paper was put together for circulation to a limited audience for feedback and review.</p><h4>Hard Fork status</h4><p><strong>The decision has been made to proceed with a hard fork following a code audit. </strong>This will allow the creation of the Ephemeral Message Layer applications.</p><p>In addition to this, the hard fork will include:</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/pull/5">Deterministic addresses</a> (QIP003)</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/pull/7">Multisignature addresses</a> (QIP004)</li><li>On-chain voting/polls (QIP in draft)</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/pull/8">Extended message transaction functionality</a> (QIP005)</li></ul><p>Feedback is still welcome on many of these QIPS!</p><h4>Proof-of-Stake</h4><p>Future potential PoS schemes were discussed in detail with the evolution of our previous protocol. <strong>A separate PoS/EMS testnet will be created.</strong></p><p>Quantum Resistant Verifiable Random number Function (QR-VRF) research ongoing and undertaken in parallel with consensus algorithm implementation with XMSS. QR-VRF is important as at the heart of PoS is the ability to fairly choose ‘winners’ at random.</p><h4>Development roadmap</h4><p>Existing development roadmap reviewed. Core team expansion to facilitate new plans discussed.</p><p>Know golang? Get in touch at jobs@theqrl.org — full job description below. We’re initially seeking those inside the QRL community who are familiar with the project, however, will expand our search should candidates not be found.</p><p><strong>Job description</strong></p><p>We’re seeking two golang developers that think they’re able to fit the description below. If you’re interested but <em>don’t fit</em> every specification, don’t let that shy you away, it is a <em>wishlist</em> afterall.</p><p>What you will do:</p><ul><li>Write industrial grade open source code that will be the backbone of a quantum resistant network.</li><li>Occasionally interact with the community in a polite and conductive manner.</li></ul><p>What we wish you to be:</p><ul><li>You have a graduate degree or higher in computer science or affiliated field.</li><li>You have written high-performance and concurrent applications.</li><li>You have been part of the QRL Community for some time.</li><li>You have p2p implementation experience</li><li>You are familiar with cryptography</li><li>You have a genuine desire to ensure all code is tested through writing unit and integration tests Compensation</li></ul><p>Competitive based on capability and experience To apply, please send an email to jobs@theqrl.org</p><h4>More</h4><p>There’s more covered in the meeting summary over at github. <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/dev-meetings/blob/master/2019/08/03-04.md">Give it a read,</a> or wait for more content to be drafted and published on our blog.</p><h3>The July QRL community nomination award</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*emHST_KJ1CljJJEYUoMGHg.png" /></figure><p>July’s nomination goes to discord user ‘Strike Attack’, who has been instrumental and gone above and beyond in The QRL Contributors. He has this to say:</p><blockquote>I had first heard about a QC (Quantum Computer) in 1997 while speaking with a colleague. I found the concept fascinating. Conceptually, the theoretical premise of being able to harness the power of nature in order to perform a mathematical function felt visceral and compelling.</blockquote><blockquote>Several years ago, I started to become aware of the accelerating progress being made with quantum computers. After some research, it was not difficult to correlate an existential threat quantum computers presented to existing encryption with blockchain, which has been undergoing undeniable growth. From this, I began researching to see if anyone was addressing this problem ahead of time and came across the QRL Foundation in early 2018, of which a purpose-built solution was already in development. I found the team members professional, knowledgeable, and passionate about the project.</blockquote><p>As an extension to the above statement, he’s written a blog that outlines his full story about how he came to know about quantum computers and QRL in more detail. It’s <a href="https://medium.com/@MichaelStrike1978/i-had-first-heard-about-a-qc-quantum-computer-in-1997-while-speaking-with-a-colleague-8cadc4b16924">well worth a read</a>.</p><p>If you know someone that’s contributed to the QRL ecosystem who you’d like to nominate, you can do so by going to The <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">QRL Discord</a> and nominating in the #butler channel.</p><h3>The QRL Community github</h3><p>Right now there’s theQRL github repository which has strict guidelines. The <a href="https://github.com/theqrl-community">QRL community github</a> is for QRL community related projects that may be a bit “edgier” and might be less tested. Presently, there’s three projects:</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theqrl-community/faqq">faqq.info</a>: Frequently Asked Quantum Questions aims to give an overview of some of the thoughts on quantum computing and blockchain.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theqrl-community/qrlbutler">qrlbutler</a>: The modular bot that is in our discord</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theqrl-community/QCcalc">qccalc</a>: A MATLAB project that generates a probability distribution for the likelihood that 256-bit ECDSA signatures will be ‘broken’ by quantum computer over the course of the coming years.</li></ul><p>Have a project that you’d like to see here or would like to host, get in touch on our <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">discord</a>!</p><h3>The QRL Contributors public release</h3><p>As an update, while no final date has been set for the grand opening, it should be within the next 30 days.</p><p>As a reminder, this is a project that aims to open up discussions and bring in both the core and community contributors alike, and is part of our path for decentralising The QRL <em>community</em> network.More can be read on our blog at: <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-contributors-ed7abd73ab1">https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-contributors-ed7abd73ab1</a></p><p>Stay tuned!</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=9ebeff44d981" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-july-30th-august-5th-9ebeff44d981">Last Week in QRL: July 30th — August 5th</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The QRL Developer Meetup]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-developer-meetup-6ef3189a6da1?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/6ef3189a6da1</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[proof-of-stake]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 23:19:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-08-02T23:19:31.075Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*UVexxXe47Kv5KYfs7NGz2w.jpeg" /><figcaption>by Pixabay user geralt: <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/geralt-9301/">https://pixabay.com/users/geralt-9301/</a></figcaption></figure><p>The QRL core developers are a diverse group of people spanning across many different continents and timezones. While there’s a weekly meeting to talk with each other, meeting in person can increase the productivity of discourse <em>substantially</em>.</p><p>It is for this reason that The QRL developers are meeting for two days on the <strong>3rd and 4th of August </strong>(tomorrow as of this blog) to discuss the upcoming fork, consensus mechanisms (primarily proof-of-stake and its derivations), and other developer related topics.</p><h3>Those in attendance</h3><ul><li><strong>JP Lomas </strong><br>Core / Full stack developer</li><li><strong>Kaushal Kumar Singh</strong><br>Core developer</li><li><strong>Peter Waterland</strong><br>Core developer</li><li><strong>James Gordon </strong><br>Technical Writer</li><li><strong>Leon Groot Bruinderink</strong><br>PhD student Post-quantum Cryptographer</li></ul><h3>Topics of discussion</h3><p>The big highlight of this developer meetup is going to be the <strong>consensus protocol</strong>. Since the genesis of our project, Proof of Stake has been one of the core features that’s been on the roadmap since as far back as February 20th, 2017, when it was first introduced to the <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/QRL/commit/c5a8ff10be841523fb43b821714e939540901f0f">QRL codebase</a>.</p><p>While the consensus protocol will be the topic de jour, the weekend will also comprise of everything in the upcoming hardforks and more, including:</p><ul><li>Smart Contracts / Addresses</li><li>Ephemeral Messaging</li><li>Multisig addresses</li><li>Deterministic address support</li><li>Extended message transaction functionality</li><li>Decentralized on-chain poll support</li><li>Hardfork scheduling / frequency</li></ul><p>May a consensus be reached!</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*fXf1ao0LA4SmbEGezIlSbw.png" /><figcaption>Sneak peak of some feature logos in development</figcaption></figure><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=6ef3189a6da1" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-developer-meetup-6ef3189a6da1">The QRL Developer Meetup</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL July 23–29, 2019]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-july-23-29-2019-941c2936f130?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/941c2936f130</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain-development]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[exchange]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 18:44:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-07-29T18:44:18.185Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Confirmed Exchange Listing, QRL Dev Summit next week</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*vSRBIwa0NZwRtOk-EfXEAw.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>As July draws to a close, we are just one week away from the QRL Developer Summit. Pursuant to that, much of the past week has been spent in preparation for the summit, as well as working on securing additional liquidity (more on this below). We are happy to report progress on both fronts, and are very excited for the developments happening both within our platform and the more general QRL ecosystem in the near future.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*gIGWGdPvBRJWdq8JiTq0QA.png" /></figure><ul><li><strong>block-explorer: </strong>Show keybase transactions in lasttx and unconfirmed tx views</li><li><strong>qrl-cli: </strong>adds WIP OTS command</li><li><strong>docs.theqrl.org: </strong>Fixes to Node document and typo in Ledger Document</li></ul><h3>Confirmed: Exchange Listing</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*-TQV8Ji38KpZdDh_uYu3BA.jpeg" /><figcaption>Note: Image is not of the exchange</figcaption></figure><p>Liquidity is a necessary element for a fully healthy and largely frictionless ecosystem. We have heard concerns from the community about having limited markets available to trade Quanta, and we recognize those concerns. Given the at-times quickly shifting topography of the cryptocurrency exchange landscape, being wholly dependent on a single exchange for liquidity can be perilous.</p><p>We are therefore happy to report that there will be an announcement in the next few weeks regarding QRL being added to another exchange. While we cannot reveal the specific exchange or specific date at this time, we wanted to report the happy news as soon as we were able. Once we are able to go public with all the details, we will announce them on all our major social media platforms.</p><h3>Upcoming QRL Developer Summit</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/640/1*ERo4QWsYrEzATY9o1HS-vA.jpeg" /></figure><p>As mentioned in last week’s blog, later this week and into early next week, the QRL Developers will be gathering in Europe to work and discuss in person. With such an international project, stretching from North America to Europe to India to Australia, real-time collaboration can be a challenge. When we have digital meetings it is always early in the morning for some, very late at night for others. Understandably, that makes communication somewhat slower than it might otherwise be.</p><p>The QRL Developer Summit will allow our very talented developers to work at the same time, in the same place, and accomplish more in less time than usual. The main topic of the summit is Proof-of-Stake and its many manifestations. We will have more to report in the coming weeks (our very next blog will almost overlap with the summit so we may not be entirely ready to report then) regarding what is accomplished at the summit. Stay tuned — there will quite possibly be a blog wholly dedicated to it.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=941c2936f130" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-july-23-29-2019-941c2936f130">Last Week in QRL July 23–29, 2019</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL July 16–22]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-july-16-22-587cca5cb89c?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/587cca5cb89c</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cli]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 19:57:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-07-22T19:57:56.838Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Development Spotlight — Command Line Interface</em></p><h3>Introduction</h3><p>As we move into the final week of July, plans for the QRL developer summit in August have been largely laid out, with only the details remaining. As mentioned in the AMA and elsewhere, this gathering of the QRL developers will be focused on Proof-Of-Stake, and will occur in Europe in August. It represents the first time that all of the developers will be in one physical location, as well as the largest gathering of QRL team members to date. We will have more on what comes of that developer summit once it has come and gone. For now, here is some of what went on last week.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*DQi6RXNonqobovCZNSbs3w.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>qrl-cli: </strong>fix: zip release assets</li><li><strong>go-qrl:</strong> Added lock before initializing Downloader</li><li><strong>QRL:</strong> Merged Dev</li></ul><h3>Development Spotlight — The QRL CLI</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/916/1*UwHBJMwLRaKWB_8RlSp8Ng.gif" /></figure><p>One of the many exciting developments being worked on by the talented team of QRL developers is the <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-cli">QRL Command Line Interface</a> (CLI). For the less technically inclined, a CLI is a text-based user interface used to view and/or manage computer files.</p><p>CLIs are an integral tool in the toolbox of a properly mature network. Not everybody wants to download a whole QRL node, or familiarize themselves with a node package manager or golang to be able to access the power of the <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/api.theqrl.org">QRL API</a> and ecosystem. In addition, there are environments in which it makes more sense to run commands in a self-contained fashion locally (network attached), and in the context of an advanced administrator to interoperate with other programs.</p><p>One example of a use-case would be an executable function to notarize documents on the QRL blockchain. More features are being added stage-by-stage, aiming to give access to the full suite of features of the platform by the time of public release.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=587cca5cb89c" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-july-16-22-587cca5cb89c">Last Week in QRL July 16–22</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL July 8–15]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-july-8-15-17a237a87d6a?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/17a237a87d6a</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl-contributors]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain-development]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 20:06:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-07-15T20:06:43.606Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, The QRL Contributors</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*eo9zWl1NAd6U76bdB837WA.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>This past week saw lots of activity behind-the-scenes at QRL, specifically in the realm of planning. Unfortunately, we cannot intimately discuss most of what those plans entail, aside from saying that we have taken in the feedback we have received of late, including the AMA, and are working to address much of it. Indeed, efforts were already underway in regards to some of the concerns, just not in a manner that we could explicitly disclose. The best of what we can discuss is below.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ElH1TzAM8c0S2OegFB2XoQ.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>mobile-wallet:</strong> Improvements for mobile wallet v2</li><li><strong>go-qrl:</strong> [MongoDB] Fix Transfer Token Transaction</li><li><strong>theqrl.org:</strong> Mention XMSS yields reusable addresses</li></ul><h3>The QRL Contributors</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/640/1*W97RMZ6AjIn5x6_UzzrOHg.jpeg" /></figure><p>The <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-contributors-ed7abd73ab1">QRL Contributors</a> consists primarily of roles, working groups, and projects. Like last week, we’d like to offer a glimpse into something from the server in today’s blog. Today we will be featuring a project, which are supposed to draw on one or multiple working groups to see them to their conclusion.</p><h4>Project: Tip Bot</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/543/1*3JjoFZrEnSWZyEQzUoXdjg.png" /></figure><p><strong>Scope</strong></p><p>Build a system that will interface with multiple social media platform API interfaces, to create a bridge to a working QRL node and wallet, allowing a user to send a tip to another user on the platform. The system should create a new address for a user even if they have not interacted with the bot. The bot would notify the user via DM that they have funds waiting and give clear instructions on how to withdraw.</p><p><strong>Main Goals</strong></p><ul><li>Allow users to tip</li><li>Stores multiple social media accounts to the same address for a single user</li><li>Allows the user to deposit and withdraw using social media platform</li><li>Reports stats to the user when requested ie: balance, total tipped, total received</li><li>Server that stores private keys should be secure and fully backed up. Bonus if somehow the data was stored on-chain and was able to be rebuilt upon catastrophe.</li><li>Web interface and domain to log into and interact with the bot to withdraw, deposit, check stats and tip users via Email?</li><li>Something similar to how keybase.io have integrated stellar to a keybase username. Allowing a user to tip via chat.</li></ul><p>We are very excited for when The QRL Contributors fully launches, as we believe it will make the path to supporting QRL clearer, to those who are interested.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=17a237a87d6a" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-july-8-15-17a237a87d6a">Last Week in QRL July 8–15</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL  July 2nd — 8th]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-july-2nd-8th-f8575ad18a02?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/f8575ad18a02</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 22:02:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-07-08T22:02:59.394Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL July 2nd — 8th</h3><h4>Development and community updates as well as a glimpse at some of The QRL Contributor activity over the last week</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/994/1*23Fc66IuE58V9rQGdRyasw.png" /></figure><h3>Blog Contents</h3><h4>Development</h4><ul><li><a href="#0795">go-qrl</a></li><li><a href="#e8cb">QRL Wallet</a></li><li><a href="#534d">Ledger live</a></li></ul><h4>Community</h4><ul><li><a href="#4081">June community nomination</a></li><li><a href="#d742">AMA Summary</a></li></ul><h4>The QRL Contributors</h4><ul><li><a href="#0572">Overview</a></li><li><a href="#6f14">Working Group: content</a></li></ul><h3>Development</h3><h4>go-qrl</h4><ul><li>Fix: Disconnect from peer when outgoing queue is full</li><li>Fix: Downloader skipping last block</li><li>Added: RecordTransactionHashes in config</li></ul><h4>qrl-wallet</h4><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/">Version 1.2 was released</a> <em>and </em>is now reflected on the front page of theqrl.org website. For those experiencing connection issues with their Ledger Nano X, give this a go.<br><strong>Note: </strong>At this time The QRL is <em>not</em> supporting the <em>bluetooth</em> feature of the Ledger Nano X. We believe this to be too experimental of a feature, and not worth the risk it could produce. <br>We may review this stance once the threat model has evolved a bit.</li></ul><h4>Ledger Live</h4><ul><li>Ledger live is working in developer mode and is very close to being pushed. No guarantees it gets merged however!</li></ul><h3>Community</h3><h4>June nomination</h4><p>Discord user II (two capital i’s) has been nominated for The QRL Nomination award of June, 2019. II states “I stumbled upon QRL by strolling the www” and adds “as an early blockchain enthusiast: I got in”.</p><p>While in The QRL community, II has had an ongoing positive poetic muse that never ceases rally up both the community and the team!</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/707/1*Zyxz5K2e8I35xLxZxGRFtQ.png" /><figcaption>An example of recent composition</figcaption></figure><h4>AMA Summary</h4><p>Part of our 1 year mainnet anniversary celebration was an AMA (Ask Me Anything) where there was a lot of amazing questions (and answers). We look forward to doing it again at a future date.</p><p>The summary of this AMA has been released and can be found <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ama-ask-me-anything-summary-b869e9239c79">here</a>!</p><h3>The QRL Contributors</h3><h4>Overview</h4><p>More work continues to go into ensuring The QRL Contributors is an inclusive and conductive place to be involved in. Some members of the general QRL community who have contributed in the past have also been given an early invite. There’s currently no official public release date of this channel, though it’s looking closer by the day!</p><p>As a reminder, a <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-contributors-ed7abd73ab1">The QRL Contributors</a> essentially consists of roles, working groups, and projects. More about The QRL Contributors can be read about in the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-contributors-ed7abd73ab1">blog</a>.</p><p>From this, we’d like to offer a glimpse into what’s transpired over the last week in <em>one</em> of the working groups below.</p><h4>Working Group: Content</h4><ul><li>More work went into <a href="https://faqq.info/">faqq.info</a>, particularly the <a href="https://faqq.info/quantum-computing-is-coming/">Quantum Computing is Coming</a> page. As a reminder, this site intends to cover an array of questions a person might have about quantum computing and the intersect of blockchain technology in a quick and convincing manner.</li><li>We’re now sitting at 13 sources in our <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Draft:Quantum_Resistant_Ledger">draft stub on wikipedia</a>. We know this has been in the works for a while, but it’s important to get right so everything isn’t rejected outright. <strong>If there’s any wikipedians in the audience that can assist with this in anyway, it would be much appreciated</strong>!</li><li>A draft has been produced about NIST and XMSS by Doney and is undergoing review and further considerations.</li><li>Corrections to messari.io have been submitted.</li><li>Corrections to cryptoslate have been submitted <em>and</em> acted upon.</li></ul><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=f8575ad18a02" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-july-2nd-8th-f8575ad18a02">Last Week in QRL  July 2nd — 8th</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AMA (Ask Me Anything) Summary]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ama-ask-me-anything-summary-b869e9239c79?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/b869e9239c79</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ama]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 21:37:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-07-08T21:37:06.937Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>The QRL Core Contributor Ask Me Anything (AMA) Summary</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/956/1*X_NmmcQjNxOdbp0gJe329A.png" /></figure><p>As part of our mainnet anniversary, we held a QRL Core Contributor AMA which took place in Discord on Monday, July 1st, 2019 for 1 hour.</p><p>From that, the QRL core contributors answered 29 base questions, or roughly 1 question every 2 minutes. This is the summary of that. The full AMA log can be found in Discord <a href="https://discordapp.com/channels/357604137204056065/357604137204056066/595329177541017623">here</a> (note: you may need to open discord first for the link to work properly).</p><h4>Q: <strong>Why the use of broken crypto SHA1 for notarization?</strong></h4><p>Legacy hashing mechanisms are included to maximise use cases: we want it to be easy for any existing proprietary notarisation systems to plug in to using the QRL. These systems are only available to those using the API and not via the web wallet to ensure hashing mechanisms considered unfit for future use are not available to the average user.</p><h4>Q: <strong>Will we get to see the financial statement of the QRL foundation, and when?</strong></h4><p>Foundation statutory reporting is in compliance with the jurisdiction (Switzerland) and the organisational structure (Stiftung). Reports will be published in due course.</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland</strong>: Basically; we have to. It isn’t for debate.</p><h4>Q: <strong>What is your stance on NDA in regards to advisors?</strong></h4><p>As an open source software project, we would prefer all conversations regarding QRL to be open and transparent to all contributors, including advisors. However, we recognise that some partners and potential partners may have legitimate business requirements in keeping discussions confidential. These requests are considered on a case-by-case basis and where as individuals or as an organisation we are subject to an NDA then we will not able to comment on that subject further at this time.</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland:</strong> NDA’s are a necessary evil and pretty much every interaction we have as a project (and individuals) starts with one..this is pretty commonplace in most of the Western world nowadays.</p><p><strong>JP Lomas:</strong> and Eastern world</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland:</strong> Just adding to the NDA point — it’s massively frustrating to us that we are legally unable to discuss many things we would like to..it goes against the open source transparent nature of the project but it is the real world.</p><h4>Q: <strong>Are there any pending legal matters in regards to QRL presale, and ECR20 token distribution?</strong></h4><p>No</p><h4>Q: <strong>How many users are there on the QRL discord server?</strong></h4><p>4929</p><h4>Q: <strong>Can we get web statistics for theQRL.org homepage, block explorer,web wallet, and QRL wallet downloads?</strong></h4><p>Users: 27,728<br>New Users: 27,585<br>Sessions: 41,329<br>Pageviews: 68,024</p><p>Stats for github are a little more involved as it requires going the the API, but they are there. Some sites make an easy interface to access them: <a href="https://www.somsubhra.com/github-release-stats/?username=theQRL&amp;repository=qrl-wallet">https://www.somsubhra.com/github-release-stats/?username=theQRL&amp;repository=qrl-wallet</a></p><h4>Q: <strong>How far off is the hard fork?</strong></h4><p>The code changes for the planned hard fork are in the main completed or near completion and undergoing testing on our devnet. A potential fork includes important governance changes such as on-chain ledger-wide voting and hard coded multisignature wallet capability. We have a developers IRL meetup next month where we will discuss a proposed hard fork schedule for the qrl-node and finalise our POS strategy and rollout. So a significant announcement on this next month (dev meeting is first week of August).</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland:</strong> So we are having a physical meetup in UK, sunny Birmingham next month. So a big ANN then.</p><h4>Q: <strong>Any idea when the probation period of the foundation will be over?</strong></h4><p>The Foundation’s supervision by the GS-EDI is important in the maintenance of the not-for-profit organisational structure. This ongoing dialogue should have minimal effect on ongoing development.</p><p><strong>JP Lomas:</strong> slow to deal with, but terribly diligent — we are fortunate to have good representation at that end</p><h4>Q: <strong>Estimate of the start of the goqrl audit?</strong></h4><p>As an open source project we have worked with OSTIF and pride ourselves on previous major audits completed prior to major milestone releases such as mainnet. This does inevitability add an element of delay to the roadmap but is good practice and therefore currently we are planning an audit prior to POS release, especially as the primary supported programming language will be golang.</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland:</strong> Basically we weren’t planning an audit for the go-qrl node per se, as the next release will be hugely different and will require another full code-audit.</p><p><strong>JP Lomas:</strong> OSTIF partner with x41 amongst others, and provide a valuable contribution to the open source community.</p><h4>Q: <strong>Will the PoS be a completely new algo from scratch or will you be able to build from the “old” PoS version you coded prior to the mainnet with PoW?</strong></h4><p>As a team we created a new novel hash-based pq-secure POS algorithm in 2017 (whitepaper on github for the interested) which due to concerns in overly delaying mainnet was temporarily put on hold to allow successful launch with POW instead. It has always been our position to return to this once the network reached maturity.</p><p>Our first iteration of POS was fairly CPU hungry and is now fairly simplistic given there are several new validated sophisticated algorithms from other major crypto assets planned or in production already. We are meeting next month in the UK to finalise our proposed algorithm (updated whitepaper to be published) and revive the POS devnet effort.</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland:</strong> So, again ANN regarding POS roadmap/timeline first week of August. Personally really excited about this..</p><h4>Q: <strong>Was the asian exchange which will be listing qrl “as soon as its practical” in contact with qrl for some time, or was the connection established because of the geofencing?</strong></h4><p>Both. We are not able to discuss exchange listings further at this time.</p><h4>Q: <strong>Are there any plans for more in depth stats on the explorer ? If so what is planned?</strong></h4><p>Yes. The existing explorer queries nodes directly. V2 of the explorer is an indexer, which allows for richer querying of the chain data. Examples of stats available are richlist, transactions and address demographics. Requests for statistics are welcomed via Github — either as a QIP (ideally) or via Issue on the block-explorer repo. Version two of the explorer is a scalable very powerful sequel to the existing explorer which will allow a much richer experience for the end user and further enable private enterprise usage.</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland:</strong> So JP can come in here, but V2 is in basically a different league to the existing explorer both in terms of functionality and, dare I say it, visibly (ducks for cover)</p><p><strong>JP Lomas:</strong> Ledger integration slowed us down with this but hopefully headed back on track for now</p><p><strong>JP Lomas:</strong> So please see above and dump ideas somewhere useful — QIP or Github.</p><h4>Q: <strong>Are there any other known network explorers being developed?</strong></h4><p>The Foundation has supported the development of V2 explorer previously mentioned. It is worth mentioning this has a completely new clean look and is (obviously) far more performant than the existing site.</p><h4>Q: <strong>Are there any known QRT’s planned for private/public usage?</strong></h4><p>We view PQ-secure digital asset storage as a major commercial boon for the crypo-asset space over the medium and longer term. We are not able to discuss potential private QRT applications further at this time.</p><h4>Q: <strong>If consensus is changed to POS how will foundation staking be governed?</strong></h4><p>This is a complex and important question as clearly the foundation address is one of the largest addresses on-chain (#2). My personal view is that the foundation funds should stake as for any other large holder, but that how foundation QRL are disbursed is to be decided through on-chain ledger-wide voting in a completely decentralised manner. This is one of the things I think are so exciting about decentralised value transfer networks when there is no one person or organisation in control. Ultimately it should be the users and ledger stake holders who decide what benefits the project moving forwards and therefore control should be voted upon.</p><h4>Q: <strong>How many single points of failure exist in QRL? Many of us saw US blocking exchange as one, how about technology transfer? Let say a dev were to disappear tomorrow, are others able to continue their unfinished job?</strong></h4><p>Risk. Again this is a huge topic of discussion. We held extensive talks and created several action plans to mitigate risks identified prior to launch of mainnet. Liquidity provision is clearly a major factor at present but we are following a plan to overcome this — as suggested previously we are not able to discuss the specifics further at this time (but you can guess).</p><p>Regarding other project risks such as the development team (in part or whole) disappearing — that is certainly a risk to any project. But the network is live, with mining nodes determining the QRL ledger for the last year and into the future. Developers may come and go but as the QRL is licensed open source then other individuals or teams may step in — that is the beauty of cryptocurrency. If you look at github there are actually many contributors who have submitted code in the various iterations of the project and it is likely the team will morph over time as it matures post-POS release and codebase updates become more refined.</p><h4>Q: <strong>Will ephemeral messaging be available as soon as go-qrl is live?</strong></h4><p>The stub functionality to allow ephemeral messaging is already in our devnet codebase. The next major release (which must be a hard fork) will include that capability out of the box. go-qrl is already live and running (experimentally!) on the network.</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland:</strong> Regarding EMS, we have had the stub code in place since launch actually, just without the lattice transaction :/ and to update = hard fork.</p><h4>Q: <strong>Are there some collaboration with other blockchain /coins in the pipeline?</strong></h4><p>There are no collaborative plans with other chains in the pipeline, although the dev team have extensively discussed and debated the idea of a PQ Bitcoin mirror in the event of a black swan ‘Y2Q’ event.</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland</strong>: So this is an interesting one. As a fully PQ-secure ledger we can ‘import’ other chains onto the QRL..</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland</strong>: So it is complicated but can be done..we should probably blog it</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland</strong>: But bitcoiners will scream</p><p><strong>JP Lomas</strong>: (louder)</p><h4>Q: <strong>Will there be some sort of ceo or strong leadership?</strong></h4><p>The QRL is a decentralised public cryptocurrency with an open source codebase for anyone to contribute to. Just like in other projects there is no CEO of the QRL. The foundation will support the development roadmap until such time as this process may be governed on-chain.</p><h4>Q: <strong>Is there already a collaboration between qrl and korona? (I guess it’s cyyber who is a member of both foundations as far as the swiss commercial register states)</strong></h4><p>There is no collaboration between QRL and Korona, which incidentally neither we have never heard of!</p><p><strong>Adam Koltun</strong>: On a personal note, I checked out korona’s .io site. Don’t go there, it’s been hacked or sold.</p><h4><strong>Q: Thoughts about quantum supremacy possibly being achieved this year?</strong></h4><p>The QRL is the first fully post-quantum secure blockchain project in the world. As a technical achievement it has been cited multiple times in the academic literature by cryptographers and blockchain experts. But to paraphrase an old saying, there is no difference between being early and being wrong. At present the progress seen in commercial quantum computer hardware has been largely ignored by the crypto asset space which puts pressure on the value proposition of a public post-quantum secure blockchain ecosystem like the QRL. But the commercial world is already spending huge sums moving to post-quantum secure technology and I would predict soon quantum supremacy will usher in a new and sustained focus on post-quantum security within the crypto-asset space. Soon is of course impossible to define at this stage, so we will build out a completely PQ-secure ecosystem in the interim.</p><p>It is worth noting that exciting progress in public commercial quantum computer development ignores what may be already possible for state-level actors with unlimited resources. (The first QC built to break existing cryptography will be unlike any other computing breakthrough — think of a machine which gives an incorrect answer to a question posed millions, trillions of times before a correct solution appears just for a moment. If a QC can run (supported by classical hardware) for weeks, even months before succeeding in breaking existing cryptographic systems then that is still giant, vast leap forwards.)</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland: </strong>Short version from me, quantum supremacy is coming. Crypto is ignoring it as high volume chains won’t work with large PQ-secure signatures and its a lot more complicated than just swap out the old signature scheme.</p><h4>Q: <strong>Is Peter Waterland ever going to have a video interview with crypto celebs to promote QRL? Come on Peter we want to hear that sexy voice again. Btw is he still involved in the surgeon business? If so, why can’t he just fork out 1 hour of his time to do a simple video interview?</strong></h4><p><strong>Peter Waterland</strong>: Glad to hear my voice was sexy! As the team can attest I actually devote a huge amount of time to the QRL. I’m not particularly comfortable in the media spotlight, it is much more than just me at this point in time, with a vibrant community and dedicated team working hard. But i’m not averse to the occasional interview if the community request it!</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland</strong>: I think moving some of our voluminous team communications [to discord] might be useful, too.</p><h4>Q: <strong>So when quantum computers become powerful enough to break most crypto, that also means they can break any SSL, including logins to servers running nodes, not to mention most of anything that used to be considered secure on the Internet. In the wake of this eventuality, how can QRL protect its own nodes and network? Will there be some period of time when QRL along with every other crypto will simply be unusable just because it relies on infrastructure that is not “quantum resistant”?</strong></h4><p>This depends largely on the speed of transition: a black swan event occurring earlier than anticipated will have differing global impact on networks to a later transition. Certainly the infrastructure around our Ledger will change (as NGOs, academics, companies: NIST, Isara, CQC) when QCs are sufficiently powerful to disrupt on a massive scale, but the core blockchain will remain secure and it this which has intrinsic value.</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland</strong>: I think personally it is more likely that commercial QC’s bring forward changes to every part of the internet in terms of cryptographic security and that will help us immensely. A public crypto theft is still quite unlikely atm.</p><p><strong>JP Lomas</strong>: And the emerging industry around that will give us airtime by proxy.</p><h4>Q: <strong>Out of 10, where does the team rate the current development of QRL blockchain? Was the team expecting to have done more or less by now?</strong></h4><p>All team members will have different opinions. As a group we’re passionate and perfectionist so there will always be things we could do and perhaps should have done better. Hindsight is wonderful, but we are confident that we have made the best development decisions for the right reasons going forward. The quality of the technical product is and has always been the overall team priority. There has been a lot of events in the space that have been completely outside our control but we have achieved more with a fraction of the resources than most of the projects in the space.</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland</strong>: I think our roadmap is a process and we are moving along it. Not launching with POS was a setback but we got past that and now have a decent ecosystem including Ledger and mobile support. Lots more coming, too.</p><h4>Q: <strong>Based on the above, how confident is the team to deliver on time the current roadmap expectations?</strong></h4><p>As always, we try and predict timescales and deliver to them. Though we too get frustrated by slipped deadlines, we will always consider what we think it in the best interests of the project over anything else.</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland:</strong> We will get to the end of the roadmap. Eventually! :-). On that note we are looking to expand the dev team.</p><h4>Q: <strong>Can you comment on what you see as the most helpful things the community can do to push this project forward?</strong></h4><p>Spread the word and bring smart people our way. We don’t have the massive financial lure the larger (over-the-top) well-funded projects have, but we do have solid technology, an interesting and varied roadmap and some of the nicest team members in open source to work with.</p><p>The community contributions have massively accelerated our capabilities to get word out. In a world of ‘fake news’ and an industry of fraud and exit scams, our strength lies in solid participation of polite, well-informed and helpful community members.</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland</strong>: There are only a few completely new codebases backing crypto projects in the space and none with crypto quite as odd as ours.</p><h4>Q: <strong>What efforts are being done to attract more devs to the project? And can the devs help try to reach out to others in the dev community to build on QRL?</strong></h4><p>There are several projects underway to attract more developers. Updating APIs to make it easier to interact with (and therefore build on) the chain are key in this: watch out for our new API bridge, codenamed “Brooklyn” and a new “getting going developing with the QRL” tutorial for starters. Again, word of mouth here is key, so if you know smart people send them our way!</p><p><strong>Peter Waterland:</strong> It’s tough to find new people. Really tough.</p><h4>Q: <strong>How many team members are working “full time” on QRL?</strong></h4><p>It varies depending on the needs of the project and what the definition of “full time” is. Team members are all contracted to provide services to the project as required to hit milestones. At peak development, we had 11 people contributing the equivalent of full time work in the run up to main-net. Keeping this number of “full time” individuals 12 months a year would not be a sensible use of resources or good for the long-term of the project.</p><h4>Q: <strong>When will the Nano X app will be integrated into the QRL web wallet?</strong></h4><p><strong>JP Lomas</strong>: Now! Nano X and Web Wallet works fine if you have a WebUSB browser.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=b869e9239c79" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ama-ask-me-anything-summary-b869e9239c79">AMA (Ask Me Anything) Summary</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL June 25 — July 1]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-june-25-july-1-6bed4d1ba772?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/6bed4d1ba772</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-x]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 22:19:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-07-01T22:19:18.822Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL June 25 — July 1</h3><p><em>Development Updates, QRL on Ledger Nano X, QRL Community Q&amp;A</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*2SUCK3v7e-pjW-FirnveOQ.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>This past week, as many are in blockchain, a busy one. We had the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-blockchain-is-one-year-old-119c78664040">one year anniversary</a> of launching the QRL blockchain, QRL is now on <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/wallet/ledger-nano-s/">Ledger Nano X</a>, and we had our first QRL Community Q&amp;A. We will be announcing the recipient of July’s QRL Community Nomination Award in a blog later this week.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*S4oe0LrU6kHk_GulfFNXVQ.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>qrl-wallet:</strong> WebUSB/Nano X support in web wallet</li><li><strong>go-qrl:</strong> Added missing return for updateChainState</li><li><strong>mobile-wallet: </strong>Improvements based on mobile wallet v2</li></ul><h3>QRL on Ledger Nano X</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/956/1*lJ9JZ9y6hKIv6WnvL12rYQ.jpeg" /></figure><p>As you may have already seen on our <a href="https://twitter.com/QRLedger/status/1144613300573020162">Twitter</a>, QRL is now available on the Ledger Nano X. Previously, QRL was available on the Ledger Nano S, and we are happy to report that our compatibility has expanded. We always strive to ensure that our users have a functional and attractive suite of utility, and one of the key elements to that is a good option for a hardware wallet. Ledger continues to be the industry standard in the hardware wallet space, and we are happy to be able to offer that compatibility to our users. You can see our guide on using the Ledger Nano S or X <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/wallet/ledger-nano-s/">here</a>.</p><h3>QRL Community Q&amp;A</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*y0tjQyU2ZnhN1UaIp233zQ.jpeg" /></figure><p>Today, on the <a href="https://discord.gg/zbAJ9YV">QRL Discord server</a>, the first QRL Community Q&amp;A occurred. You can go check it out in the #qrl channel of the server yourself (for reference: it started today, July 1st, at 1800 UTC). We will also be cleaning up the questions, answers, follow-ups and responses, and putting them in an easy-to-access place. This should be available in a few days.</p><p>The Q&amp;A consisted of questions from the community, both sent in previously, as well as asked in the moment. Members from the team answered questions, as well as responded to comments as they occurred, while offering their opinions on a variety of matters. Moving forward, we will try to hold similar Q&amp;As, with some probably being more generalized, like today, with others potentially being more focused on a specific topic or cluster of topics.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=6bed4d1ba772" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-june-25-july-1-6bed4d1ba772">Last Week in QRL June 25 — July 1</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The QRL Contributors]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-contributors-ed7abd73ab1?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/ed7abd73ab1</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl-contributors]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 15:38:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-06-28T17:02:14.884Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Contribution is the backbone of any opensource project like The QRL, and is emergent from the community that surrounds it.</p><p>In this way it’s important to keep things not only accessible and open, but simple, enticing, guided, cohesive, and malleable to the changing needs of both the project and how it fits into the wider cryptocurrency space.</p><p>With this in mind, we’d like to announce <strong>The QRL Contributors</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/956/1*hCwi5dq-C-nJc2TlccDwZQ.png" /></figure><p>This is a project that aims to open up discussions and bring in both the core and community contributors alike, and is part of our path for decentralising The QRL <em>community</em> network.</p><p>Practically speaking, this will allow people (QRL contributors) to work in the QRL project by collaborating on different aspects of the ecosystem from coding to design and outreach in an organised collaborative fashion. For those who aren’t contributors, the more open transparency will make it easier to follow along.</p><p>Right now, it’s open to the core contributors as well as a select group of community contributors as we squash some bugs that may arise, but we’re excited about opening this up to the wider community in the future.</p><h4>Sections</h4><ul><li><a href="#5cd4">Objectives</a> (Primary Goals, Secondary Goals)</li><li><a href="#9751">Overview</a> (technical, in practice)</li></ul><h3><strong>Objectives</strong></h3><h4><strong>Primary goals</strong></h4><ol><li><strong>Accessible</strong>: Where possible, the team and contributors should be reachable and act as ambassadors.</li><li><strong>Open</strong>: Discussions and the general development of materials should be a public process that’s transparent.</li></ol><h4><strong>Secondary goals</strong></h4><ol><li><strong>Enticing</strong>: Creating an incentive scheme that is appealing, sustainable, and produces results.</li><li><strong>Guided</strong>: Structure is important to establishing a common vision within which to work. Additionally so is outlining proper scope and tracking long-term tasks for coordinating people from each working group.</li><li><strong>Cohesive</strong>: Everybody has their own skillset(s) to contribute, and should be encouraged and endorsed for self-electing the way in which they’d like to participate. However, each working group should be formed with the innate ability and desirability to work cohesively with every other working group. This may be an important enough goal to have a group all on its own, as it presents special usability and tooling challenges.</li><li><strong>Malleable</strong>: It’s important to remain flexible so that significant overhead is not incurred to make necessary changes.</li><li><strong>Resilient</strong>: Permissions and tasks should be set up and documented in such a way that any working group or person can walk away from the project with no warning and not meaningfully negatively impact efforts.</li></ol><h3>Overview</h3><h4>On a technical level</h4><p>The requirements for The QRL Contributors is a system that has <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Role-based_access_control">Role Based Access Control (RBAC)</a>, specifically with the ability to have read-only environments for all visitors. Additional functionality, though not a strict requirement, is the ability to communicate and flag certain roles through mentioning them.</p><p>Right now, much of the community (and the core contributors) is in Discord, which also fills these roles, so we are hosting the QRL Contributors on Discord initially. It should be noted however, that these requirements are system agnostic so it’s possible to change platforms, should the need or desire arise.</p><h4>In practice</h4><p>The structure is kept as simple and potent as possible to keep onboarding a relatively light endeavor.</p><p><strong>Visitors</strong> are able to view discussions, but not add to them. Through viewing the discussions at play, as well as any outstanding tasks that need to be done, a visitor might want to apply to take on a bigger role <em>as a contributor</em>.</p><p>Once accepted as a <strong>Contributor</strong>,<strong> </strong>they can self-assign<strong> </strong>one or more <strong>roles</strong>. These roles can be seen as specialisations that a person has. Some examples would be ‘developer’, ‘designer’, ‘writer’, and ‘marketer’. Roles are something that’s taggable, as in practice, another contributor might need some insight or help from members of the team that have a specific specialisation.</p><p>Along with roles, also self-assigned are <strong>Working Groups (WG)</strong>’s, which can be seen as committees that come together to achieve specific ongoing goals. Often a working group is similar to the role or specialisation (ie. ‘wg-marketing’), but not always (ie. ‘wg-documentation’, ‘wg-website’).</p><p>For things that are temporary in nature, but are large enough to warrant a committee of their own, there’s also <strong>Projects</strong> which are elected and can be self-assigned. Some examples of projects might be for videos and the organisation of events.</p><p>While the core contributors and a select group of community contributors utilise this system, it’s possible some of the above structure will change before the public release. What is described is how it is now, as of this writing.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=ed7abd73ab1" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-contributors-ed7abd73ab1">The QRL Contributors</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>