<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Cryptography with longevity. A post-quantum secure blockchain featuring a stateful signature scheme and unparalleled security. - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 19:49:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/the-quantum-resistant-ledger" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL March 12–18 2019]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-march-12-18-2019-4e5c48d32651?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/4e5c48d32651</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[crypto]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 19:55:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-03-18T19:55:58.765Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>What went on at QRL the past week</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*MgU5w0qWpXVVKjOi5GvKJQ.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Here in North America, Daylight Savings Time has come and gone once more, signalling for many the near-arrival of spring. However, in much of the rest of the world, DST does not arrive for another few weeks. In the meantime, we are double-checking our schedules whenever we have to meet to ensure we do not miss one another. As always, there was much activity behind the scenes. Below is a bit of what we can talk about right now.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/640/1*VomS0Va6MmuqPFU2u_fuTA.png" /></figure><ul><li><strong>Go QRL:</strong> Now receives unconfirmed transactions</li><li><strong>Vote_Tx: </strong>Planning for this transaction type discussed</li><li><strong>Block Explorer: </strong>Additional desirable features discussed (e.g. token type-ahead in search) — input welcomed from wider QRL community</li></ul><h3>Website Update</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/433/1*-nnNOdcZSDDLz_xx5_03EA.png" /><figcaption>What the new site might look like on mobile</figcaption></figure><p>In the coming weeks, you will notice some changes to the website. At QRL, we believe in regularly checking in with and updating our website. With new sections, some new content, and a new emphasis on QIPs, we hope that the website update will be an improvement. As always, we have and will continue to utilize user and community feedback. The best way to effect change is to make your opinion known to us, preferably through opening a <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/QRL/issues">GitHub issue</a>, where they can be tracked and followed up on more easily.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=4e5c48d32651" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-march-12-18-2019-4e5c48d32651">Last Week in QRL March 12–18 2019</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL March 5–11]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-march-5-11-c7a094f2eca5?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/c7a094f2eca5</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-x]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-s]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 21:42:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-03-12T18:52:24.340Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Some of the highlights from QRL the past week</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*RDck70DrnwYTl5zR1zLM9Q.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Last week was a big one for QRL; our Ledger application fully launched! The day that many on the team (and even more in the community) had been waiting for finally arrived, and went very smoothly. Aside from that, there’s been the normal focus on development, outreach, etc.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Az6ChygHN7sHr5B2phxANg.png" /></figure><ul><li><strong>Wallet:</strong> v1.1.1 of wallet released with full cross platform support</li><li><strong>Python Node:</strong> Separate address state for multisig created</li><li><strong>Go-QRL:</strong> Unit test for multisig_create complete</li><li><strong>Mobile: </strong>Sending Tx with insufficient funds exception now correctly caught</li></ul><h3>Ledger App Launch</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/600/1*ovAgpb6Kzi0HIWAXXaeFcA.jpeg" /></figure><p>As we <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-app-launched-3a8323d2de8f">happily reported last week</a>, the QRL Ledger App has launched! We have <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-nano-s-or-x-simple-instructions-49d864c570a5">step-by-step instructions</a>, as well as a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NL_u9biLy1g">how-to video</a> for anyone that is interested. So far we are happy to report that there have been no complaints regarding the application.</p><p>As always, if you have any questions or concerns regarding the QRL Ledger App, you can email <a href="mailto:support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a>, ask a question on our Discord, or message us on Twitter <a href="https://www.twitter.com/QRLedger">@QRLedger</a>.</p><h3>Automatic Migration</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*QJkYxWkZvQ1r7EwZ1Nqiog.jpeg" /></figure><p>Token migration has been quite a journey for the QRL community. From our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-token-migration-begins-b0d5b53f697f">blog announcing its start in April of 2018</a>, to the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/bittrex-exchange-migration-proper-liquidity-secured-for-the-qrl-df41045497e3">Bittrex Exchange Migration in late 2018</a>, to our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-app-update-eb89bcc5e657">more recent update</a>, and of course the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-app-launched-3a8323d2de8f">Ledger App launch </a>last week, Ledger support has been something on the minds of many in our community as a necessary element before they would feel comfortable migrating. Now that it is here, <strong>automatic migration will close on June 15th, 2019.</strong></p><p>As we have stated previously (and will continue to state moving forward), the end of automatic migration is not the end migration entirely. However, it <em>is </em>the end of our current process, and the start of a new one. Again, the process articulated below will only start after <strong>automatic migration closes on June 15th, 2019.</strong></p><p><strong>The QRL Foundation strongly encourages any and all users who still have QRL ERC20s to migrate them BEFORE the closure of automatic migration on June 15th, 2019.</strong></p><p>As is, the current process is <strong>automatic, anonymous</strong>, and <strong>almost immediate.</strong></p><p>After <strong>June 15th, 2019</strong>, the process for migrating ERC20s will be <strong>manual, semi-anonymous, </strong>and may take an<strong> indeterminate amount of time. </strong>Additionally,<strong> </strong>The QRL Foundation reserves the right to evaluate each manual migration on a <strong>case-by-case basis.</strong></p><p>The new process will look like:</p><ul><li>A QRL User will email <a href="http://support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a> with a QRL mainnet address the user created (QRL addresses that start with a Q)</li><li>The QRL Foundation (via <a href="http://support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a>) will respond to the User with an ETH ERC20 burn address</li><li>User will send QRL ERC20s to the ETH burn address sent via email</li><li>QRL address provided by User will be sent Quanta at a 1:1 ratio to ERC20s burnt</li><li>User will now have 1 Quanta in their QRL address for every 1 ERC20 they sent to their burn address</li></ul><p>As always, if you have any questions, comments or concerns about this process, or any other process, please do not hesitate to reach on Discord, Twitter, or send an email to <a href="http://support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a></p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=c7a094f2eca5" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-march-5-11-c7a094f2eca5">Last Week in QRL March 5–11</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ledger App Launched!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-app-launched-3a8323d2de8f?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/3a8323d2de8f</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-x]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-s]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 21:29:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-03-05T21:29:41.638Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR — The QRL Ledger app has been fully approved and launched. You can download, install, and run the application on Ledger Nano S or X today!</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*PqEllAcBIH74HXMBt_1dVQ.jpeg" /></figure><h3>How Do I Use It?</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/805/1*aBt1eqQKWOoHj0ykDC-C_A.jpeg" /></figure><p>As excited as we are to have the application finally launched, we are even more excited for people to actually download, install, and use it on their Ledger devices. The easiest way to do that is to go to <a href="https://www.ledger.com/pages/ledger-live">Ledger Live</a>, download it, and then select QRL’s application from the available options. If you would like a more detailed explanation, we have a separate, dedicated <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-nano-s-or-x-simple-instructions-49d864c570a5">How To blog</a>.</p><h3>A Developmental Triumph</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*xHVUe2hQ5ZhY6xJo3vaOrw.jpeg" /></figure><p>Given the uniqueness of our signature scheme (XMSS), we at QRL could not imitate or attempt to replicate any other project’s Ledger application. As has often been the case, our developers had to design a specific solution that fit the unique needs of our blockchain. While I am not the right person to pen an in-depth explanation of what went into that (though someone else may well do that in a later blog), I would be remiss to neglect to mention their tireless efforts.</p><h3>Auto Migration Post-Ledger Integration</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/429/1*rbHJPM08b8gP0PSYSOVJ0Q.png" /></figure><p>As we have indicated previously, we have been holding off on announcing an exact date for the closing of the auto-migration portal, waiting on Ledger integration. As a reminder, even after the auto-migration portal is closed, users will still be able to migrate their un-burnt ERC20s to main network Quanta. The process will simply no longer be automatic. Details on when exactly the auto-migration portal will be closed, and what the new system will look like, will be in an upcoming blog. The date announcement will also be echoed throughout our social media channels, with regularly scheduled reminders leading up to the day the portal closes.</p><h3>What This Means For QRL</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/200/1*XZt6vF_VdysWmnja_kE0qQ.png" /></figure><p>As we have discussed in previous blogs, Ledger integration has been an important milestone for the project — Ledger is the most used hardware wallet in the space, as well as the leader in hardware wallet technology. It is an important milestone for the community — one of the most dedicated and vocal segments of our user base are Ledger users. We have long heard their calls, and are very happy we can now provide them with the solution to storing Quanta on their Ledger Nano S or X.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=3a8323d2de8f" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-app-launched-3a8323d2de8f">Ledger App Launched!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ledger Nano S or X: Simple Instructions]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-nano-s-or-x-simple-instructions-49d864c570a5?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/49d864c570a5</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-x]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger-nano-s]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 21:28:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-03-05T21:32:10.877Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Ledger Nano: Installation Instructions</h3><p>There’s a full instructional video coming, and extensive full text-instructions with pictures already on our <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/wallet/ledger-nano-s/">documentation site</a>, but for those that want the TL;DR of installing QRL on your ledger device, this is for you.</p><p>If you already have setup Ledger Live before and are all updated, you will want to skip straight to <a href="#8897">step 3</a>.</p><h3>Setup and installation</h3><h4>1. Install Ledger Live</h4><p>The easiest way to install QRL on your ledger device is through <a href="https://www.ledger.com/pages/ledger-live">Ledger Live</a>. If you already have Ledger Live, ensure you install the latest firmware update.</p><h4>2. Setup your Ledger device</h4><p>If you’ve already done so, you can skip to step 3, otherwise follow the instructions on the <a href="https://support.ledger.com/hc/en-us/articles/360006395233-Take-your-first-steps">Ledger documentation website: first-steps</a></p><h4>3. Connect and unlock your Ledger device</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1004/1*W0hwfGE48qRyj3HhOhzZqg.jpeg" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1002/1*iqEVtF3xss5rYjdr1LX4hw.jpeg" /></figure><h4>4. Go to Manager and search for QRL</h4><p>After you have connected your device, search for QRL in the manager and click install. Follow any prompts.</p><p><em>Note: Ledger Live just enables easy installation of the QRL app on your ledger device, you will not be able to add or manage your QRL account from there.</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1006/1*sjp6Kuu4pwc_O2QOiC8Igg.jpeg" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*5utJw10OXSHcyUbgaGRz2w.jpeg" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1003/1*NVGxWmIGu26-0dSML6pFHA.jpeg" /></figure><h4>5. Initialising the QRL App</h4><p>Open the QRL app on your ledger device and scroll down to where it says <strong>Init Device</strong> and press <em>both buttons</em>. This will generate 256 keys (note: be patient, this takes about half an hour). After you are done, your device will be say <strong>QRL READY rem:256. </strong><a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/wallet/ledger-nano-s/#initialising-the-qrl-app">More details</a></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*1Ebyx6JDkUMEBEwHsuA7OQ.jpeg" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*uaDbR9jU7mK885ExJRVHbw.jpeg" /></figure><h3>Using your device</h3><h4>1. Make sure your device is unlocked (you don’t need Ledger Live for this) and the QRL app is open to “QRL READY”</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*uaDbR9jU7mK885ExJRVHbw.jpeg" /></figure><h4>2. Open the webwallet in explorer and Goto open wallet</h4><p>Direct link <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org/open">here</a>.</p><h4>3. Select from the dropdown “Ledger Nano S” or “Ledger Nano X” and click “Open Ledger Nano S” or “Open Ledger Nano X”</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*AP8Q-OWvVR1fBan6NEXnEw.jpeg" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*FAzPqyA1XH9qeKn-04Bblw.jpeg" /></figure><h4>4. Done</h4><p>Congratulations, you have successfully installed the QRL app and connected it to the wallet for secure transfers!</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*y_hv2WnQeh9TKADA1QKT7A.jpeg" /></figure><p>For a usage demonstration when it’s connected, Scott Donald has created a video which can be seen below</p><iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FNL_u9biLy1g%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DNL_u9biLy1g&amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FNL_u9biLy1g%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;key=d04bfffea46d4aeda930ec88cc64b87c&amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;schema=youtube" width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><a href="https://medium.com/media/43eaedbd6040b4e280addd9df5a4279e/href">https://medium.com/media/43eaedbd6040b4e280addd9df5a4279e/href</a></iframe><h3>Extra</h3><p>As a reminder, this is just a brief overview, if you want more information you can always head over to our extensive documentation page on the <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/wallet/ledger-nano-s/">Ledger Nano</a> or ask any questions you may have on <a href="https://reddit.com/r/QRL">Reddit</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/QRLedger">Twitter</a>, <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">Discord</a>, or email <a href="mailto:support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a>.</p><p>For those that are a bit more patient, we also have a video in the works covering this process.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=49d864c570a5" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/ledger-nano-s-or-x-simple-instructions-49d864c570a5">Ledger Nano S or X: Simple Instructions</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL Feb 26 — Mar 4]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-feb-26-jan-4-7d1a7ff00bfc?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/7d1a7ff00bfc</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 21:49:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-03-11T17:45:39.264Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL Feb 26 — Mar 4</h3><p><em>What has happened at QRL over the past week</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*VTtnRj7hMAlcbN5os0YBeQ.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Another week in the books at QRL! We have been looking at/editing the footage from DeveloperWeek, as well as scheduling (and rescheduling) some potential upcoming appearances/interviews on podcasts/web shows. The best of the rest is below.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*LrlifOiMRjhMoJzVQcUZMQ.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>Go-QRL: </strong>Added missing code to remove unconfirmed txn from collection</li><li><strong>Offline Wallet:</strong> Checksum and PGP signing complete</li><li><strong>Ledger: </strong>Ledger asked for a small UX change in BOLOS app which has been implemented</li><li><strong>Mobile: </strong>Crash on Android under investigation</li></ul><h3>Website Refresh</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*WcQRBqA9rWucyCwRvLXgkw.png" /></figure><p>As many of you have probably already noticed, we have pushed some light updates to the <a href="https://theqrl.org/">QRL website</a>. These include new categories for the content on the website, as well as changing what was our Roadmap page to the <a href="https://theqrl.org/protocol-updates/">Protocol Updates</a> page. There are also new pages for QIP review, such as the <a href="https://theqrl.org/qip/Multi-Signature-Wallet/">Multi-Signature Wallet</a> page. You can now review any QIP directly on the website (though comments are still done on GitHub).</p><h3>Community</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*188skQSflu5UIWG54FHUHQ.png" /></figure><p>We are happy to announce that Discord user PQAdvantage is February’s QRL Community Nomination Winner! We asked PQAdvantage to tell us a bit about how they came to QRL:</p><blockquote>In 2017, I had discussions with several cybersecurity industry leaders who raised serious concerns about the imminent threat of quantum computing technology to cryptocurrencies and cryptography in general. While I was well acquainted with all things quantum and crypto, the alarm bells had not gone off in my head until those discussions. I spent several months researching the best projects and concluded that QRL surpassed the field by a considerable margin (hat tip to Doney and other great minds in the QRL community for helping me expedite that process).</blockquote><blockquote>Indeed, QRL is exactly what I was looking for as a hedge against the inherent quantum vulnerabilities of the rest of my crypto portfolio. I am astounded by how much the QRL team has achieved to date and excited to see where they go in the future. I believe they are nicely positioned to become quite literally the most secure and reliable post-quantum blockchain platform in the world. I’m also floored by the depth and breadth of the QRL community and learn something new from them every day. In closing, if ECDSA isn’t cracked by the end of 2020, I’ll eat my own qubit</blockquote><p>As a reminder, if there is a member of the QRL community that you would like to put up for the QRL Community Nomination, please nominate them in Discord in the channel #butler.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=7d1a7ff00bfc" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-feb-26-jan-4-7d1a7ff00bfc">Last Week in QRL Feb 26 — Mar 4</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL Feb 19–25, 2019]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-feb-18-25-2019-647f2ab91a14?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/647f2ab91a14</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[developerweek]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-computing]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 22:34:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-02-26T17:04:55.696Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>What happened at QRL the past week</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*2eNwEKRe-3XWv7ZNEm7tgw.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Adam and James just got back from DeveloperWeek 2019 at the end of last week. This blog will be less brief than we thought it might be, as there is the pleasant surprise of QIP 5 to introduce to everyone. At QRL, we are continuing to perfect existing systems and features, as well as continuing to develop new ones. Below is some of what has been going on the past week.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*CiW9ZgDwdARVD_76LwNENw.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>Python Node: </strong>Node with pagination running in devnet</li><li><strong>Python Node: </strong>Address state updated to support multisig</li><li><strong>GoQRL/MongoDB/Explorer: </strong>Explorer being largely refactored (practically rewritten) to take advantage of the rapid speed and reduce node overhead</li><li><strong>Node development: </strong>Go to become primary node implementation in the long term</li></ul><h3>DeveloperWeek 2019</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/600/1*XN3dz5ajWVr1xNjmFX8tUA.png" /></figure><p>I will be brief here since we also have our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-developerweek-2019-b539dc30a146">Reflecting on DeveloperWeek blog</a>. DeveloperWeek 2019 was a success; it was an eminently professional setup, the presentation went well, and it was a massive event that seemed to work like a well-oiled machine.</p><p>After spending so much time in our own particular niche of the wider technical world, it was both refreshing and inspiring to see how much progress is being made in other areas of technology like Artificial Intelligence, and Virtual Reality.</p><h3>QIP 5: Extending Message transaction Functionality</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/639/1*TJxmqR3MCHUak_0ezgjz3w.jpeg" /></figure><p>Another week, another <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips">QRL Improvement Protocol (QIP)</a>. The newest QIP on the block(chain) is <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/blob/master/2.Proposals/1.%20Open/5%20extended%20message%20format.md">QIP 5: Extending Message tx Functionality</a>. As always, we highly encourage everyone to go read the QIPs in full for themselves. Here is the abstract:</p><blockquote>Message transactions sent on the QRL blockchain network allow broadcast and decentralised storage of 80 bytes of data per transaction for purposes such as notarisation and data stamping. This minor QIP extends the message transaction format to include an optional payee/receipt address.</blockquote><p>We are very excited at the potential of the QIP system, and are very heartened by the QIPs we have seen so far. Whether a given QIP is ultimately integrated or not, we believe that the discussions they inspire are helpful for the growth of the QRL network. Without properly discussing both the necessary next steps, as well as the paths not taken, we cannot be sure that QRL will continue to be the best decentralized blockchain network that it can be. As always, we <em>highly </em>encourage anyone with interest to submit a QIP. It remains one of the most direct ways to contribute to the overall QRL ecosystem, as well as a way to make your desires regarding the continued development of QRL known.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=647f2ab91a14" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-feb-18-25-2019-647f2ab91a14">Last Week in QRL Feb 19–25, 2019</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reflecting on DeveloperWeek 2019]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-developerweek-2019-b539dc30a146?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/b539dc30a146</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[devweek]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[developerweek]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-computing]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 19:32:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-02-25T19:32:43.188Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR — Spoke at and attended DeveloperWeek 2019 in Oakland with James</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*uqyvUN3A2YYFeX5N8FlPLg.jpeg" /></figure><h3>Setting the Scene</h3><p>This past week, James and I attended <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/">DeveloperWeek 2019</a> in Oakland, California. It was held at the <a href="http://www.oaklandconventioncenter.com/">Oakland Convention Center</a>, located near downtown Oakland. DeveloperWeek is a massive conference, expo, hackathon, and hiring expo that spans 5 days and attracts over 8,000 attendees. To say that it was massive is an understatement.</p><p>In my time at QRL I have only been to one conference that matched the intensity and scale of DeveloperWeek — Consensus 2018. However, while Consensus was massive, it was still an undertaking that was focused on blockchain and cryptocurrency. DeveloperWeek is relatively more broad. In no particular order, DeveloperWeek 2019 had tracks focused on <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/conference/conference-schedule/">VR/AR</a>, <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/conference/popular-programming-languages-frameworks/">popular coding languages</a>, <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/conference/next-generation-languages/">next generation coding languages</a>, <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/conference/the-future-of-developer-tools/">future of development tools</a>, <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/conference/new-database-technologies/">new database technologies</a>, <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/conference/blockchain-development/.">blockchain</a>, <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/conference/artificial-intelligence-dev-conference/">AI</a>, <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/conference/apis-microservices-track/">APIs</a>, and <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/conference/javascript-conference/">JavaScript</a>, among others. As compared to the niche of blockchain/cryptocurrency, DeveloperWeek covers quite a wide scope of topics.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/600/1*XN3dz5ajWVr1xNjmFX8tUA.png" /></figure><h3>A New Standard</h3><p>DeveloperWeek was not only one of the largest conferences I have had the opportunity to attend in my role at QRL — it was easily the most professional and pleasant set up I have interacted with as a speaker. Once on stage, it is all up to the presenter, but there is much that can help put someone in a position to succeed before they step on stage. Things like regular communication in the weeks/months before the event, clearly marking all locations at the event, having dedicated A/V managers for each stage, standardized presentation format to reduce visual irregularities, presentation rooms with good/neutral acoustics, and last (but certainly not least) — keeping everything on schedule so that people know where they need to be, when they need to be. I am happy to report that in all of these areas DeveloperWeek excelled.</p><p>In the 10 or so presentations I have given on behalf of QRL, I have seen a wide variety of setup and execution. DeveloperWeek is now the conference that I can hold up as the gold standard of front and back-end logistics. Given that it was also the longest presentation I have given, for one of the larger audiences, it made the experience that much more pleasant that it was handled so professionally.</p><h3>The Presentation</h3><p>My presentation at DeveloperWeek 2019 was titled, “Quantum Computing and the Blockchain/Cryptocurrency Community.” I was given 50 minutes to present (35–45 minute presentation + 5–15 minute Q&amp;A), which was more than we are usually given (most conferences we have 20–30 minutes total). While anyone would appreciate extra time to explain things, given what a complex topic quantum computing is, especially at DeveloperWeek, the extra time was valued. That is because I had the opportunity to present to what was probably the most technically literate audience I’ve had access to. This was not only evidenced in the rapt attention and looks of comprehension I saw on the faces on various audience members, but in the quality of questions I received, both during the Q&amp;A section, as well as after my talk had concluded.</p><p>One such question that I want to highlight here came from a gentlemen who inquired about the open-source nature of QRL (that is to say, whether or not we were open-source). He wanted to make sure that if we were developing solutions, that people would be able to access them, and potentially learn from them. As a reminder, QRL is and will continue to be under the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MIT_License">MIT Open Source License</a>. Blockchain would not be here today if it was not for the open source development community, and QRL remains steadfast in its commitment to giving back to that community, as well as helping to propagate it through the use of the MIT License and thorough documentation.</p><p>In addition, James was able to capture a video of my presentation that we plan on editing (potentially into smaller, bite-sized videos), and putting up on our YouTube page (which will be linked to Medium and elsewhere). Stay tuned!</p><h3>Final Thoughts</h3><p>In terms of conferences, 2019 has certainly started off on a high note. While our 2019 schedule is still taking shape, it is unlikely, for a number of reasons, that we will match the sheer intensity of the conference schedule we had in 2018. We want to make fewer appearances and have a greater impact.</p><p>While we did not end up having a formal supporter meetup due to logistic issues, informally I ran into some people who either were aware of, or had directly used the QRL network. I do not think I will ever tire of those experiences.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=b539dc30a146" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-developerweek-2019-b539dc30a146">Reflecting on DeveloperWeek 2019</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL Feb 11–18 2019]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-feb-11-18-2019-f21e59181742?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/f21e59181742</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[developerweek]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[mobile-wallets]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 21:35:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-02-18T23:26:41.099Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*MoR-8LV6oKiH7fp15_fgpA.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Last week was Valentine’s Day in the Western World, and tomorrow Adam and James head out to Oakland for DeveloperWeek 2019. Next week’s “Last Week in QRL” blog will likely be brief, as there will be a typical “Reflections” blog on DeveloperWeek out as well. We are starting off our conference attendance with a bang in 2019, as DeveloperWeek’s attendance will likely eclipse even that of Consensus last year, as well as covering a broader scope.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*HwoygmrZ0lqp9nBbUmjyLg.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>Offline Wallet Generator: </strong>fix: long-style v-on and v-bind</li><li><strong>Mobile Wallet:</strong> v1.0.8 update</li><li><strong>Mobile Wallet:</strong> Wallet creation test using Appium</li><li><strong>Mobile Wallet:</strong> Simple end-to-end test using Detox</li><li><strong>API:</strong> Adding Explorer API Documentation</li></ul><h3>QIP 4: Multi-Signature Wallet</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Z_ZjOpYV4iiy7ik3JM0Lvw.jpeg" /></figure><p>For those of you unfamiliar, our <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips">QRL Improvement Protocol (QIP)</a> is the vehicle through which we hope to drive much of the serious discussion around specific feature development. To review, some of the first QIPs were regarding <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/tree/master/2.Proposals/1.%20Open/1%20Cryptonote%20v8">Cryptonight V8</a> and <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/tree/master/2.Proposals/1.%20Open/2%20-%20MessageTransaction%20Encoded%20Message%20Standard">A standard message encoding format to indicate encoded data</a>. They live over on our <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips">GitHub</a> and we encourage members of the community to comment, create and discuss them there.</p><p>The most recent QIP is <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/blob/master/2.Proposals/1.%20Open/4%20Multi-signature%20wallet.md">QIP4: Multi-Signature Wallets</a> — if you feel inclined to read it yourself, we highly encourage it! As the QIP states, multi-signature wallets, “allow multiple authorities to have a transaction from a single wallet once consent has been established.”</p><p>Generally speaking, multi-signature wallets allow for more complex uses of a wallet. One such example would be a team within a company, with 5 people, where 3 of the 5 needed to approve any expenditure for a given project. With a multi-signature wallet, they could ensure that in order for funds to be spent, 3 of the 5 signatures associated with the wallet would need to be employed.</p><h3>Upcoming Conference</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/600/1*XN3dz5ajWVr1xNjmFX8tUA.png" /></figure><p>Adam and James will be heading out to Oakland tomorrow to present at and attend DeveloperWeek 2019. You can see a preview of what Adam will be presenting <a href="https://developerweek2019.sched.com/speaker/adam_koltun.1yz9ak9c">here</a>. You can find all the details about DeveloperWeek 2019 and our involvement in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/developerweek-2019-this-week-8992e1c38434">our preview blog</a>. As always, we will have a reflections blog following the conference. Be on the lookout for the blog the week following their return from DeveloperWeek.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=f21e59181742" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-feb-11-18-2019-f21e59181742">Last Week in QRL Feb 11–18 2019</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DeveloperWeek 2019 this week!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/developerweek-2019-this-week-8992e1c38434?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/8992e1c38434</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[conference]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[developerweek]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 16:56:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-02-18T16:56:01.761Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/600/1*XN3dz5ajWVr1xNjmFX8tUA.png" /></figure><p><em>TL;DR — The Who/What/Where/When/Why of DeveloperWeek 2019</em></p><h3>Who</h3><p>Developer Week 2019 will be attended by:</p><ul><li>Adam</li><li>James</li></ul><h3>What</h3><p>DeveloperWeek 2019 is San Francisco’s largest developer conference &amp; event series with dozens of week-long events including the DeveloperWeek 2019 Conference &amp; Expo.</p><p>Each year, 8,000+ developers, engineers, software architects, dev teams, managers and executives from 70+ countries gather in the SF Bay Area — the world’s epicenter of developer innovation — to discover the latest in developer technologies, languages, platforms, and tools.</p><p>DeveloperWeek covers technologies like VR Dev, Artificial Intelligence Dev, Blockchain Dev, IoT Dev, Serverless technology, Microservices technology, new JavaScript frameworks, and more.</p><p>2019 Theme: <strong>The DevTech Age</strong></p><p>When it comes to technology, there’s incremental change, and then there’s fundamental innovation. Developer technology, from blockchain and artificial intelligence to big data and quantum computing represents fundamental innovation that people can build on for years. We are in the DevTech Age, where developer technologies and tools are now the most disruptive and fundamental technology innovation in the marketplace.</p><h3>Where</h3><p><a href="http://www.oaklandconventioncenter.com/">Oakland Convention Center</a>, Oakland, California</p><h3>When</h3><p>February 20–24th, 2019</p><h3>Why</h3><p>When we were approached with the opportunity to present at DeveloperWeek 2019, we immediately realized that this was an opportunity worth taking. DeveloperWeek is one of (if not the) premiere development-centric events in the United States each year, and 2019 is no exception. While we have spoken to audiences that skewed more technical before, we have not had a chance to speak to a crowd like the one we will probably have at DeveloperWeek.</p><p>It’s location in Oakland obviously situates it in the middle of Silicon Valley, the area with the densest location of tech companies, innovation, and development in America. Additionally, we have been granted a longer-than-average speaking slot, as compared to other conferences we have attended (usually presentations are 20–30 minutes, we have 50 at DeveloperWeek).</p><p>Finally, due to a host of factors across the industry and within our own project, we are going to be more selective about which conferences/events we attend in 2019. We have certainly set the bar high with DeveloperWeek as our first outing of the year.</p><h3>Supporter Meetup</h3><p>Due to the tightness of our schedules and the scale of the response we received, we will not be having an official supporter meetup while we are in Oakland. However, if you are going to be at the actual conference, feel free to message us on Twitter or Discord and we may be able to meet up and say Hi, time allowing.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=8992e1c38434" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/developerweek-2019-this-week-8992e1c38434">DeveloperWeek 2019 this week!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL Feb 5–Feb 11]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-feb-5-feb-11-4ffe424d4e7a?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/4ffe424d4e7a</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl-wallet]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 19:02:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-02-11T19:18:53.698Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*NVLCuh6b5zRlDMBsO-O2-Q.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>This is the final week of preparation before <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/">Developer Week 2019</a> next week. We will have a “Last Week in QRL” blog like normal on the 18th, then Adam and James will be heading out to Oakland the following morning. Both the seasonal and crypto winter have continued to slog on, but unlike the bear (both literal and figurative), we are not content to hibernate our way through. Progress continues, and below are some of the highlights that we can talk about.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*v7jfETYh3a3L0BU5KXSPsQ.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>Block Explorer:</strong> Fix search box on mobile</li><li><strong>Ledger:</strong> Fix nodejs comm names</li><li><strong>Wallet:</strong> Many changes, see QRL Wallet section below</li></ul><h3>QRL Wallet</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*l1AhaetbiZWOHuuk8Fg1iA.png" /></figure><p>The QRL Wallet has had a huge week of changes, so much so that we figured we should break it out into its own</p><ul><li>Supports Ledger Nano S in Web and Desktop apps across Mac, Windows and Linux (Ubuntu tested).</li><li>Desktop app now has installers (DEB for Linux, DMG for Mac, MSI for Windows)</li><li>Improved build process for Electron Desktop app</li><li>Improved desktop app closure process (resolve hanging node.js process)</li><li>Update Meteor 1.8.0.1 to 1.8.0.2</li></ul><h3>Upcoming Conference</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/600/1*XN3dz5ajWVr1xNjmFX8tUA.png" /></figure><p>Only 9 days until <a href="https://developerweek2019.sched.com/speaker/adam_koltun.1yz9ak9c">Adam speaks at DeveloperWeek 2019</a> — if you are still interested in attending a meetup somewhere nearby in Oakland, please reach out via Discord DM, Twitter, or Reddit. So far we have seen some interest, but not yet enough to justify a meetup. We will announce the meetup (if there is one) in our official preview blog of the conference (coming later this week).</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=4ffe424d4e7a" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-feb-5-feb-11-4ffe424d4e7a">Last Week in QRL Feb 5–Feb 11</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>