<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Cryptography with longevity. A post-quantum secure blockchain featuring a stateful signature scheme and unparalleled security. - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 16:45:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/the-quantum-resistant-ledger" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Integration feature: New Mining Pool — NewPool Cool]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/integration-feature-new-mining-pool-newpool-cool-67914cf0ce6b?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/67914cf0ce6b</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency-mining]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 16:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2020-04-14T16:16:40.807Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Integration feature: New Mining Pool — NewPool Cool</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*rgNfIOeaxgTBByNvQntS-Q.png" /></figure><h3>Overview</h3><ul><li>URL: <a href="https://qrl.newpool.cool">https://qrl.newpool.cool</a></li><li>QRL Docs URL: <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/#newpool-cool">https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/#newpool-cool</a></li><li>Default Stratum: qrl.newpool.cool:4444</li><li>Pool Fee: 0.5%</li><li>Minimum payout: 1 QRL</li><li>Payment Interval: 30 minutes</li></ul><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=67914cf0ce6b" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/integration-feature-new-mining-pool-newpool-cool-67914cf0ce6b">Integration feature: New Mining Pool — NewPool Cool</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video: How to Mine QRL Quanta — EP006]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/video-how-to-mine-qrl-quanta-ep006-545c2f4b2a6d?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/545c2f4b2a6d</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cpu-mining]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[xmrig]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency-mining]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-computing]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 16:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2020-04-13T16:01:01.022Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Video: How to Mine QRL Quanta — EP006</h3><h4>A step-by-step guide on how to mine Quanta on a windows computer</h4><iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2F5e7FK7A7svU%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3D5e7FK7A7svU&amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2F5e7FK7A7svU%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;key=a19fcc184b9711e1b4764040d3dc5c07&amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;schema=youtube" width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><a href="https://medium.com/media/fbfdabf7424e07062c3c4a4af79f3918/href">https://medium.com/media/fbfdabf7424e07062c3c4a4af79f3918/href</a></iframe><h3>Video Transcription</h3><h4>Introduction</h4><p>Welcome to the official Quantum Resistant Ledger channel, your video portal into post quantum digital asset security.</p><p>The first week of April 2020 has been an exciting one. With QRL 2.0 comes multisignature transactions, support for an ephemeral messaging system, multiple improvements and enhancement across different code suites, and of course the RandomX PoW protocol. We covered what <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S0ETCcT3vGY">RandomX was in a previous video</a>, jump to that video if you have not seen it yet for a high level view. This video is going to be for Windows users that want to start mining Quanta right way. I’ll walk you through step by step and a list of pools can be found on our site at <a href="http://www.theqrl.org">www.theqrl.org</a>. Lengthy intros are annoying, so let’s get down to it.</p><h4>Steps covered in the Video</h4><ol><li><strong>Antivirus Software [</strong><a href="https://youtu.be/5e7FK7A7svU?t=65"><strong>1:05</strong></a><strong>]</strong></li><li><strong>Firefox Whitelisting and Exceptions[</strong><a href="https://youtu.be/5e7FK7A7svU?t=126"><strong>2:06</strong></a><strong>]</strong></li><li><strong>Create a new wallet [</strong><a href="https://youtu.be/5e7FK7A7svU?t=150"><strong>2:30</strong></a><strong>]<br></strong>Webwallet link: <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org/">https://wallet.theqrl.org/</a></li><li><strong>Download xmrig [</strong><a href="https://youtu.be/5e7FK7A7svU?t=187"><strong>3:07</strong></a><strong>]<br></strong>Download: <a href="https://github.com/xmrig/xmrig/releases/latest/">https://github.com/xmrig/xmrig/releases/latest/</a></li><li><strong>Extract xmrig [</strong><a href="https://youtu.be/5e7FK7A7svU?t=295"><strong>4:55</strong></a><strong>]</strong></li><li><strong>Edit xmrig config.json file [</strong><a href="https://youtu.be/5e7FK7A7svU?t=305"><strong>5:00</strong></a><strong>]<br></strong>Mining pools: <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/">https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/</a></li><li><strong>Run xmrig [</strong><a href="https://youtu.be/5e7FK7A7svU?t=393"><strong>6:33</strong></a><strong>]</strong></li><li><strong>Bullet points [</strong><a href="https://youtu.be/5e7FK7A7svU?t=551"><strong>9:10</strong></a><strong>]</strong></li></ol><h4>Bullet points</h4><p>OK, I hope those steps were helpful, here are a few important bullet points to remember.</p><ol><li>If you can, tune your RAM above 2133Mhz. Nearly all modern DDR RAM out there now is designed for a fast clock speed. There are some discussions in our Discord community and lots of videos on Youtube.</li><li>Clock speed is important, but not at the cost of stability. If you overclock your CPU or RAM and the system becomes unstable, any gains you would have received from a higher clock rates will be lost when you come back and find out your PC went on holiday or PTO and didn’t tell you first. This can be upsetting so remember to always run some sort of utility to stress test CPU and RAM if you take this route.</li><li>If you run XMRIG, make sure you run it as Administrator. This allows it to use huge pages and set CPU register values if needed. Which can increase your hashrate substantially. At the time of this video, the latest version is 5.10.</li><li>If you actually want to be able to USE your PC while you mine, edit the config.json file in XMRIG to disable one or two CPU cores or threads. Noooooootttt you wallet.json file! This way, your system can mine and stay usable, you might even be able to still watch Netflix while your PC mines Quanta in the background.</li><li>And of course, don’t forget to run a node. It’s super easy to get one up and running, supports the project, and doesn’t take up minimal CPU resources</li></ol><p>One last thing, if you have questions, ASK. You can reach me for mining questions on Discord as Strike Attack #8102 with questions. I do my best to answer all the mining questions that get asked or go unanswered.</p><p>Thanks for watching, happy mining!</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Ebwwj7G-vTx7rHGnFtGpOw.png" /></figure><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=545c2f4b2a6d" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/video-how-to-mine-qrl-quanta-ep006-545c2f4b2a6d">Video: How to Mine QRL Quanta — EP006</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The QRL Bromine Hardfork: A look inside]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-bromine-hardfork-a-look-inside-2eed61ea90fd?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/2eed61ea90fd</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[encryption]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[messaging]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[audit]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain-technology]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 20:38:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2020-04-07T20:38:48.235Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*A58S4XszIgYoxfCB3g1JRQ.png" /></figure><h4>Quantum secure weighted threshold multisignature addresses &amp; transactions, ephemeral messaging LatticeTX, and RandomX land in QRL mainnet.</h4><p>From the beginning, we have been passionate about driving the solutions to prepare for the next revolution in secure digital asset storage.</p><p>This was demonstrated in 2018 with the launch of the first usable quantum secure enterprise-grade blockchain backed by the stateful signature scheme XMSS, as opposed to ECDSA found in many blockchains. <a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc8391">XMSS</a> is now currently slated as a <a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.800-208-draft.pdf">draft recommendation</a> by the <a href="https://www.nist.gov/">National Institute of Science and Technology (NIST)</a>.</p><p>Our launch was further accompanied by a full suite of tools:</p><ul><li>Desktop wallets for <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/releases/latest">Linux, Mac, and Windows Web</a></li><li>A <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org">web wallet</a> with the full functionality of the desktop wallet.</li><li>Explorer, both on the <a href="https://explorer.theqrl.org">web</a> and bundled as part of the desktop wallet clients.</li><li>An API along with <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org">extensive documentation</a></li><li>Colored Token functionality through QRT’s</li><li>Two audits by <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/red4sec-security-audit-concludes-a-summary-563ecfe04c75">Red4Sec</a> and <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/audits/blob/master/X41-theQRL-Review-2018-Final-Report.pdf">x41 D-sec</a></li><li><a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/developers/address/">Flexible address format designed to be extensible and support a wide range of signature schemes and hash functions.</a></li></ul><p>Which we continued to improve upon our network by adding things like:</p><ul><li>An <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/offline-wallet-generator">offline wallet generator</a></li><li>Mobile wallets for <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/qrl-wallet/id1458620542">iOS</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.theqrl&amp;hl=en">Android</a></li><li>Hardware wallet support with the <a href="https://support.ledger.com/hc/en-us/articles/360019184453-Quantum-Resistant-Ledger-QRL-">Ledger Nano S/X</a></li><li>Multiple API’s documented at <a href="https://api.theqrl.org">api.theqrl.org</a></li><li>A <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/developers/qrl-cli/">qrl-cli</a> for easy command-line usage</li><li>Quantum resistant <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/tools/notarisation/">notarisation</a></li><li><a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/tools/keybase/">Keybase integration</a></li><li><a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/qrledger/qrl-docker">Docker QRL node support</a></li></ul><p>And with this hardfork, Bromine, we’re adding/improving:</p><ul><li><a href="#3065">Weighted threshold multisignature transactions</a></li><li><a href="#ff89">Ephemeral Messaging LatticeTX</a></li><li><a href="#2cb2">RandomX</a></li></ul><p>Still to look forward to are:</p><ul><li>Smart contracts</li><li>Proof-of-Stake</li><li>On-chain voting</li><li>Proposals that have passed through the <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips">QRL Improvement Proposals (QIP)</a> process</li></ul><p>For the <strong>QRL Bromine hardfork</strong>, a special thanks goes out The QRL Contributors group, as well as the 48 contributors with 7,888 commits over the years that helped in innumerable ways.</p><h3>Major changes</h3><h4>Weighted threshold multisignature addresses &amp; transactions</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1004/1*SsXFrl3CxVK5xmtKSObdAQ.png" /></figure><p>Critical to any trustless (and trusted) system is the ability to handle different methods of governance on how allocated funds can be spent.</p><p>For this to work, during the creation of a multisig address, one or more signatories (addresses) are assigned and a final threshold to spend is set. Any signatory can then create a <em>spend request</em> (which is a proposed transaction to be voted on) with a final expiration date in the form of a block-height. If enough people vote to approve the transaction and meet or exceed the set threshold <em>before</em> that block-height is reached, the transaction goes through.</p><p>Examples use-cases for this are numerous, including:</p><ul><li><strong>Petty joint account:</strong> Any signatory party can spend funds. Often used between two individuals with an established level of trust (couples).</li><li><strong>Two-factor Authentication address: </strong>As a way to add an extra level of security, it’s possible to setup a multisig address with two signatories, with the credentials spread between different devices and/or locations. In order to spend, a vote from both signatories would be required.</li><li><strong>Committee in control of funds</strong>: Allows for a select number of committee members to approve the spending of funds.</li></ul><p>The <em>weighted threshold </em>aspect refers to the ability to assign <em>variable weights</em> to any signatory. So in the committee example, it’s possible that a few members are higher ranking (whether by seniority or otherwise) and could be assigned a higher weight.</p><p>More information on this can be found in a<a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/post-quantum-secure-multisignature-wallets-321f75323e50"> historic blog of ours (Oct-2018)</a>.</p><p>Multisignature transactions functionality can be found in our desktop wallet in both <a href="http://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/releases/latest">binary (for Windows, Mac, and Linux)</a> and on the <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org">web</a> under the tools section. This is also accessible with the <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/wallet/wallet-cli/">qrl node cli</a>.</p><h4>Ephemeral messaging (LatticeTX)</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1004/1*-we4MriMrfHaAcVInWkcgQ.png" /></figure><p>The Ephemeral Messaging System allows peer-to-peer messaging which is able to secure messages (or any data really) back and forth — and in the future with GO-QRL, utilize the QRL network to do so.</p><p>This is all done utilizing the quantum resistant key encapsulation and digital signature algorithms <a href="https://pq-crystals.org/kyber/">Kyber</a> and <a href="https://pq-crystals.org/dilithium/">Dilithium</a>. To <em>further</em> increase security, these quantum resistant algorithms are combined with pre-quantum schemes that have been proven secure against classical computers.</p><p>To derive the keys for encryption and signatures, only the master seed of the wallet is used. Public keys are securely stored by a lattice transaction (LatticeTX) and associated to a QRL address, which can be seen as an identity. By deploying this functionality, the QRL blockchain can also serve as a standalone public-key infrastructure by any third-party application.</p><p>You can use qrl-cli to interact: <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-cli/">https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-cli/</a></p><p>As mentioned before, for the moment, you’ll still need to create your own <em>off-chain network</em>, but this sets the stage for GO-QRL, where everything can be incorporated on-chain for a fully decentralized, quantum secure, ephemeral messaging network!</p><h4>RandomX</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*C9sTRGLU4OI357N7L1oLEw.jpeg" /><figcaption>Art created by Discord user Smith</figcaption></figure><p>QRL initially launched mainnet with cryptonight variant 1 (cn/1) due to its commitment to security (it was extensively reviewed) and its ability to avoid ASIC’s from centralizing the hashrate of the network. As time has gone on however, we’ve seen an increase of centralization to fewer miners.</p><p>While no PoW mining algorithm can completely avoid the progress of ASICS and FPGA’s, there’s been some implementations that show more promise than others. RandomX is one of those algorithms that shows promise.</p><p>As indicated <a href="https://github.com/tevador/RandomX">from their github</a>, RandomX is a proof-of-work (PoW) algorithm that is optimized for general-purpose CPUs. RandomX uses random code execution (hence the name) together with several memory-hard techniques to minimize the efficiency advantage of specialized hardware.</p><p>Beyond that, it’s critical that any algorithm that underpins the security of the network undergoes a thorough peer-review process. To that end, RandomX has been reviewed by 4 independent security research firms.</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.trailofbits.com/">Trail of Bits</a></li><li><a href="https://www.x41-dsec.de/">X41 D-SEC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.kudelskisecurity.com/">Kudelski Security</a></li><li><a href="https://quarkslab.com/en/">QuarksLab</a></li></ul><h3>Other minor changes</h3><h4>Environment switch</h4><p>Ability to toggle mainnet or testnet with a network-type argument to `start_qrl`.</p><p><em>Note: To run both at the same time, it’s still necessary to change ports in config.yml of one of the nodes to avoid conflicts.</em></p><h4>Added addr_to field in message transaction</h4><p>Now an address can be added to an 80 byte message transaction, allowing for assignable messages on the blockchain.</p><h4>Added message_data to transfer transaction</h4><p>Allows for on-chain transactions to include references to transaction ID’s in things like e-commerce applications.</p><h4>Other</h4><ul><li>New API has been added to support data related to new transactions</li><li>Address State has been optimized</li><li>Block reorg limit has been reduced from 22,000 to 300 blocks</li><li>Legacy API support for wallet daemon &amp; grpcProxy</li><li>grpcProxy &amp; wallet daemon both support — network-type as an argument</li><li>Updated versions for some of the dependencies</li><li>Added more unit tests covering different scenarios</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*gOrStBxFYBOQaq1yBNkhVA.png" /></figure><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=2eed61ea90fd" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-bromine-hardfork-a-look-inside-2eed61ea90fd">The QRL Bromine Hardfork: A look inside</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Integration feature: Bromine hardfork pool — Fungibly]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/integration-feature-bromine-hardfork-pool-fungibly-6d3d3a953da5?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/6d3d3a953da5</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[mining-pool]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency-mining]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 14:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2020-04-07T14:31:00.863Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Integration feature: Bromine hardfork pool — Fungibly</h3><h4>Fair and transparent QRL mining pool</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*Ld2FGgse0jtwnwZFh2_CFg.png" /></figure><h4>Overview</h4><ul><li>URL: <a href="https://qrl.fungibly.xyz">https://qrl.fungibly.xyz</a></li><li>QRL Docs URL: <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/#fungibly">https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/#fungibly</a></li><li>Default Stratum: qrl.fungibly.xyz:4444</li><li>Pool Fee: 1% PPS with Hashback program</li><li>Minimum payout: 1 QRL</li><li>Payment Interval: 30 minutes</li><li>Medium: <a href="https://medium.com/u/24eb18c7fb06">fungibly</a></li><li>Telegram: <a href="https://t.me/fungibly">https://t.me/fungibly</a></li><li>Discord: <a href="https://discord.gg/PeeK7Br">https://discord.gg/PeeK7Br</a></li></ul><blockquote>Our goal at fungibly.xyz is to provide the fairest and most transparent QRL mining pool. With Hashback and our recent <a href="https://medium.com/@fungibly/monero-pay-per-share-pps-mining-fungibly-xyz-566b7d8be75?source=friends_link&amp;sk=a58dd998538eb4105223e84f04a45ab5">switch to pay per share (PPS)</a> we hope we are on are way to reaching that goal.</blockquote><blockquote>Please contact us with any questions or concerns, we are available on <a href="https://t.me/fungibly">telegram</a> and <a href="https://discord.gg/PeeK7Br">discord</a>. Stay tuned for more articles on mining <a href="https://medium.com/u/24eb18c7fb06">fungibly</a>. Happy Mining!</blockquote><h4>Hashback program</h4><p>Your exact Hashback rate will be calculated based on your total fees paid. As a guide please see the table below for Hashback rates at various fee levels.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/357/1*btgRA-tSYGCpkKvGlI9gQw.png" /></figure><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=6d3d3a953da5" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/integration-feature-bromine-hardfork-pool-fungibly-6d3d3a953da5">Integration feature: Bromine hardfork pool — Fungibly</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Integration feature: Upcoming Bromine hardfork pool — herominers]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/integration-feature-upcoming-bromine-hardfork-pool-herominers-6aa30fa6d433?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/6aa30fa6d433</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain-technology]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 12:07:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2020-04-07T12:01:00.931Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Integration feature: Upcoming Bromine hardfork pool — herominers</h3><h4>Cryptonight mining pools</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*JjkSp4QQ2JqpdXwjS1mSbQ.png" /></figure><ul><li>URL: <a href="https://qrl.herominers.com/">https://qrl.herominers.com/</a></li><li>QRL Docs URL: <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/#herominers">https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/#herominers</a></li><li>Default Stratum: qrl.herominers.com:10371</li><li>Pool Fee: 0.9%</li><li>Minimum payout: 1 QRL</li><li>Payment Interval: 5 minutes</li></ul><p>Herominers has been a longstanding QRL mining pool from the very beginning of QRL mainnet. We’re happy that they’ve continued to support us for our upcoming hardfork, Bromine!</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=6aa30fa6d433" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/integration-feature-upcoming-bromine-hardfork-pool-herominers-6aa30fa6d433">Integration feature: Upcoming Bromine hardfork pool — herominers</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Integration feature: Upcoming Bromine hardfork pool — GNTL Mining Pools]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/integration-feature-upcoming-bromine-hardfork-pool-gntl-mining-pools-49ba190694bf?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/49ba190694bf</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency-mining]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 09:01:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2020-04-07T09:01:00.942Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Integration feature: Upcoming Bromine hardfork pool — GNTL Mining Pools</h3><h4>GNTL Mining Pools, low fees, great support, all hashrates are welcome</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*JFtqAZZ94UPDkQ-qA_d6tg.png" /></figure><ul><li>URL: <a href="https://qrl.pool.gntl.co.uk/">https://qrl.pool.gntl.co.uk/</a></li><li>QRL Docs URL: <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/#gntl-mining">https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/#gntl-mining</a></li><li>Default Stratum: qrl.pool.gntl.co.uk:4444</li><li>Pool Fee: 0.1%</li><li>Minimum payout: 1 QRL</li><li>Payment Interval: 1 hour</li><li>Discord: <a href="https://discord.gg/bxr3TYQ">https://discord.gg/bxr3TYQ</a></li></ul><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=49ba190694bf" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/integration-feature-upcoming-bromine-hardfork-pool-gntl-mining-pools-49ba190694bf">Integration feature: Upcoming Bromine hardfork pool — GNTL Mining Pools</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Integration feature: Upcoming Bromine hardfork pool — Leafpool]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/integration-feature-upcoming-bromine-hardfork-pool-leafpool-8edb3c41af6d?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/8edb3c41af6d</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[integration]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[hard-fork]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 06:16:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2020-04-07T06:16:00.908Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Integration feature: Upcoming Bromine hardfork pool — Leafpool</h3><h4>Multi-algorithm fast mining pool</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*SJ2M0tCSWdVZHUA9QWgSHA.png" /></figure><ul><li>URL: <a href="https://qrl.leafpool.com/">https://qrl.leafpool.com/</a></li><li>QRL Docs URL: <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/#leafpool">https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/#leafpool</a></li><li>Default Stratum: qrl-us.leafpool.com:4444</li><li>Pool Fee: 0.8% (PROP)</li><li>Minimum payout: 1.0 QRL</li><li>Payment Interval: 10 minutes</li><li>Telegram: <a href="https://t.me/Leafpool_Mining">https://t.me/Leafpool_Mining</a></li><li>Discord: <a href="https://discord.gg/ZrvWWjC">https://discord.gg/ZrvWWjC</a></li></ul><p>Leafpool is a mining pool that deals in a wide variety of mining algorithms such as BeamHashII, Sha3, Cryptonight-turtle-light, Cryptonight-GPU, and soon to be RandomX</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=8edb3c41af6d" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/integration-feature-upcoming-bromine-hardfork-pool-leafpool-8edb3c41af6d">Integration feature: Upcoming Bromine hardfork pool — Leafpool</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Integration feature: Upcoming Bromine hardfork pool — Fastpool]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/integration-feature-upcoming-bromine-hardfork-pool-fastpool-1e276f6d8bde?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/1e276f6d8bde</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[hard-fork]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency-mining]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 23:06:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2020-04-06T23:06:28.923Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Integration feature: Upcoming Bromine hardfork pool — Fastpool</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*dgUHeB7hsSeCBjCsUxAnCw.png" /></figure><ul><li>URL: <a href="https://fastpool.xyz/qrl/">https://fastpool.xyz/qrl/</a></li><li>QRL Docs URL: <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/#fastpool">https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/#fastpool</a></li><li>Default Stratum: fastpool.xyz:10108</li><li>Pool Fee: 0.5% (PROP)</li><li>Minimum payout: 1 QRL</li><li>BLOCK FINDER REWARD 0.1% (Bonus)</li><li>Payment Interval: 30 minutes</li><li>Location: Europe</li><li>Discord: <a href="https://discord.gg/YPbeDVx">https://discord.gg/YPbeDVx</a></li></ul><p>Fastpool.xyz is a mining pool that consists mostly of cryptonight and randomx algorithms such as cn/r, cn/half, cn-lite and rx/0. A feature also available is multi-algorithm pools.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=1e276f6d8bde" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/integration-feature-upcoming-bromine-hardfork-pool-fastpool-1e276f6d8bde">Integration feature: Upcoming Bromine hardfork pool — Fastpool</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Integration  feature: Upcoming Bromine hardfork pool — Miningocean]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/integration-feature-upcoming-bromine-hardfork-pool-miningocean-f6d57b949336?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/f6d57b949336</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[mining]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 19:34:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2020-04-06T19:35:12.080Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><strong>Integration feature: </strong>Upcoming Bromine hardfork pool — <strong>Miningocean</strong></h3><h4>Ultra Stable High Performance Mining Pools</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*7LzUjYMaQG0kJCp046ykCA.png" /></figure><ul><li>URL: <a href="https://qrl.miningocean.org/">https://qrl.miningocean.org/</a></li><li>QRL Docs URL: <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/#miningocean">https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/#miningocean</a></li><li>Default Stratum: qrl.miningocean.org:5555</li><li>Pool Fee: 0.4%</li><li>Minimum payout: 0.5 QRL</li><li>Payment Interval: 30 minutes</li></ul><p>Mining ocean has been a longstanding QRL mining pool from the very beginning of QRL mainnet.</p><p>From mining ocean:</p><blockquote>Comfortable &amp; Reliable Quantum Resistant Ledger QRL Mining pool, run by first-class professionals. Adaptive DDOS Protection. Advanced support.</blockquote><blockquote>World class service at a low 0.4% fee. Our qrl pool keeps your rig hashrate safe and secure! Join us to contribute to the decentralization of the network!</blockquote><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=f6d57b949336" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/integration-feature-upcoming-bromine-hardfork-pool-miningocean-f6d57b949336">Integration  feature: Upcoming Bromine hardfork pool — Miningocean</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Get ready. QRL Bromine is coming]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/get-ready-qrl-bromine-is-coming-e31d5fbe2bb?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/e31d5fbe2bb</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[hard-fork]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[updates]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 10:43:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2020-04-06T10:55:45.774Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>In ~24 hours, QRL Bromine will be here. This is a brief overview and reminder of what actions you’ll want to take.</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*2HFOUkRsRLt3aIJtU5R2vg.png" /></figure><p>As of this post, QRL Bromine is going to hit <strong><em>in roughly 24 hours</em></strong> based on the current average blocktime. This blog contains a quick reminder of what actions you’ll want to (or need to) take depending on what group you find yourself in:</p><ul><li><a href="#e82b">Everyone with QRL</a></li><li><a href="#0bba">Pool miners</a></li><li><a href="#dabe">Node operators</a></li></ul><p><strong>Note: Even if you follow none of these procedures, remember, your funds are safe.</strong></p><h3>Everyone with QRL</h3><h4>Update your wallet binaries</h4><p>If you use either the binary desktop or mobile wallets, due to some minor API changes, you’ll need to update. Otherwise, use the online wallet. This update also allows you to take advantage of multisig addresses and transactions.</p><p><strong>Online</strong></p><ul><li><a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org/">https://wallet.theqrl.org/</a></li></ul><p><strong>Mobile</strong></p><ul><li>iOS: <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/qrl-wallet/id1458620542">https://apps.apple.com/us/app/qrl-wallet/id1458620542</a></li><li>Android (update 2.2.1 coming): <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.theqrl">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.theqrl</a></li></ul><p><strong>Desktop</strong></p><ul><li>Mac, Windows, Linux: <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/releases/latest">https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/releases/latest</a></li></ul><h3>Pool Miners</h3><h4>Setup xmrig with failover</h4><p>There will be a transition from cryptonight to randomX, which means that you’ll want your client (in this case, xmrig) to successfully switch without downtime.</p><p>To assist with this, we setup an official pools list page with a complete working xmrig config.json configuration for each pool: <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/">https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/pools/</a></p><h3>Node operators (Exchanges/pools/mining-nodes)</h3><h4>Upgrade your nodes</h4><p><strong>This can take several hours (~8) as it updates the state upon reinitializing the node, so needs to be done with time to spare <em>before</em> the hardfork.</strong></p><p>Take your node offline (ctrl+c) and update it:</p><pre>pip3 install -U qrl</pre><p>Then reinitialize your node</p><pre>start_qrl</pre><p>Nodes running QRL Node version lower than 2.0.0 will be automatically disconnected by the peers running QRL v2.0.0 or higher once the hardfork triggers.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=e31d5fbe2bb" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/get-ready-qrl-bromine-is-coming-e31d5fbe2bb">Get ready. QRL Bromine is coming</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>