<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Cryptography with longevity. A post-quantum secure blockchain featuring a stateful signature scheme and unparalleled security. - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 20:09:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/the-quantum-resistant-ledger" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Month in QRL 12/2019–1/2020]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-month-in-qrl-12-2019-1-2020-9ae87f253e7e?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/9ae87f253e7e</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dev-summit]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[hard-fork]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 18:20:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2020-01-13T20:10:48.002Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Developer Summit, Hard Fork News</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*8gRonUdQo1443PCCJBQ85A.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Happy New Year! This marks the first blog in the new monthly format. We have switched to this format to allow for these blogs to contain more information, be more meaningful, and to make it easier to follow along with each and every blog.</p><p>Since our last entry, the holidays have come and gone, and already there has been news on the Quantum Computing front. IBM and Daimler have <a href="https://www.cnet.com/roadshow/news/ibm-daimler-ces-2020-quantum-computer-solid-state-batteries-lithium-sulfur/">announced a partnership</a> to develop new lithium-sulfur batteries using quantum computers, <a href="https://phys.org/news/2020-01-advance-benchmark-quantum.html">new benchmarks for quantum computers</a> have been developed by researchers at the US Department of Energy, and <a href="https://www.eetimes.com/intel-cryogenic-chip-for-quantum-computing/">Intel has developed a new type of hardware chip</a> for quantum computers called Horse Ridge. 2020 has barely begun, and already it is looking like it will be a big year for quantum computing.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*z_DehZcA2vi3DwIPrtehCQ.jpeg" /><figcaption>Credit: Discord user Smith</figcaption></figure><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrandomx/commit/c9cac9e1c5f9d1ce260fc9605dbd4df947ade807">qrandomx</a>: Fix - Process all items on eventQueue to avoid deadlock</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/api.theqrl.org/commit/26111a862f70465c34a8235b8496abacaa988e74">api.theqrl.org</a>: API Patches (New API)</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/block-explorer/pull/331">block-explorer</a>: Use latest explorer-helpers module</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/explorer-helpers/commit/700dd2f29a298368869df50ae3692c30e07d4f5e">explorer-helpers</a>: build(deps): bump handlebars from 4.1.2 to 4.5.3</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-cli/commit/6b82388f8c506b4b624e7e9a591f4cf3c8a82784">qrl-cli</a>: feat: Add create-lattice and get-keys functions</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/commit/24aaf86ec33645bbf82b86750e6ac9c38830ed14">qrl-wallet</a>: Fix some UI issues and spend bug</li></ul><h3>Upcoming Amsterdam Dev Summit</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*eK6lo3akAk7DISzNU-CfQw.jpeg" /></figure><p>As many of you are aware, the developers for QRL will be meeting in Amsterdam this week to collaborate in person on the most important technical developments for the QRL network. Being able to work in the same place (to say nothing of the same timezone) can be invaluable to the development process. First in line for this particular summit is the upcoming hard fork — what is will contain (more on that below), implementation, optimization, and testing.</p><p>Look for more announcements regarding the developer summit and all it has accomplished once it has been completed.</p><h3>The Hard Fork</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*-nNQCz8N12ry2Zr-hwI-pA.png" /></figure><p>While more information will come out regarding the hard fork on the other side of the developer summit, and as we approach the date of the fork, for now we can give you some of what will be included, as well as some information regarding the timing of the hard fork:</p><p><strong>Dates<br>CODE FREEZE: 10th February </strong><br><strong>RELEASE: 11th February <br>FORK DATE: 25th February — Block height TBA</strong></p><p><strong>Features</strong></p><ul><li>RandomX mining Algorithm</li><li>Multisig addresses &amp; transactions</li><li>LatticeTX (ephemeral messaging stub)</li></ul><p>There will be more information regarding the hard fork as we approach the dates for code freeze and ultimately, the fork itself. Watch this space as well as our <a href="http://@QRLedger">Twitter</a>, <a href="https://discord.gg/BheKAZb">Discord</a>, and our <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/QRL/">subreddit</a> for more information.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=9ae87f253e7e" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-month-in-qrl-12-2019-1-2020-9ae87f253e7e">Last Month in QRL 12/2019–1/2020</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First post-quantum cryptography approval from NIST..]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/first-post-quantum-cryptography-approval-from-nist-6f132be3e41c?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/6f132be3e41c</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[nist]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[post-quantum-cryptography]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[post-quantum]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Peter Waterland]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:16:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-12-15T11:17:25.710Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/318/1*2Wep1olQzSWKjv6sd_KIKg.png" /></figure><p>This is a short but very important update for the project.</p><p>In mid-2016 the idea for a fully post-quantum secure ledger was conceived and one of the really tough decisions was which signature scheme to use.</p><p>Eventually <a href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007%2F978-3-642-25405-5_8">XMSS</a> was chosen for it’s cryptographic properties — but this was not an easy choice given it is stateful and requires significant computation prior to first use.</p><p>A small number of other projects utilise variants of one-time <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hash-based_cryptography">hash-based signatures</a> but QRL is the only crypto asset or blockchain which uses XMSS to protect the entire ledger.</p><p>Being unique in that respect it is exciting to see NIST have <a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.800-208-draft.pdf">draft approved</a> hash-based signature families XMSS and LMS for usage. In practice this means that currently QRL is the only crypto asset using (soon to be) NIST-approved post-quantum cryptography.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=6f132be3e41c" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/first-post-quantum-cryptography-approval-from-nist-6f132be3e41c">First post-quantum cryptography approval from NIST..</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Video Interview with Know The Coin]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/video-interview-with-know-the-coin-fc8f9d8445bc?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/fc8f9d8445bc</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-computing]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 19:21:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-12-09T19:21:21.306Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Video Interview with ChangeNOW</h3><p><em>Adam sat down with Pauline from ChangeNOW to discuss QRL and Blockchain</em></p><h3>Video Interview With ChangeNOW — Know The Coin</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*55PwLZQRy61N8TRRQ9ahDQ.jpeg" /></figure><p>Earlier this month, I had the opportunity to sit down with Pauline from <a href="https://changenow.io/">ChangeNOW</a> to record a video interview for their YouTube series <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLXY0gJl_qhdFpaewjzHn6Syf7EkaIF0VS"><em>Know The Coin</em></a>. Here’s the interview:</p><iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FYTW0FauLZu8%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DYTW0FauLZu8&amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FYTW0FauLZu8%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;key=a19fcc184b9711e1b4764040d3dc5c07&amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;schema=youtube" width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><a href="https://medium.com/media/2c2ef1bc344ce054458da74f3d4ef5fc/href">https://medium.com/media/2c2ef1bc344ce054458da74f3d4ef5fc/href</a></iframe><p>Additionally, here’s a link to the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YTW0FauLZu8&amp;">interview</a> on their YouTube channel.</p><p>The interview runs 48 minutes and in it we cover topics ranging from the basics of what QRL is, to blockchain security issues, the threat posed to blockchain and cryptocurrency technology from quantum computers, as well as the importance of open-source solutions in security in general, and in today’s blockchain industry in particular. We at QRL always enjoy the opportunity to share a bit about ourselves and our perspective in interviews like this.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=fc8f9d8445bc" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/video-interview-with-know-the-coin-fc8f9d8445bc">Video Interview with Know The Coin</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week In QRL 11/26–12/2]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-11-26-12-2-b4a34ecb3310?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/b4a34ecb3310</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[what-is-crypto-podcast]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 21:46:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-12-02T21:46:46.974Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, New Interview Released, Changing Format</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*B5iXCEipz86PCVo1g_7MLw.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>As you may have seen in the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/decentralised-voting-and-trustless-autonomous-hard-forking-269d024f4edb">blog released earlier today</a>, Ephemeral Messaging, Multisignature Wallets, and ledger-wide polls are some of the features that will be included in the next QRL hard-fork. We also have the audio from the <a href="https://soundcloud.com/whatiscrypto/episode-11-how-to-protect-bitcoin-from-quantum-computing-w-adam-koltun">What Is Crypto Podcast </a>(more on that below), and today another video interview was recorded (likely to be released later this month). We will also be slightly changing the format of this blog series moving forward (more on that below as well).</p><h3>Change To The Format Moving Forward</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*aWTgDUNZJtFH4s5_8Dn1Ng.jpeg" /></figure><p>When we started this “Last ___ in QRL” blogs, we debated internally whether to make it a weekly or monthly blog. The question was one of whether or not we would have consistent enough content to fill out a weekly blog, as well as whether or not a monthly blog would be too infrequent to give a good sense of progress. We initially decided on a weekly blog, and for the past 54ish weeks that has come in the form of the “Last Week in QRL” blog. While the format has served us at times, ultimately the disparities in content available to us on a weekly basis has made it clear; these blogs will be more consistent, and more useful to the community, if delivered in a monthly manner.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*3wTIdKSXxdBWuHvdJiVh_g.png" /><figcaption>Credit: Discord user Smith</figcaption></figure><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/commit/6e3f8a90e7c25ab60fdfad7da35160d999db4e79"><strong>mobile-wallet</strong></a><strong>:</strong> Correct hexseed and mnemonic retrieval for iOS advanced wallets</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/block-explorer/pull/329"><strong>block-explorer:</strong></a> Add MS_Vote and Fix UI handling of invalid transactions</li></ul><h3>New Interview Released — What Is Crypto Podcast</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/300/0*JuYyeDdvFPbc64zX" /></figure><p>A few weeks ago I sat down with Michael Nye of the “What Is Crypto” podcast to talk QRL, Quantum Computing, and blockchain in general. The audio is available on <a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/2VdNosP06URJb29IaH3PC3?si=NMKhSxL2R16XHiG1QZbKog">Spotify</a> and <a href="https://soundcloud.com/whatiscrypto/episode-11-how-to-protect-bitcoin-from-quantum-computing-w-adam-koltun">Soundcloud</a> right now. The interview runs about 20 minutes long and is mostly introductory (the podcast is called “What Is Crypto” after all). It is always a pleasant opportunity to introduce new audiences to what QRL is, and why we need quantum resistance in blockchain today.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=b4a34ecb3310" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-11-26-12-2-b4a34ecb3310">Last Week In QRL 11/26–12/2</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Decentralised voting and trustless autonomous hard forking]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/decentralised-voting-and-trustless-autonomous-hard-forking-269d024f4edb?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/269d024f4edb</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Peter Waterland]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 15:41:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-12-01T15:52:20.115Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Back in 2012/3 when I first became obsessed with bitcoin it was obvious to me there were many more applications than value transfer for bitcoin-like systems to improve the world. Chief among these was decentralised voting for use in provably fair and secure political elections. This was long before the QRL existed and even before the consensus related issues around bitcoin and the block-size fiasco.</p><p>Conflicts of interest are inevitable in any ecosystem where value is created, transferred and stored. If we have learnt anything from that period of bitcoin history, it is that decentralised monetary blockchains should be able to adapt in an autonomous manner without relying upon gatekeeping developers who may not share the same goals or viewpoint of the stakeholders (userbase) of that cryptocurrency. Contentious consensus changes may only be introduced in such a system following a specified upgrade path.</p><p>It seems logical that the place where contentious decisions to both network and token functionality should be decided is on-chain — the sole point of truth for everyone.</p><p>(Note: this may not stop the default and easiest position for contentious decisions to be deferred simply continuing the status quo).</p><h3>Roadmap upgrades</h3><p>For some time the core team and community have been debating various system upgrades through our <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips">QIP</a> (QRL Improvement Process). This process on github allows anyone to suggest an improvement to the existing QRL ecosystem to built. There, a safe dialogue between developers and users can occur where technical points of view may be discussed, or the merits of a particular upgrade debated transparently. Such discussion naturally includes only a small component of the community and tends to attract largely technical users and preclude interested but non-technical users. Still it is a crude measuring stick for deciding whether a feature should be actively pursued or set aside.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*72v61d9U1aXuUPPDU0UA-A.png" /></figure><p>The QIP system is a real gem for the QRL but governance of the project can be improved moving forward.</p><h3>On-chain voting</h3><p>The upcoming qrl-core hard fork includes several exciting new features including ephemeral messaging, multisignature wallet capability (built into the webwallet GUI) and an extension of multisig where ledger-wide polls may be held and voted upon by all QRL users with a non-zero balance.</p><p>How does this work? First let’s discuss how our QRL multisig setup works. First in the node or webwallet a new multisig address is created using a <em>MultisigCreateTx </em>In where more than one QRL addresses are added to the address with signatory weighting (think voting rights for each address). Next to move funds a <em>MultiSigSpendTx</em> is created by one of the listed addresses and the value to transfer and destination address(es) are declared. Finally, each signatory may make a <em>MultiSigVoteTx</em> to sign the spend transaction — then once the threshold is reached funds are moved (note: multisig vote and spend are functionally identical). Whilst this sounds complicated it is actually extremely simple using the click-through GUI of the webwallet.</p><h4>So, voting..?</h4><p>To allow ledger-wide voting a ‘magic’ multisig address (‘Q110000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000000’ to be precise — and unspendable) is now designated. This address is special because instead of a limited list of specific QRL addresses it has <em>all</em> QRL addresses with a non-zero balance as valid signatories.</p><p>Whilst in the backend they are actually modified multisig functions — to keep things clean there are two newly presented transactions subtypes to be used for voting:</p><ol><li><em>ProposalCreateTx</em></li><li><em>ProposalVoteTx</em></li></ol><p>Any QRL address may create a valid <em>ProposalCreateTx</em> and start a ledger-wide poll. This transaction sets the type of poll (QIP, user, consensus-changing configuration settings, etc) and allows a specific QIP to be designated, with an additional optional descriptive text string supplied, and a block-height expiry.</p><p>To vote upon an existing ledger-wide poll a QRL address simply creates a <em>ProposalVoteTx </em>supplied with the relevant<em> ProposalCreateTx </em>txid and supplies the voting data — support, reject, abstain etc..</p><p>Some of you will have realised that tracking and cataloguing decentralised on-chain polls and votes in the QRL will be easy by simply looking up the magic address on the explorer — with all data piped into readable useful form on the protocol updates page realtime.</p><p>With just the above behaviour it is possible for any QRL user to propose a new QIP and ask the community and stakeholders (coin holders) to objectively vote upon whether it should proceed — no developers or core team required whatsoever — fully decentralised.</p><h3>Self-amending chain behaviour</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/853/1*2y_77DdYw7SRDWqAQYgQkw.jpeg" /></figure><p>The more eagle-eyed will be wondering what ‘consensus-changing configuration settings’ means.</p><p>Once ledger-wide polls and voting is active then this opens up the possibility of creating self-amending behaviour for network consensus rules and behaviour.</p><p>The following parameters are <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/QRL/blob/master/src/qrl/core/config.py">configuration</a> settings in the qrl-core client. If changed they will potentially cause a hard fork and split the network into one or more chains. They may all be potentially ‘amendable’ following implementation of on-chain voting:</p><ol><li>block-time interval</li><li>block-reward</li><li>total emission</li><li>maximum block-size limit</li><li>consensus-changing threshold limit</li><li>block-height poll expiry maximum</li><li>minimum transaction fee</li><li>hard coded peer_list</li><li>re-org limit</li><li>minimum accepted qrl-node version</li><li>consensus algorithm (for a later release!)</li></ol><p>It is possible using the <em>Proposal</em> transaction subtypes to propose a direct network change, and then upon reaching a satisfactory threshold for that on-chain proposal, to autonomously fork in the new consensus settings from the next block. Thus, a poll with a successful vote may alter the parameters of the network in a completely decentralised trustless and autonomous fashion.</p><p>In effect the existing rules of the system are moved onto the chain and may be altered only by ledger-wide voting consensus.</p><h4>Examples</h4><p>An example could be altering the emission curve based upon consensus or making blocks more or less frequent than currently. Another simple change would be to alter the peer_list to amend a new IP address acting as a discovery node for new entrants to the network — say if some of the earliest network nodes were migrating to a new platform. During a network transaction spam attack it may be necessary to implement a temporary minimum transaction fee — this could be done via a voting proposal and direct fork update to raise the minimum transaction fee from zero.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/283/1*QNmylxWA1MG_vmpWqqYM9w.png" /></figure><h4>Future upgrades</h4><p>It is also possible to extend these initial self-amending features to include future code modules to automate a mining algorithm change or other consensus upgrade — for example, migration to POS at a given block-height.</p><p>There is a QIP coming out which will flesh this out in more detail and interested parties will be able to help us test these changes on QRL testnet in the near future.</p><h3>Definitions:</h3><p>Hard fork — a network upgrade which is not backwards compatible to existing clients, with legacy nodes behaving differently if not upgraded, potentially resulting in two versions of the chain going forward.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=269d024f4edb" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/decentralised-voting-and-trustless-autonomous-hard-forking-269d024f4edb">Decentralised voting and trustless autonomous hard forking</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL November 19–25]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-november-19-25-3d963a70789f?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/3d963a70789f</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain-development]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 21:11:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-11-25T21:11:37.950Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Call for Testers, Community Nomination Award</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*pkTYlvgdYH6zVIHnGooh1w.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>We are in the final week of November, and in the United States it is Thanksgiving on Thursday. As we move towards the end of the year, we want again to reiterate the call for those interested in testing multisignature wallets on the test network (more on this below). We also have a belated Community Nomination Award at the bottom of this blog from September.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/791/1*Mf7nZKSc0OxSpPWEm5SujQ.png" /><figcaption>Credit: Discord user Smith</figcaption></figure><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrandomx/commit/14c25b81e1bb1e2558db518a0e902d5cb1a2ee21">qrandomx</a>: Updated rx-slow-hash.c</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/docs.theqrl.org/commit/20091cc7bc0da9d6e76afcf3507eb03374b44a49">docs.theqrl.org</a>: CI/cache update</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/commit/093119ef0d9697fd6541bea0402476a751181dd0">qrl-wallet</a>: Add v1.1.15 to recognised versions</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrllib/commit/6d3fa7544fa0411ded2613062bf5b27d63d1900a">qrllib</a>: Add Dilithium+Kyber to webAssembly build</li></ul><h3>Call for Testers for Multisignature Wallets on Testnet</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*oniKuPD_6WG4V5DtBBARig.png" /></figure><p>We would like to reiterate the call for testers for multisignature wallets on testnet. If you would like to participate, it is as easy as creating a specific wallet address (not used for anything else) using our normal <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org/">web wallet</a> or one of our <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/releases/tag/v1.2.0">desktop wallets</a>, and messaging myself (Puck342 on Discord) or Jack (Jackalyst on Discord), or sending an email to adam@theqrl.org</p><p>If you are unsure whether or not you would feel comfortable using our testnet, you can try interacting with the QRL network in other ways, such as <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/node/QRLnode/">running your own node</a>, or <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/mining/mining/">mining on the network</a> to familiarize yourself. You can read more about nodes, mining, and everything else QRL on our <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/">documentation site</a>.</p><h3>Community Nomination Award — September</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*FYiFR1pOTqJ6dejAFMzAVA.png" /></figure><p>We are pleased to announce that the September QRL Community Nomination Award goes to Discord user wintermute.</p><p>Here is what wintermute had to say:</p><blockquote>I first became aware of the QRL project when it was just an idea. I recall seeing Peter Waterland mentioning on the bitco.in/forum, that he was mulling over the idea of a post-QC blockchain. I made a mental note of this at the time, as I could see its potential, although I was, and still am, nowhere near technical enough to volunteer services in “getting my hands dirty” on such a project. Since then, I have become seriously impressed at what he has achieved, instead of being just a voice amongst the millions, he pulled together a like-minded, hugely qualified team, and put in substantial work in many areas to made his idea a real-world product.</blockquote><blockquote>The first ground-up QC-resistant blockchain is revolutionary and must be considered a top three asset in any multi-coin cryptocurrency portfolio. For my own part, I enjoy observing the advancement of QRL, even if the market is not yet pricing in its full potential. I have spent many years observing other blockchains, and one take-away which I see separates the failures from successes, is avoiding the Not Invented Here syndrome. If a good, empirically working solution to a problem can be found from any source, even a rival coin, then consider using it on its merits. Avoid the trap of bias due to NIH. I see QRL embracing such pragmatism and this foretells a brighter future.</blockquote><p>As per their own words, wintermute has been aware of QRL since “it was just an idea.” We value all of our community members, but the perspective of a long-time member such as wintermute is irreplaceable as our community continues to grow. Wintermute has shown themselves to be a productive, positive member of our community and we are pleased that they have received the September Community Nomination.</p><p>Know someone who you think deserves a Community Nomination? Write “nominate [platform] [username]” (example: nominate twitter QRLedger) in the <a href="https://discordapp.com/channels/357604137204056065/357607117412106241/510858891706236929">#butler channel</a> of our <a href="https://discord.gg/BheKAZb">Discord server</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=3d963a70789f" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-november-19-25-3d963a70789f">Last Week in QRL November 19–25</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL November 12–18]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-november-12-18-9d2438ae52e?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/9d2438ae52e</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[randomx]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[multisig]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qip]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 20:40:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-11-18T20:40:55.568Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, QIP 010 — Quanta emission change</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*4btE0CL_8j1lxHSP7olcmQ.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Another week, another new QIP. With the second new QIP in as many weeks, we see another QIP that is targeted at the mining side of the blockchain. While more details are below, it is worth noting that changing the mining algorithm (as was proposed in QIP 009), or changing the emission schedule, as with QIP 010, are both fundamental changes to the blockchain that will likely require substantial debate and testing before any potential implementation.</p><p>We will also soon be asking for testers for multisignature wallets on testnet. If you have any interest, please feel free to reach out to myself (Puck342 on Discord) or Jack (Jackalyst on Discord) with interest.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/700/1*4MJCD9OZqdufiNuy98_I_g.jpeg" /><figcaption>Credit: Discord user Smith</figcaption></figure><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-cli/commit/fcc8f914c9bdcb534beaa59c1390641ca2c8086c"><strong>qrl-cli</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Adding descriptions to commands</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/docs.theqrl.org/commit/251095a3d7e9826cecadce6cf4c3e4aab3812b1f"><strong>docs.theqrl.org</strong></a>: Fixes to Node document and typo in Ledger Document</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrandomx/commit/2bca2fe13eeffe5227a05e18e167fa4ae236ea73"><strong>qrandomx</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Updated Swig Interface to expose ThreadedQRandomX instead of QRandomX</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/commit/093119ef0d9697fd6541bea0402476a751181dd0"><strong>qrl-wallet</strong></a>: Add v1.1.15 to recognized versions</li></ul><h3>QIP 010: Quanta emission change to 2 Quanta per minute</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*usz5t3QLTvc62eSvcBvZVg.jpeg" /></figure><p>Recently, GitHub user <a href="https://github.com/Ottslayer">Ottslayer </a>proposed <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/pull/21">QIP 010</a> — Quanta emission change to 2 Quanta per minute. Here is what he wrote:</p><blockquote>Emission is currently close to 6 Quanta per minute and will be exponentially reduced to 0 in approximately 200 years. Reducing the emission to 2 Quanta per minute will reduce the availability of Quanta.</blockquote><blockquote>Lower emission rate will most likely increase demand of Quanta, the price, and people who are willing to point their mining rigs to qrl which will enlarge the network.</blockquote><p>As of this writing, there are seven comments from four users on the QIP. The mining algorithm and emission schedule are two of the pillars upon which any blockchain is built upon. Change to either (or both) of these will probably have an effect on the relative desirability of mining a given chain, and as such can have direct effects on its hashrate and relative security, as well as its popularity in the mining community. It is therefore quite interesting that the last two QIPs have both dealt with these issues (QIP 009 being related to the mining algorithm).</p><p>As always, we would highly encourage any community members with opinions to voice them on the <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/pull/21">GitHub page for QIP 010</a>. However, given the nature of the proposal, we would especially encourage anyone who is currently mining QRL, or who has experience mining in general, to weigh in as to how you feel the proposed changes would (or would not) affect the current mining situation for QRL. As always, we are deeply appreciative of the involvement of our community members, and there is no better way to get involved than creating and/or commenting on a QIP.</p><p>Remember — anyone can submit a QIP on GitHub. Have a great idea for QRL? <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips">Submit a QIP</a>!</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=9d2438ae52e" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-november-12-18-9d2438ae52e">Last Week in QRL November 12–18</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL 11/5–11/11]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-11-5-11-11-9a7aa79de773?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/9a7aa79de773</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qip]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[randomx]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 19:03:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-11-11T19:03:21.687Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, QIP 009, New QRL Team Member</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*1QYtSmAfwpbDJoyig1fXwQ.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>As we move into the middle weeks of November, we at QRL have continued to play with multi-signature wallets on devnet, which we will be bringing to testnet in a reasonable timeframe. It is worth reiterating that multisignature wallet functionality will allow for more varied uses for our wallet, and will help provide functionality for second-layer application development moving forward.</p><p>Additionally, it is always exciting whenever we are able to add passionate and talented individuals to the QRL team. We are happy to announce that Michael Strike (Discord user StrikeAttack) has joined the QRL team! We have a blurb from Michael and more on what he will be doing below.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*urUBIFDA6rrLGHfXfrLQKw.png" /><figcaption>Credit: Discord user snannerb</figcaption></figure><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/explorer-helpers/commit/a21273c9bebb88ce38a682803681925b16b5a020"><strong>explorer-helpers</strong></a>: Parse multi_sig_address from Buffer</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/commit/093119ef0d9697fd6541bea0402476a751181dd0"><strong>qrl-wallet</strong></a>: Add v1.1.15 to recognised versions</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/theqrl.org/commit/7a399a885303e30b71f36ec94b7c716418ad9e49"><strong>theqrl.org</strong></a>: Google fonts + Update blog</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/QRL/commit/130044cb5015ad21db49a3b6867f1327a071b680"><strong>QRL</strong></a>: Fixes and updated integration tests</li></ul><h3>QIP 009: Change mining algorithm to RandomX</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ojnxSRHZ041dgcsy_IFtyw.jpeg" /></figure><p>Four days ago, GitHub User <a href="https://github.com/doctor-gonzo">doctor-gonzo</a> submitted QIP 009: Change mining algorithm to RandomX. Here is what he had to say (via <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/pull/20">GitHub</a>):</p><blockquote>A mining algo change would go a long way towards re-vitalizing the mining community. Many people built rigs or pointed rigs at QRL initially but have been crushed by ASICs / FPGAs and no longer participate.</blockquote><p>As of this writing, 8 different individuals have weighed in on the QIP, including 3 QRL team members (<a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/pull/20">link</a> to comments). Mining (for those chains that utilize PoW) forms the bedrock of operationality for a blockchain, and any changes to it will almost certainly have a ripple effect. That also means that inaction can be as dangerous as action, as an untenable situation can have a corrosive effect on the health of a blockchain network. As such, it is important to take such discussions very seriously, and the more good-faith participants in the discussion, the better.</p><h3>Introducing Michael Strike</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*bo0FMUqghvvsUxA6ttL2Kw.jpeg" /><figcaption>Pictured: Michael Strike</figcaption></figure><p>Many of you already know Michael Strike (Discord user StrikeAttack) from his activity on the <a href="https://discord.gg/VR9kcs2">QRL Discord</a>. An active community member for more than a year now, over time Michael’s involvement with the project grew. Recently, we have asked him to join us on the community/advocacy side of QRL. He will help us continue to optimize and grow our efforts to help raise the profile of the project, as well as continuing to help set us apart within the crowded blockchain space.</p><p>Some words from Michael:</p><blockquote>It is with great excitement that I have accepted a role with QRL as a core team member. I’ve been involved with the project since before mainnet, and getting to know the community and core team members has been personally rewarding. While I will be wearing many hats in this role which will likely change over time, I can share a few ideas up front. First, I intend to aggressively, professionally, and tactfully reach out to people of influence, organizations, and government agencies in order to expedite community awareness of our project so that we will be more strategically positioned in the future. Second, I also believe that establishing a solid brand identity is critical to the future success of this project. Third, I plan to develop media content and look for strategic areas of process improvement that will streamline efficiency. I have a strong, vested, and passionate interest in the success of this project and am looking forward to contributing the best that I can. Thank you.</blockquote><p>Once again we would like to extend a heartfelt welcome to Michael from the entire QRL team and community — we are certain that he will be an excellent addition to QRL!</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/498/1*-JhzEhEYTcoG9SAF19ChZg.gif" /></figure><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=9a7aa79de773" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-11-5-11-11-9a7aa79de773">Last Week in QRL 11/5–11/11</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL 10/29–11/4]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-10-29-11-4-db9d2e3b5987?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/db9d2e3b5987</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[swap-space]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 20:33:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-11-04T20:33:17.589Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, QRL on SwapSpace, QRL Community Nomination Update</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*AEhGT4z5iu-TbbD1KChQCw.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Last week marked the end of October and the beginning of November. Halloween has come and gone. At QRL, we have continued to work towards providing our users with more reasonable liquidity options. Additionally, we have been continuing to develop, iterate and progress our own internal projects. We have had some inquiries into our <a href="https://angel.co/company/theqrl/jobs">golang developer and UI/UX developer positions</a>, and some initial interest expressed in our research grants. We will hopefully have more news on that shortly, but for now, the best of the rest is below.</p><p>We have spent the week in part playing with multi-signature wallets on devnet, which we still hope to bring to testnet in a reasonable timeframe. It is worth reiterating that multisignature wallet functionality will allow for more varied uses for our wallet, and will help provide a bedrock of functionality for later second-layer application development.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*FwIeiNDdSUmyAgR9tzONKw.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/api.theqrl.org/commit/22589733e7417fea2e2717cee2b6c5eba68ed0c6"><strong>api.theqrl.org</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Fixes (<a href="https://github.com/theQRL/api.theqrl.org/pull/3">#3</a>)</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/js-api-bridge/commit/d8afed62ade219c6cd981fa77662f3ede42deadb"><strong>js-api-bridge</strong></a><strong>: </strong>TS -&gt; JS (babel) and a bit more…</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-cli/commit/fcc8f914c9bdcb534beaa59c1390641ca2c8086c"><strong>qrl-cli</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Adding descriptions to commands</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/commit/701fdc7350f2239e07310a7ec5af28b83ff4c5f5"><strong>qrl-wallet</strong></a><strong>: </strong>UX tweaks to wallet opening</li></ul><h3>QRL On SwapSpace</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*vbjYert7rA-ZI1UPjZuOUg.png" /></figure><p>QRL has been added to <a href="https://swapspace.co/">SwapSpace</a>! SwapSpace describes itself as, “a cryptocurrency exchange aggregator that will save you time.” As you can see in the above screenshot, using SwapSpace is easy; pick the digital asset to send in, pick what to receive, then enter in the address where you want to receive your funds. SwapSpace also has a handy <a href="https://swapspace.zendesk.com/hc/en-gb/articles/360009348540-Introduction">“How To” article</a> if you are unsure, as well as an <a href="https://swapspace.zendesk.com/hc/en-gb/sections/360001755039-FAQ">FAQ</a>.</p><h3>Community Nomination Update</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*UnmlJxDvSBsLOXxfMx9MPQ.png" /></figure><p>We will have the October QRL Community Nomination Update in a separate blog later this week.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=db9d2e3b5987" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-10-29-11-4-db9d2e3b5987">Last Week in QRL 10/29–11/4</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinex + QRL Promotion]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/vinex-qrl-promotion-6cadae9f7b9e?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/6cadae9f7b9e</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[vinex-exchange]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[vinex]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 15:20:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-11-02T06:01:16.194Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Vinex’s QRL Promotion</h3><p><em>You can earn extra QRL for depositing BTC and/or withdrawing QRL from Vinex</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ftcfjTDyy_PCEePf-4C5dA.png" /></figure><h3>Terms</h3><p><strong>Promotion Period</strong></p><ul><li>November 1st — December 1st</li></ul><p><strong>Promotion Pool</strong></p><ul><li>10,000 QRL</li></ul><p><strong>Details</strong></p><ul><li>Any user who deposits BTC to Vinex.exchange during the promotion period will get a <em>proportional </em>distributed share of 5,000 QRL, based on the amount of BTC deposited.</li><li>Accounts that have a QRL purchase order filled, and withdraw QRL to an external address during the promotion period, will get an <em>evenly </em>distributed share of 5,000 QRL.</li><li><a href="https://vinex.network/market/BTC_QRL">QRL-BTC</a> and <a href="https://vinex.network/market/USDT_QRL">QRL-USDT</a> markets on Vinex</li></ul><h3>How To Get Started</h3><ul><li>Go to Vinex and <a href="https://id.midasprotocol.com/register?client_id=ZPP2SyMeEGoeRNPaSxMasnhQ&amp;redirect_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fvinex.network%2Foauth%2Fcallback">set up an account</a></li><li>Have an external wallet ready for withdrawal via <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org/">Web Wallet</a> or <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/releases/tag/v1.2.0">Desktop Wallet</a></li></ul><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=6cadae9f7b9e" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/vinex-qrl-promotion-6cadae9f7b9e">Vinex + QRL Promotion</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>