<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Cryptography with longevity. A post-quantum secure blockchain featuring a stateful signature scheme and unparalleled security. - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:26:03 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/the-quantum-resistant-ledger" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL September 1–7]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-1-7-44c65be4f4b2?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/44c65be4f4b2</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain-jobs]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 18:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-10-07T18:47:00.536Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL October 1–7</h3><p><em>Development Updates, Job Opening for Golang and UI/UX</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*qwNSvuGWPEWevyGFOKCJ8g.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>We are now into the final quarter of 2019. Recently, quantum computing has been back in the news in a bigger way, with <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-02935-4">reports of increased levels of private investment in space</a>, as well as continued attention being paid by governments. We are also continuing to post job openings (more on this below), as we look to strategically grow the team ahead of our next development objectives. Finally, we will have the September Community Nomination recipient sometime later this week or next week.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*fJuyiylFc6FOZsiBPJg5-w.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>qrl-wallet:</strong> UX tweaks to wallet opening</li><li><strong>theqrl.org:</strong> Remove unnecessary clutter from splash</li><li><strong>block-explorer: </strong>Wallet address changed</li></ul><h3>Call for Golang Developer, UI/UX Designer</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*0AEyNpQM3HLQsrlz2jBd5A.jpeg" /></figure><p>As we have mentioned elsewhere, QRL is hiring three individuals for two specific positions (we are also separately searching for cryptographers interested in threshold lattice cryptography, for a grant we are developing) — UX/UI Designer, and Golang Developer(x2). You can see these <a href="https://angel.co/company/theqrl/jobs">job postings on angel.co</a>. We have received some interesting applications already, but want to cast as wide a net as possible to maximize the likelihood of finding the ideal candidate.</p><h4>Golang Developer</h4><p>From the <a href="https://angel.co/company/theqrl/jobs/638007-golang-developer">angel.co job posting</a>:</p><blockquote>If you’re interested but don’t fit every specification, don’t let that shy you away, it is a wish-list after all.</blockquote><blockquote>What you will do:<br>- Write industrial grade open source code that will be the backbone of a quantum resistant network.<br>- Work with a small, but growing team of talented developers and cryptography experts.<br>- Occasionally interact with the community in a polite and conductive manner.</blockquote><blockquote>What we wish you to be:<br>- You have a graduate degree or higher in computer science or affiliated field.<br>- You have written high-performance and concurrent applications.<br>- You are part of the QRL Community.<br>- You have p2p implementation experience.<br>- You are familiar with cryptography.<br>- You have a genuine desire to ensure all code is tested through writing unit and integration tests</blockquote><blockquote>Compensation<br>- Competitive based on capability and experience</blockquote><h4>UI/UX Designer</h4><p>From the <a href="https://angel.co/company/theqrl/jobs/307891-ux-ui-designer">angel.co job posting</a>:</p><blockquote>We are looking for someone to:<br>- Build a consistent brand identity and pleasurable user experience<br>- Explore ideas to improve the usability to our tools and apps<br>- Build upon corporate identity/image, color schemes, logo, layouts, visual identity</blockquote><blockquote>Your qualifications:<br>- BSc. degree in design/fine arts, related fields or experience in the area<br>- Minimum of 3yrs experience<br>- Experience in HTML/CSS, mobile applications<br>- Ideally experience in mobile hybrid frameworks such as Ionic, Framework7, etc.<br>- Previous experience with Android/iOS development.<br>- Some experience in software development is a plus.<br>- Critical thinking and able to work independently<br>- We appreciate if you can provide a portfolio of previous work.<br>- Language: English is critical</blockquote><blockquote>We offer:</blockquote><blockquote>- You will be a freelance contributor working remotely<br>- Very international team distributed around the world.<br>- Remote work and very flexible working times.<br>- Open source development, most of your work will be publicly recognized.<br>- We expect massive growth in the short/medium term.<br>- As an open source cryptocurrency project, you will receive payment in the cryptocurrency of your choice.</blockquote><h3>Community Nomination — September</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*UnmlJxDvSBsLOXxfMx9MPQ.png" /></figure><p>We do not yet have the response ready from the QRL Community Nomination recipient for September. We will probably have that later this week or early next week.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=44c65be4f4b2" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-1-7-44c65be4f4b2">Last Week in QRL September 1–7</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL: September 24th —  30th]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-24th-30th-e09ccd5b88fa?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/e09ccd5b88fa</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 04:16:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-10-01T04:16:22.064Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL: September 24th — 30th</h3><h4>Quantum supremacy coverage, development updates, and a call for cryptographers for grant(s) in threshold lattice cryptography.</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/994/1*id4o3CQ7l4MRE9IlkXQ0Og.png" /></figure><p>There’s been a flurry of activity since NASA temporarily dropped a paper indicating of google reportedly achieving quantum supremacy.</p><p>From that we responded with a <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/quantum-supremacy-and-the-case-for-quantum-security-today-in-blockchain-390fe55daab5">piece reasserting our position that it’s not a matter of if but when quantum computers pose a threat, and that blockchains should be either already prepared or be preparing for a post-quantum world</a>.</p><p>This was a followup article to the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/no-ibms-quantum-computer-won-t-break-bitcoin-but-we-should-be-prepared-for-one-that-can-cc3e178ebff0">previous one</a> when IBM announced a commercial quantum computer earlier this year in January.</p><p>If you’d like to know more about google’s achievement specifically, the best source is a blog from Scott Aaronson, who does a great job at breaking it down understandably for a high-school level audience. The blog is aptly called “<a href="https://www.scottaaronson.com/blog/?p=4317">Scott’s Supreme Quantum Supremacy FAQ!</a>”.</p><h3>Some coverage</h3><p>Needless to say, we’ve had some coverage, including a latest one where Coindesk and Adam Koltun connected in an article “<a href="https://www.coindesk.com/what-googles-quantum-supremacy-means-for-the-future-of-cryptocurrency">What Google’s ‘Quantum Supremacy’ Means for the Future of Cryptocurrency</a>”</p><p><strong>Other mentions include</strong></p><ul><li><a href="https://en.ethereumworldnews.com/google-quantum-supremacy-bitcoin/">Google Achieves “Quantum Supremacy”; is Bitcoin (BTC) Threatened?</a><br>- EthereumWorldNews</li><li><a href="https://decrypt.co/9642/what-google-quantum-computer-means-for-bitcoin">What Google’s quantum computer means for Bitcoin</a><br>- Decrypt</li><li><a href="https://cryptodaily.co.uk/2019/09/how-will-blockchains-battle-quantum-computing">How Will Blockchains Battle Quantum Computing</a><br>- Crypto Daily</li><li><a href="https://www.altcoinbuzz.io/crypto-news/blockchain-technology/does-google-threaten-cryptocurrencies/">Does Google Threaten Cryptocurrencies?</a><br>- Altcoin Buzz</li></ul><h3>Development updates</h3><p>Work continues to happen for the upcoming fork, (more on that in another blog). Outside of that there’s some small updates such as one to the wallet.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/643/1*qLb955qGcfDz-yRNfKV6Ig.gif" /></figure><p>It was reported from discord user Strike Attack that the wallet seed can be snatched from eavesdropping (think security cameras). This was quickly patched by JP Lomas in 24 hours with the current functionality shown in the above animated image.</p><h3>Call for cryptographers</h3><p>As part of our Foundations research arm, we’re putting out a call for cryptographers for a grant in threshold lattice cryptography.</p><p>More details will be released on that shortly.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=e09ccd5b88fa" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-24th-30th-e09ccd5b88fa">Last Week in QRL: September 24th —  30th</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[QRL Now Listed on VCC Exchange]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-now-listed-on-vcc-exchange-5c6d369ac4ab?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/5c6d369ac4ab</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[vcc-exchange]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 15:46:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-09-27T15:46:42.811Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>QRL is now trading on VCC Exchange, a Bittrex partner</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*_249rM2XPPQeKwSYj4hfeQ.png" /></figure><p><a href="https://vcc.exchange/">VCC Exchange</a> is a Singapore/Vietnam-based digital asset exchange focusing on blockchain who partnered with Bittrex in May of 2019 who continues to leverage its technology to offer “<a href="https://bittrex.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360028035472-VCC-Exchange-Launches-Digital-Asset-Trading-Platform-Powered-by-Bittrex-in-Vietnam-">Vietnam a secure, reliable and advanced trading experience</a>”</p><p>From Tung Dao from VCC Exchange:</p><blockquote>We are honored to launch our platform with the support of an established industry player like Bittrex. They are an ideal partner for us as we focus on compliance and transparency in the Vietnamese blockchain industry</blockquote><p>Those at VCC Exchange are cryptocurrency users too, and aim to provide a credible and transparent exchange users can actually trust and use. Their core competencies go beyond just that of being an exchange however, and includes blockchain startup crowdfunding, including IEO and incubation programs.</p><h3>Access</h3><p>Our <a href="https://vcc.exchange/exchange/basic?currency=btc&amp;coin=qrl">QRL/BTC market</a> can be accessed by creating an account and heading to our exchange page: <a href="https://vcc.exchange/exchange/basic?currency=btc&amp;coin=qrl">https://vcc.exchange/exchange/basic?currency=btc&amp;coin=qrl</a></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*hNkr6gxoGk7FYW9HhjioAQ.png" /></figure><h4>Mobile</h4><p>Other platforms for trading include iOS and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.vccexchange">Android</a> for trading on the go.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1002/1*scn0fRfF4vAiu7Z3L71z-g.png" /><figcaption>Image taken from VCC Exchange website homepage</figcaption></figure><h4>Final thoughts</h4><p>We are always wanting to expand our availability, whether that’s making cryptocurrency more usable, more developer friendly, or more otherwise accessible to those from around the world from all walks of life.</p><p>We’re happy to have VCC Exchange as part of this expansion of availability.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=5c6d369ac4ab" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-now-listed-on-vcc-exchange-5c6d369ac4ab">QRL Now Listed on VCC Exchange</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mobile Wallet v2.0]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/mobile-wallet-v2-0-f854d95afbef?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/f854d95afbef</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ios]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[mobile-wallet-app]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 16:50:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-09-25T16:50:39.111Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*B-9gXEIyEmOglGtTq_MeBA.png" /></figure><p>The QRL mobile wallet <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/the-qrl-mobile-wallet-is-officially-launched-e3014dd79d8e">Version 1.0</a> was released in 5 months ago to the iOS and Android platforms as the first usable quantum-secure blockchain wallet. Needless to say, it was met with a positive response, and a flurry of suggestions.</p><p>Those suggestions were appreciated, and Adem Bilican has been hard at work bringing most of those suggestions to materialization. Below are the results of his labours.</p><p><strong>Before we get into that, for those that can’t wait to get started, you can get the </strong><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/qrl-wallet/id1458620542?ls=1"><strong>iOS</strong></a><strong> or </strong><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.theqrl"><strong>Android</strong></a><strong> wallet at their respective stores.</strong></p><h3>Better wallet management</h3><p>Now you can set different names of wallets. Deleting a wallet has a better warning and asks for the PIN. Also corrected is the QR code generated on the wallet section.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*qoBnBaKavGSo2wn9Qz3aLQ.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*CbM90ui0EsEwp1FuR5X63w.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*tnv16XferZFDDpkF66XT0g.png" /></figure><h3>More fine-tuned transactions</h3><p>You can now choose the OTS key index by just tapping the “OTS key index” in the send view. In addition to that the transaction details page has been refined to include more helpful information without having to view things in the external block explorer.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*TjQLxily8fFyQwOqhmaU5A.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*iCyd8O1cnvyUaHCO-QDtJQ.png" /></figure><h3>New: Settings page</h3><p>A new settings page will allow you to change the node (and port) to connect to. If anything but the default node is selected, a small warning icon is presented next to the settings menu to let you know that you know you’re not connecting to the default node. If there’s connection issues a message will be displayed on the transaction list page.</p><p>You can also turn on or off PIN security depending on your circumstances (it’s generally suggested to leave it on if in doubt!). If turned on, the app will always ask for the PIN when the user switches back to the wallet or if the application is left idle for more than 15 seconds.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*1Uo5llHN4nFq3hVRrjQe-w.png" /></figure><h3>Better login/create page</h3><p>It’s now possible to open an existing wallet with a mnemonic. Previously, only the hexseed was supported, now you can open up an existing wallet with either the mnemonic or hexseed. This can be accessed from the login / create page, which can in turn be found when you’re adding a new wallet from the wallet management screen.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*iYZWGa9wA7pqhuqBaMHj-A.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*LRET8zMBLTeuoVkfTFJcRg.png" /></figure><h3>Other fixes</h3><ul><li>Date and Time are shown according to users’ general timezone preferences</li><li>Smoother and more responsive transitions between views</li><li>Additional UI/UX improvements</li></ul><h3>Version 3.0 and beyond</h3><p>With version 2.0 released, you may have some other feature request or change you’d like to see, or, you may have noticed that maybe your request didn’t make it into version 2.0.</p><p>First, check to see if your request isn’t already slated for version 3 and beyond by checking out github: <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/milestone/2">https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/milestone/2</a></p><p>If it’s not there, then feel free to make a request/bug report on the mobile wallet issues page: <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues/">https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues/</a></p><p>Finally, a big shoutout to the community members that graciously tested the mobile wallet, broke it, and made a bug report. Truly unsung heroes that don’t get thanked enough.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=f854d95afbef" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/mobile-wallet-v2-0-f854d95afbef">Mobile Wallet v2.0</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL September 17–23]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-17-23-de2cb842e019?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/de2cb842e019</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-supremacy]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ios]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 17:32:43 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-09-23T17:32:42.914Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Google Quantum Supremacy, New Exchange Listing, QRL Mobile Wallet 2.0 Coming Soon</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*vOMa2YhCOF7NZlsLhvPTYA.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>This past week has seen developments both within the QRL project, as well as in the wider world of quantum computing. On the local front, we saw the listing on <a href="https://trade.biteeu.com/trades">QRL on Biteeu</a> (link to <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/new-exchange-listing-biteeu-3d00fd8fbedf">blog</a>). On the national/international stage, we saw <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/b9bb4e54-dbc1-11e9-8f9b-77216ebe1f17">The Financial Times</a> initially break the story that Google has achieved Quantum Supremacy, which is easily the largest quantum computing advancement of 2019 so far. Finally, we are happy to announce a release date for our QRL Mobile Wallet 2.0</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*OhNo_CFeqF8VKdMcG2hfwg.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>audits:</strong> x41 audit report uploaded to GitHub</li><li><strong>theqrl.org:</strong> Blog + New market for markets page</li></ul><h3>Google Quantum Supremacy</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/920/1*6hJ0kInd5b5zSSrvU--2Yw.jpeg" /><figcaption>Credit: Google</figcaption></figure><p>Reported this past Friday by <a href="https://fortune.com/2019/09/20/google-claims-quantum-supremacy/">Fortune</a>, last week a paper was published to NASA.gov before being taken down, which seemed to indicate that Google has achieved <a href="https://fortune.com/2019/09/20/what-is-quantum-supremacy/">quantum supremacy</a>. The stated reason for the paper’s being taken down was that it was accidentally published early before a fully scientific vetting could take place (this could take up to months in time). Assuming that the claims in the paper are validated, it will usher in a new era in quantum computing, and will serve as further evidence that it is potentially possible to scale quantum computing.</p><p>The implications for the blockchain space (as well as a more thorough write-up on the signficance of quantum supremacy) can be found in the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/quantum-supremacy-and-the-case-for-quantum-security-today-in-blockchain-390fe55daab5">blog we published on this new when it broke</a>. To summarize, the advancement of quantum computing technology brings closer the date when the theoretical vulnerability of most blockchains in existence today, ECDSA public key cryptography, is able to be actively capitalized upon. Please go back and read the more in-depth blog if you are interested, it is full of information on the subject.</p><h3>New Exchange Listing — Biteeu</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*mRFcim9GR1MdKrJG7jHuqw.png" /></figure><p>As we wrote in our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/new-exchange-listing-biteeu-3d00fd8fbedf">blog last week</a>, we are happy to announce that QRL has been listed on another exchange — Biteeu. A partner of Bittrex, Biteeu is based in Estonia, and is a partner of Bittrex. You can go over to Biteeu and <a href="https://trade.biteeu.com/sign-up">sign up for an account</a> if you are interested.</p><h3>QRL Mobile Wallet 2.0 Coming Soon</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*odYhWFTGDzwwkGOs0qpkxQ.png" /></figure><p>As we have been stating in previous blogs, the QRL Mobile Wallet update is nearly upon us. This Wednesday, September 25th, the QRL Mobile Wallet 2.0 will be released. We are all very excited for the improvements coming along with this update. A summary of most of the improvements coming in 2.0:</p><ul><li>User can open existing wallet with mnemonic (only hexseed was supported so far)</li><li>User can choose the OTS key index, just tap the OTS key index in the send view</li><li>New settings page</li><li>User can change the node (and port) to connect to. If not connected to a specific node, a small warning icon is presented next to the Settings menu.</li><li>The user can turn on/off the PIN security. If turned on, the app will always ask for the PIN when the user switches back to the wallet</li><li>PIN is required if the user leaves the app for more than 15 seconds</li><li>Deleting a wallet has a better warning and asks for the PIN</li><li>User can give a name to the wallets</li><li>Corrected the QR code generated on the wallet section</li><li>Date and Time are shown according to users’ general timezone preferences</li><li>Additional UI/UX improvements</li></ul><p>We realize that, next to our block explorer, our mobile wallet is the most-used way for people to interact with the QRL blockchain. We are very happy to be bringing this update to iOS and Android phones later this week!</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=de2cb842e019" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-17-23-de2cb842e019">Last Week in QRL September 17–23</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Quantum supremacy and the case for quantum security today in blockchain.]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/quantum-supremacy-and-the-case-for-quantum-security-today-in-blockchain-390fe55daab5?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/390fe55daab5</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-computing]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 17:14:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-09-21T17:42:28.793Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Google has reportedly hit quantum supremacy. This is an overview of that, why it matters, and what this news means to blockchain and other systems.</h4><h3>Contents</h3><ul><li><a href="#b06d">Overview &amp; why it matters</a></li><li><a href="#3c36">What does this mean for blockchain? Modelling and risk assessment</a></li><li><a href="#53d0">What about the banks and the rest of the internet?</a></li><li><a href="#1cb8">The case for The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a></li></ul><h3>Overview</h3><p>Recently, news has broken out about Google reportedly hitting quantum supremacy.</p><p>This was first reported by the <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/b9bb4e54-dbc1-11e9-8f9b-77216ebe1f17">financial times</a>, who indicated that they’ve read a paper put on the NASA website before it was later taken down for unknown reasons. Since then, sites like <a href="https://gizmodo.com/google-says-its-achieved-quantum-supremacy-a-world-fir-1838299829">Gizmodo</a>, <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/f/614416/google-researchers-have-reportedly-achieved-quantum-supremacy/">MIT Technology Review</a>, and <a href="https://fortune.com/2019/09/20/google-claims-quantum-supremacy/">Fortune</a> have covered the event with more easily on the horizon.</p><p>While we’ll have to wait for Google to comment before we can confirm this milestone, there is some merit as they’ve been at the verge of achieving quantum supremacy for the last year when Google collaborated with NASA in 2018 to help them prove quantum supremacy. It was speculated late last year (2018) that the results would be seen <em>within months</em>.</p><p>Quantum supremacy, while ominous sounding, is really just a term that describes the ability of quantum computing devices to solve some specific (often limited in scope) problem that classical computers practically cannot. It’s the precursor to quantum advantage, where the problems become useful <em>beyond</em> merely demonstrating that they can solve problems that classic computers practically cannot.</p><p>Being able to outperform tasks of a classical computer is a watershed moment for quantum computing history.</p><h3>What does this mean for blockchain?</h3><p>If you’re not up to date, most blockchains (including all in the top 5 on CMC) use Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm (ECDSA) for public key cryptography. Using a quantum computer, <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/quant-ph/0301141">Shor’s algorithm</a> can be used to break ECDSA.</p><p>What this means is powerful enough quantum computers can derive the private key from the public key. So if an adversary gets your public key (and has access to a powerful enough quantum computer), then they can derive your private key, create a transaction, and empty your wallet.</p><p>As of June of 2018, it’s been c<a href="https://medium.com/@sashagnip/how-many-bitcoins-are-vulnerable-to-a-hypothetical-quantum-attack-3e59e4172e8">alculated that 36% of bitcoins reveal their public keys</a>. Further complicating the above matter, anytime you make a transaction, your public key is revealed to the network. At that point, if the quantum computer is fast enough, (or the network is congested, you pay a low tx fee, etc), a private key can be derived and a new transaction with a higher fee can be made which will process sooner, and empty your wallet.</p><p>More can be read in the paper “<a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1710.10377.pdf">quantum attacks on bitcoin, and how to protect against them</a>”.</p><p>While all of the above is <em>absolutely true</em>, it should also be noted that quantum supremacy isn’t going to break blockchain <em>today.</em> Despite this,<strong> we absolutely should be ready for one that can.</strong></p><h4>The nuance of risk</h4><p>As blockchain is a ledger of transactions entrusted by the soundness of cryptography, it’s of paramount importance to ensure that the cryptography backing it is secure.</p><p>Without that security, the blockchain as a system that can’t be trusted — and there would be no point using it. It doesn’t matter how great your UI is or how many transactions per second or what smart contract features you have, without a foundation of security there’s no blockchain as we know it today.</p><p>With this in mind, it’s generally well understood that under the assumption that quantum computers are going to continue to make progress, at some point blockchain developers will need to update the cryptographic portion of their blockchain to be quantum resistant.</p><p>How much time do they have? Well, there’s a lot of considerations to take place. Everything from the advancement of quantum computers to the time to select and implement the algorithm. <a href="https://medium.com/u/ad87280e1b3e">Allen Walters</a> laid out everything in his article that took <a href="https://medium.com/altcoin-magazine/an-addition-to-the-bitcoin-wiki-page-on-quantum-computing-and-moscas-theorem-of-risk-f2345e504bb4">Mosca’s Theorem Of Risk Determination and applied it to Blockchain</a>.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*uJYfTV46S1QNwc3byIFWWg.png" /></figure><p>Modified for brevity from the article</p><blockquote>v = Selection of signature scheme, proposal for implementation. There are no plug and play signature scheme to replace current schemes.</blockquote><blockquote>w = Reaching consensus and upgrading the nodes.</blockquote><blockquote>x = Migration period. Due to the decentralized nature of blockchain, this can only be done by the users themselves, since only they have the private key and thus only they have access to the coins.</blockquote><blockquote>y = Stagnant phase to minimize the risk of burning live funds. After the migration period there will be unmigrated coins. Eventually the decision will need to be made of what to do to those addresses which are still vulnerable.</blockquote><blockquote>z = The time we have until a quantum computer of a critical level has materialized</blockquote><blockquote>q = Margin we should deduct from z as a safe margin to compensate the blind spot caused by the fact that any assessment of the development curve of quantum computers is based on incomplete information. Additionally, q accounts for the fact that developments on other levels like algorithms improvements can contribute to a quicker reach of the moment a quantum computer can break the cryptography in question.</blockquote><blockquote>V, w, x, y, z, and q are all undetermined. V, w, x, y will need to be done for every single blockchain that is serious about risk determination personally. Since for none of these periods there is a substantiated period of time known, no serious risk determination can be done.</blockquote><p>The time we have until a quantum computer of a critical level has materialized (variable ‘z’ in the above formula) is different depending on who you ask. The paper referenced earlier, quantum attacks on bitcoin and how to protect against them, modeled earliest estimates to be 2027 (8 years from now).</p><p><a href="https://github.com/theqrl-community/QCcalc">QCCalc</a> is another model which can be run using Octave or Matlab and takes into consideration things like:</p><ul><li>yearly increase in qbits</li><li>yearly error rate improvement</li><li>yearly algorithmic improvement</li><li>required runtime</li><li>maximum acceptable risk</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*KRD91ySRje6jMxOdy6zX4g.png" /><figcaption>Some possible assumptions and their output by the author of QCCalc</figcaption></figure><p>Outside of these models there’s predictions ranging from 2 to 30+ years, but it’s important to consider that <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2019/06/how-to-predict-the-future/588040/">humans are often comically bad at predicting events</a>.</p><p>It’s <em>also</em> worth noting that while these models try to predict the future often based on past historical behavior, quantum computing is in its infancy and is now in an arms race. There’s lots at stake here for nations and commercial enterprises:</p><ul><li>The <a href="https://faqq.info/quantum-computing-is-coming/#fn:USA">USA</a>, <a href="https://faqq.info/quantum-computing-is-coming/#fn:CHINA">China</a>, <a href="https://faqq.info/quantum-computing-is-coming/#fn:EU">EU</a> and other nation states are investing heavily into quantum computing.</li><li>Tech giants such as <a href="https://faqq.info/quantum-computing-is-coming/#fn:GOOGLE">Google</a>, <a href="https://faqq.info/quantum-computing-is-coming/#fn:IBM">IBM</a>, <a href="https://faqq.info/quantum-computing-is-coming/#fn:INTEL">Intel</a>, <a href="https://faqq.info/quantum-computing-is-coming/#fn:RIGETTI">Rigetti</a> and <a href="https://faqq.info/quantum-computing-is-coming/#fn:MICROSOFT">Microsoft</a> are all competing for market share.</li></ul><p>This makes being ready for what is known as a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_swan_theory">black swan</a> event critical to critical systems.</p><h3>What about the banks and the rest of the internet?</h3><p>These are critical systems, but they’re also (mostly) centralized systems!</p><p>This means they don’t face some crucial issues decentralized blockchains do. They can centrally change their cryptography without compliance of their users and the whole process can be done behind user interface. Banks for example have your keys so can afford to upgrade their systems later without you noticing.</p><p>For websites and the internet at large, both servers and browsers will need to update to include post quantum security. However, it’s possible to safely deny users on older systems wanting to use insecure cryptographic methods. To add, organizations like Google and Cloudflare are hard at work ensuring our internet is safe:</p><ul><li><a href="https://security.googleblog.com/2016/07/experimenting-with-post-quantum.html">https://security.googleblog.com/2016/07/experimenting-with-post-quantum.html</a></li><li><a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/towards-post-quantum-cryptography-in-tls/">https://blog.cloudflare.com/towards-post-quantum-cryptography-in-tls/</a></li></ul><h3>The case for the Quantum Resistant Ledger</h3><p>As we’ve found in creating our own blockchain, the process of making a blockchain quantum secure wasn’t merely matter of dropping in another signature scheme and opening a github repository.</p><p>We first needed to consult with experts in the field of post-quantum cryptography and begin work on the structure of our codebase, which was first released to github in 2016. It wasn’t until 2 years later did we release mainnet in 2018</p><p>Part of it is that time spent is because we’re pioneers in the field. This is the first time a project has used the eXtended Merkle Signature Scheme (XMSS) in a blockchain project. While XMSS is recognized by NIST as being post-quantum secure due to its minimal security assumptions (hashes), it’s also stateful, which means it needs to be run in systems that keep state (like blockchain), but comes with some special design considerations.</p><p>Beyond that, post-quantum secure cryptography often has performance and size considerations when compared to the likes of ECDSA and we had to ensure our network design and nodes could handle the load.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*msfoieYeQjNDoXzYwrT1eg.png" /><figcaption>Taken from a previous blog of ours which looked at performance: <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-improvements-i-63813234ef23">https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-improvements-i-63813234ef23</a></figcaption></figure><p>The QRL also includes the possibility to upgrade signature schemes (XMSS, SPHINCS, + future) and cryptographic hash functions (SHA2_256, SHAKE_128, SHAKE256 etc), and indicate so through an address format. This brings forward the capability of being crypto-agile, something no blockchain should be without.</p><p>All of this is externally audited with 100% coverage between <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/red4sec-security-audit-concludes-a-summary-563ecfe04c75">red4sec</a> and <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/audits/blob/master/x41%20Audit%20Response.pdf">x41 D-sec</a>.</p><p>From this strong foundation built up a full <em>very user friendly</em> ecosystem</p><ul><li>Desktop (<a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/">Windows</a>, <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/">Mac</a>, <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/">Linux</a>)</li><li>Mobile (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/qrl-wallet/id1458620542?ls=1&amp;mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.theqrl">Android</a>)</li><li>Web (<a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org">wallet</a>, <a href="https://explorer.theqrl.org">explorer</a>)</li><li>Hardware wallet support with <a href="https://support.ledger.com/hc/en-us/articles/360019184453">Ledger Nano S</a></li><li>Reusable addresses</li><li>On-chain message support (80 bytes)</li><li>PQ-notarisation support</li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-and-keybase-84968003bca2">Keybase</a> ID integration</li></ul><p>Along with several methods to interact with the foundation to further expand the ecosystem.</p><ul><li><a href="https://api.theqrl.org/#qrl-api">QRL API</a>: Organized around GRPC which uses <a href="https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers/docs/overview">protocol buffers</a> for serializing structured data. If you’re working on an integrated application, this is what you want.</li><li><a href="https://api.theqrl.org/#explorer-api">Explorer API</a>: Great for quickly getting QRL address balances, population, and other such data.</li><li><a href="https://api.theqrl.org/#wallet-api">Wallet API (requires node)</a>: If you’re working with wallets (ie. exchanges and other services), this is recommended.</li><li><a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/wallet/wallet-cli/">qrl command line (requires node)</a>: Comes equipped with the python node, offers simpler functionality to the wallet API.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-cli">qrl-cli</a>: Executable with mac, linux, and osx binaries, for interacting with the QRL blockchain via scripts and applications without requiring a full node.</li></ul><p>All of this can be found in our <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org">documentation</a> and <a href="https://api.theqrl.org">API</a> sites.</p><p>What it comes down to is every blockchain will need to go through proposing and designing an implementation (not likely to be drop-in replacement), reach consensus of the propsal, (hopefully) audit their implementation, and then to get as much as the total population to manually migrate before making the decision to invariably lock peoples funds or let them be hacked.</p><blockquote><strong>Today, QRL has 100% quantum secure ledger coverage, and is ready to be built on and used for a quantum tomorrow.</strong></blockquote><p>Be sure to come join us and our community at <a href="https://twitter.com/qrledger">Twitter</a>, <a href="https://reddit.com/r/qrl">Reddit</a>, <a href="https://facebook.com/theqrl">Facebook</a>, and <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">Discord</a>.</p><p>Want to get in touch to speak with us about quantum computing and how it intersects with blockchain technology or would be interested in collaborating? You can reach out through email at <a href="mailto:info@theqrl.org">info@theqrl.org</a> or on our <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">Discord</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=390fe55daab5" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/quantum-supremacy-and-the-case-for-quantum-security-today-in-blockchain-390fe55daab5">Quantum supremacy and the case for quantum security today in blockchain.</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Exchange Listing — Biteeu]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/new-exchange-listing-biteeu-3d00fd8fbedf?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/3d00fd8fbedf</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[crypto-exchange]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[biteeu]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 15:17:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-09-20T15:17:16.435Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>New Exchange Listing — Biteeu</h3><p><em>QRL is now trading on Biteeu</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*mRFcim9GR1MdKrJG7jHuqw.png" /></figure><h3>What is Biteeu?</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/910/1*g-gk3GyyIM_uhP5MEELbrg.png" /></figure><p>Biteeu is an exchange based in Estonia, a member of the European Union. Biteeu is a partner of Bittrex.</p><p>From the Biteeu website:</p><blockquote>BITEEU DCX OÜ was founded in 2019 in the Republic of Estonia by professionals with solid experience in banking sector, stock market and international public companies. It is a fully licensed and compliant virtual currency exchange in the European Union. We highly value integrity, safety and security. Therefore, we have developed our anti-money laundering and know your customer policies in accordance with the strict requirements of local laws and International acts.</blockquote><p>Regarding their collaboration with Bittrex:</p><blockquote>BITEEU DCX OÜ in collaboration with Bittrex uses its advanced technology to offer our customers safe, reliable and comfortable trading experience. Our platform supports several languages including English, Russian and Chinese. It provides round-the-clock customer service and ensures the safety of your assets and data.</blockquote><p>CEO of Bittrex Bill Shihara had this to say about Biteeu:</p><blockquote>The Biteeu platform will provide customers in Estonia and the region with a reliable, secure, and advanced trading option along with liquidity and the world’s most innovative blockchain projects. That is a combination that excites us as we continue to expand our partner network and increase adoption of this revolutionary technology. We are always looking to drive the blockchain revolution forward and in Biteeu we have a new partner who shares that same vision!</blockquote><h3>How Do I Access QRL On Biteeu?</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/512/1*MoV_Z0Q4TtlJqDc7c2N58w.png" /></figure><p>With over 50 digital assets available on its platform, against three base pairs (BTC, ETH, USDT), Biteeu has quickly expanded following receiving licenses from the Republic of Estonia earlier this year. It currently holds the following licenses:</p><ul><li>Providing a virtual currency wallet service (FRK000660)</li><li>Providing services of exchanging a virtual currency against a fiat currency (FVR000760)</li></ul><p>To access QRL on Biteeu, first you will need to <a href="https://trade.biteeu.com/sign-up">make an account with Biteeu</a>. You can also <a href="https://trade.biteeu.com/search">check out their markets</a> before you sign up if you’d like. There is a light/dark mode for those with specific UI preferences.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=3d00fd8fbedf" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/new-exchange-listing-biteeu-3d00fd8fbedf">New Exchange Listing — Biteeu</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL September 10–16]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-10-16-ff1065770b7a?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/ff1065770b7a</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[mobile-wallets]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ios]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 22:13:50 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-09-16T22:22:01.695Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Thanks to Beta Testers, New Exchange Listing Coming</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*i3I9iGSFw8J8qPDDEs2XCA.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>As we move further into September, there are many exciting things on the horizon. Recently, Proof-of-Stake has been discussed more internally, as have greater attempts to involve our passionate community, and we are nearing the release window for Mobile Wallet v2. Additionally, we are happy to announce that there is another exchange listing on the horizon (more on this below).</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*fY_2YroVG0hzMHFJGjqCxA.png" /></figure><ul><li><strong>mobile-wallet:</strong> Preparing Release 2.0</li></ul><p>As a reminder, here is a general list of the features/changes coming to Mobile Wallet 2.0</p><ul><li>User can open existing wallet with mnemonic (only hexseed was supported so far)</li><li>User can choose the OTS key index, just tap the OTS key index in the send view</li><li>New settings page</li><li>User can change the node (and port) to connect to. If not connected to a specific node (we can decide which one, the default will be mainnet-*) a small warning icon is presented next to the Settings menu.</li><li>The user can turn on/off the PIN security. If turned on, the app will always ask for the PIN when the user switches back to the wallet</li><li>PIN is required if the user leaves the app for more than 15 seconds (I can change it if too short/long)</li><li>Deleting a wallet has a better warning and asks for the PIN</li><li>User can give a name to the wallets</li><li>Corrected the QR code generated on the wallet section</li><li>Date and Time are shown according to users’ general timezone preferences</li><li>Additional UI/UX improvements</li></ul><h3>Thank You Mobile Beta Testers</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*-vzkIxIj_Cs1hoMYLidS5A.jpeg" /></figure><p>The QRL Team would like to extend our thanks to all the beta testers who have participated in testing the upcoming mobile wallet 2.0. In any technological endeavor, testing is important, but for a project our size, having a group of passionate beta testers who can look at our mobile wallet in various operating systems, screen sizes, etc helps us in our efforts to develop the best QRL ecosystem possible.</p><h3>New Exchange Listing Incoming</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/637/1*ezTHk5Wuv02yk94FZ8ckTg.jpeg" /></figure><p>While we usually use these blogs as an opportunity to review what has happened in the wide world of QRL over the past week, on occasion we will also look to the future. Given the priority of conversation that exchange listings have taken in our community of late, we thought it reasonable to let our users know that there is another exchange listing coming.</p><p>For obvious reasons, we cannot be explicit in the details at this time in terms of what exchange it is, and exactly when we will be listing. However, we did not want to remain entirely silent in the face of the continuing conversation regarding liquidity availability for our users. Look for a dedicated blog, as well as dedicated social posts, regarding this development once the listing day arrives.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=ff1065770b7a" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-10-16-ff1065770b7a">Last Week in QRL September 10–16</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL September 3–9]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-3-9-d6ac1eef7a64?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/d6ac1eef7a64</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 21:37:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-09-09T18:49:41.923Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Community Nomination Blog Incoming</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*dr3gyjnrK8iE89_uqMNT2Q.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>September is upon us, and with it the first inklings of Autumn crispness ready to drive out the Summer heat. At QRL, there has been a flutter of activity both within the team itself, as well as in our interactions with outside organizations/individuals. Unfortunately, a significant portion of this activity cannot be discussed in detail yet. The best of the rest is below.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*eVmEIQjTsrj7O-ziaxQhXg.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>mobile-wallet:</strong> Release v0.2.6-beta</li><li><strong>theqrl.org:</strong> Added a standards body (nist/IETF) section to highlight documents/etc</li><li><strong>block-explorer:</strong> Wallet address changed — herominer</li></ul><h3>August Community Nomination Award</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*UnmlJxDvSBsLOXxfMx9MPQ.png" /></figure><p>This month’s Community Nomination Award was not included in last week’s or today’s blog because there has been a slight delay in confirming the recipient. A separate blog on the August Community Nomination Award recipient should be forthcoming in the next week or so.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=d6ac1eef7a64" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-3-9-d6ac1eef7a64">Last Week in QRL September 3–9</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL — August 27th to September 2nd]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-august-27th-to-september-2nd-6dc285d3927b?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/6dc285d3927b</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[api]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-computing]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[app-development]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 21:43:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-09-03T16:11:13.461Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*gWIJsu0HPzqtTy5A53eFWQ.png" /></figure><h3>Last Week in QRL — August 27th to September 2nd</h3><h4>Mobile Wallet v2: Testers Needed! and API’s and spotlights: Apps wanted!</h4><h3>Mobile Wallet version 2: Testers Needed!</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*pRbo9beNhPFGXbeF2_CywA.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*CbM90ui0EsEwp1FuR5X63w.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*iCyd8O1cnvyUaHCO-QDtJQ.png" /><figcaption>Sneak peak.</figcaption></figure><p>Our iOS/Android version 1 wallet came with the ability to manage multiple wallets, send/receive Quanta, view your balance/transaction history, set a lock-screen, and instantiate a wallet from our web-wallet through a QR Code.</p><p>Since then, there’s been many feature requests that’s been segmented into <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues?q=is%3Aopen+is%3Aissue+milestone%3Av2">version 2</a> and <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/milestone/2">version 3 and beyond</a>.</p><p>We’re pleased to announce that version 2 is ready for beta testing with the following updates:</p><ul><li>User can open existing wallet with mnemonic (only hexseed was supported so far)</li><li>User can choose the OTS key index, just tap the OTS key index in the send view</li><li>New settings page</li><li>User can change the node (and port) to connect to. If not connected to a specific node (we can decide which one, the default will be mainnet-*) a small warning icon is presented next to the Settings menu. If you want to try, for the test version the default node (the one without a warning) is: <a href="http://testnet-4.automated.theqrl.org">testnet-4.automated.theqrl.org</a></li><li>The user can turn on/off the PIN security. If turned on, the app will always ask for the PIN when the user switches back to the wallet</li><li>PIN is required if the user leaves the app for more than 15 seconds (I can change it if too short/long)</li><li>Deleting a wallet has a better warning and asks for the PIN</li><li>User can give a name to the wallets</li><li>Corrected the QR code generated on the wallet section</li><li>Date and Time are shown according to users’ general timezone preferences</li><li>Additional UI/UX improvements</li></ul><p>Before we release it to the general public however, proper testing is required.</p><h4>TestPilots required!</h4><p>We have gone through internal testing, now we need your help!</p><p><strong>iOS users: </strong>There is nothing you need to do, granted that you are already enrolled in the beta test through the apple store. Once the latest version hits the Apple store you will have the ability to update to the latest version.</p><p>If you would like to enroll in the iOS beta test, please send a DM to ‘@adem’ on Discord with the email address associated with your App store account.</p><p><strong>Android users:</strong> Please send a <strong>DM</strong> to @adem on Discord with your <strong>GMAIL Address</strong> associated with your play store account so he can add you to the testing group in the play store. This will allow the same functionality as the apple store, pushing the latest changes to your device.</p><p><strong><em>As a reminder, this is a BETA test!!</em></strong></p><ul><li>The beta wallet uses our <strong>Testnet</strong>, no actual funds are used for this test.</li><li><em>OTS keys </em><strong><em>MUST</em></strong><em> never be re-used. Using the same wallet for </em><em>mainnet and </em><em>testnet is dangerous. Generate a new test wallet and don’t reuse across networks.</em></li><li>Things may break or become un-reliable while we update and make changes.</li><li>You can’t use two different applications on your phone at the same time. If you’re planning on removing your current v1 application and installing the beta,<strong> be sure to backup your current wallet and make sure you can recover it!!! We will not be responsible for lost funds.</strong></li><li>If you need some <strong>Testnet</strong> funds, put out a message on one of our social media platforms with your testnet address and someone we’ll send you some.</li></ul><p><strong>What We Expect Of You</strong></p><p>Try and break things! Hack them if you can, or simply think like a beginner. Can your parents/grandparents/kids/friends use this application? Is it easy? What could be improved?</p><p>Feedback and issues should be directed over at github, so we can keep things organized and track the changes requested: <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues">https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet/issues</a></p><p>Please include this information GitHub for any issues you have found.</p><pre>Action:<br>Expected Result:<br>Actual Result:<br>Android/iOS version:<br>Android/iOS handset model:</pre><p>For feedback in the form of feature requests, check to see if it already exists and then write it as an issue, freeform. Be sure to use a descriptive title!</p><p>No feedback is bad feedback!</p><h3>APIs and Spotlights</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*osqj_ihls3BJylOML6BIIA.png" /></figure><p>We now have 5 different ways to work off of The QRL, with another on its way explicitly for EMS:</p><ul><li><a href="https://api.theqrl.org/#qrl-api">QRL API</a>: Organized around GRPC which uses <a href="https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers/docs/overview">protocol buffers</a> for serializing structured data. If you’re working on an integrated application, this is what you want.</li><li><a href="https://api.theqrl.org/#explorer-api">Explorer API</a>: Great for quickly getting QRL address balances, population, and other such data.</li><li><a href="https://api.theqrl.org/#wallet-api">Wallet API (requires node)</a>: If you’re working with wallets (ie. exchanges and other services), this is recommended.</li><li><a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/wallet/wallet-cli/">qrl command line (requires node)</a>: Comes equipped with the python node, offers simpler functionality to the wallet API.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-cli">qrl-cli</a>: Executable with mac, linux, and osx binaries, for interacting with the QRL blockchain via scripts and applications without requiring a full node.</li></ul><h4>Apps Wanted!</h4><p>The above functionality should be plenty to start developing your post-quantum secure blockchain application!</p><p>For those building QRL applications and wanting to showcase them, it’s encouraged to request to put them in our <a href="https://github.com/theqrl-community">theqrl-community</a> github, which will allow projects to get some spotlight from the QRL community.</p><p>Need an idea? Head over to <a href="https://discord.gg/KAg5fAm">#qrl-app-ideas</a> in our Discord and pick one. Stuck? Post in our <a href="https://discord.gg/AmG7659">#development</a> channel for any help you may need, and finally, don’t forget our <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/">documentation</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=6dc285d3927b" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-august-27th-to-september-2nd-6dc285d3927b">Last Week in QRL — August 27th to September 2nd</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>