<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Cryptography with longevity. A post-quantum secure blockchain featuring a stateful signature scheme and unparalleled security. - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 19:03:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/the-quantum-resistant-ledger" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL 11/5–11/11]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-11-5-11-11-9a7aa79de773?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/9a7aa79de773</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qip]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[randomx]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 19:03:21 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-11-11T19:03:21.687Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, QIP 009, New QRL Team Member</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*1QYtSmAfwpbDJoyig1fXwQ.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>As we move into the middle weeks of November, we at QRL have continued to play with multi-signature wallets on devnet, which we will be bringing to testnet in a reasonable timeframe. It is worth reiterating that multisignature wallet functionality will allow for more varied uses for our wallet, and will help provide functionality for second-layer application development moving forward.</p><p>Additionally, it is always exciting whenever we are able to add passionate and talented individuals to the QRL team. We are happy to announce that Michael Strike (Discord user StrikeAttack) has joined the QRL team! We have a blurb from Michael and more on what he will be doing below.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*urUBIFDA6rrLGHfXfrLQKw.png" /><figcaption>Credit: Discord user snannerb</figcaption></figure><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/explorer-helpers/commit/a21273c9bebb88ce38a682803681925b16b5a020"><strong>explorer-helpers</strong></a>: Parse multi_sig_address from Buffer</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/commit/093119ef0d9697fd6541bea0402476a751181dd0"><strong>qrl-wallet</strong></a>: Add v1.1.15 to recognised versions</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/theqrl.org/commit/7a399a885303e30b71f36ec94b7c716418ad9e49"><strong>theqrl.org</strong></a>: Google fonts + Update blog</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/QRL/commit/130044cb5015ad21db49a3b6867f1327a071b680"><strong>QRL</strong></a>: Fixes and updated integration tests</li></ul><h3>QIP 009: Change mining algorithm to RandomX</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ojnxSRHZ041dgcsy_IFtyw.jpeg" /></figure><p>Four days ago, GitHub User <a href="https://github.com/doctor-gonzo">doctor-gonzo</a> submitted QIP 009: Change mining algorithm to RandomX. Here is what he had to say (via <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/pull/20">GitHub</a>):</p><blockquote>A mining algo change would go a long way towards re-vitalizing the mining community. Many people built rigs or pointed rigs at QRL initially but have been crushed by ASICs / FPGAs and no longer participate.</blockquote><p>As of this writing, 8 different individuals have weighed in on the QIP, including 3 QRL team members (<a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/pull/20">link</a> to comments). Mining (for those chains that utilize PoW) forms the bedrock of operationality for a blockchain, and any changes to it will almost certainly have a ripple effect. That also means that inaction can be as dangerous as action, as an untenable situation can have a corrosive effect on the health of a blockchain network. As such, it is important to take such discussions very seriously, and the more good-faith participants in the discussion, the better.</p><h3>Introducing Michael Strike</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*bo0FMUqghvvsUxA6ttL2Kw.jpeg" /><figcaption>Pictured: Michael Strike</figcaption></figure><p>Many of you already know Michael Strike (Discord user StrikeAttack) from his activity on the <a href="https://discord.gg/VR9kcs2">QRL Discord</a>. An active community member for more than a year now, over time Michael’s involvement with the project grew. Recently, we have asked him to join us on the community/advocacy side of QRL. He will help us continue to optimize and grow our efforts to help raise the profile of the project, as well as continuing to help set us apart within the crowded blockchain space.</p><p>Some words from Michael:</p><blockquote>It is with great excitement that I have accepted a role with QRL as a core team member. I’ve been involved with the project since before mainnet, and getting to know the community and core team members has been personally rewarding. While I will be wearing many hats in this role which will likely change over time, I can share a few ideas up front. First, I intend to aggressively, professionally, and tactfully reach out to people of influence, organizations, and government agencies in order to expedite community awareness of our project so that we will be more strategically positioned in the future. Second, I also believe that establishing a solid brand identity is critical to the future success of this project. Third, I plan to develop media content and look for strategic areas of process improvement that will streamline efficiency. I have a strong, vested, and passionate interest in the success of this project and am looking forward to contributing the best that I can. Thank you.</blockquote><p>Once again we would like to extend a heartfelt welcome to Michael from the entire QRL team and community — we are certain that he will be an excellent addition to QRL!</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/498/1*-JhzEhEYTcoG9SAF19ChZg.gif" /></figure><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=9a7aa79de773" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-11-5-11-11-9a7aa79de773">Last Week in QRL 11/5–11/11</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL 10/29–11/4]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-10-29-11-4-db9d2e3b5987?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/db9d2e3b5987</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[swap-space]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 20:33:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-11-04T20:33:17.589Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, QRL on SwapSpace, QRL Community Nomination Update</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*AEhGT4z5iu-TbbD1KChQCw.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>Last week marked the end of October and the beginning of November. Halloween has come and gone. At QRL, we have continued to work towards providing our users with more reasonable liquidity options. Additionally, we have been continuing to develop, iterate and progress our own internal projects. We have had some inquiries into our <a href="https://angel.co/company/theqrl/jobs">golang developer and UI/UX developer positions</a>, and some initial interest expressed in our research grants. We will hopefully have more news on that shortly, but for now, the best of the rest is below.</p><p>We have spent the week in part playing with multi-signature wallets on devnet, which we still hope to bring to testnet in a reasonable timeframe. It is worth reiterating that multisignature wallet functionality will allow for more varied uses for our wallet, and will help provide a bedrock of functionality for later second-layer application development.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*FwIeiNDdSUmyAgR9tzONKw.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/api.theqrl.org/commit/22589733e7417fea2e2717cee2b6c5eba68ed0c6"><strong>api.theqrl.org</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Fixes (<a href="https://github.com/theQRL/api.theqrl.org/pull/3">#3</a>)</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/js-api-bridge/commit/d8afed62ade219c6cd981fa77662f3ede42deadb"><strong>js-api-bridge</strong></a><strong>: </strong>TS -&gt; JS (babel) and a bit more…</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-cli/commit/fcc8f914c9bdcb534beaa59c1390641ca2c8086c"><strong>qrl-cli</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Adding descriptions to commands</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/commit/701fdc7350f2239e07310a7ec5af28b83ff4c5f5"><strong>qrl-wallet</strong></a><strong>: </strong>UX tweaks to wallet opening</li></ul><h3>QRL On SwapSpace</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*vbjYert7rA-ZI1UPjZuOUg.png" /></figure><p>QRL has been added to <a href="https://swapspace.co/">SwapSpace</a>! SwapSpace describes itself as, “a cryptocurrency exchange aggregator that will save you time.” As you can see in the above screenshot, using SwapSpace is easy; pick the digital asset to send in, pick what to receive, then enter in the address where you want to receive your funds. SwapSpace also has a handy <a href="https://swapspace.zendesk.com/hc/en-gb/articles/360009348540-Introduction">“How To” article</a> if you are unsure, as well as an <a href="https://swapspace.zendesk.com/hc/en-gb/sections/360001755039-FAQ">FAQ</a>.</p><h3>Community Nomination Update</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*UnmlJxDvSBsLOXxfMx9MPQ.png" /></figure><p>We will have the October QRL Community Nomination Update in a separate blog later this week.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=db9d2e3b5987" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-10-29-11-4-db9d2e3b5987">Last Week in QRL 10/29–11/4</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vinex + QRL Promotion]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/vinex-qrl-promotion-6cadae9f7b9e?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/6cadae9f7b9e</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[vinex-exchange]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[vinex]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[btc]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 15:20:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-11-02T06:01:16.194Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Vinex’s QRL Promotion</h3><p><em>You can earn extra QRL for depositing BTC and/or withdrawing QRL from Vinex</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ftcfjTDyy_PCEePf-4C5dA.png" /></figure><h3>Terms</h3><p><strong>Promotion Period</strong></p><ul><li>November 1st — December 1st</li></ul><p><strong>Promotion Pool</strong></p><ul><li>10,000 QRL</li></ul><p><strong>Details</strong></p><ul><li>Any user who deposits BTC to Vinex.exchange during the promotion period will get a <em>proportional </em>distributed share of 5,000 QRL, based on the amount of BTC deposited.</li><li>Accounts that have a QRL purchase order filled, and withdraw QRL to an external address during the promotion period, will get an <em>evenly </em>distributed share of 5,000 QRL.</li><li><a href="https://vinex.network/market/BTC_QRL">QRL-BTC</a> and <a href="https://vinex.network/market/USDT_QRL">QRL-USDT</a> markets on Vinex</li></ul><h3>How To Get Started</h3><ul><li>Go to Vinex and <a href="https://id.midasprotocol.com/register?client_id=ZPP2SyMeEGoeRNPaSxMasnhQ&amp;redirect_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fvinex.network%2Foauth%2Fcallback">set up an account</a></li><li>Have an external wallet ready for withdrawal via <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org/">Web Wallet</a> or <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/releases/tag/v1.2.0">Desktop Wallet</a></li></ul><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=6cadae9f7b9e" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/vinex-qrl-promotion-6cadae9f7b9e">Vinex + QRL Promotion</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL 10/22–10/28]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-10-22-10-28-bc6ee2aef86b?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/bc6ee2aef86b</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[upbit]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[grant-research]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[vinex]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 19:14:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-10-28T19:14:51.123Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Research Grants, New Exchange Listing, UpBit Update</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*u35SUx9jODupMG69nkwuQQ.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>As we approach Halloween, there has been a recent flurry of activity in the Quantum Resistant space. Not all weeks are created equal, and this week saw more activity than most. Externally, there was a large announcement that <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/23/20928294/google-quantum-supremacy-sycamore-computer-qubit-milestone">Google had confirmed its claims of Quantum Supremacy</a>. This luckily coincided with our intention to announce the launch of <a href="https://theqrl.org/research/grants/">our first batch of research grants</a>, and on Friday <a href="https://www.pr.com/press-release/797923">we did just that</a>; announcing that we were launching four research grants into the field of Lattice-based threshold cryptography.</p><p>Additionally, another podcast interview was recorded (look for that to drop in about a month). Internally, we released multi-signature wallets on devnet, which we hope to be able to bring to testnet in a reasonable timeframe. Multisignature functionality will allow for wider and more varied uses for our wallet, and will help provide more useful elements for later second-layer application development.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/511/1*MPxCNIsWHyBWOq3dGuhA0g.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/explorer-helpers/commit/ac088bfea6aea33a5883342ee84ee637ccb0905a"><strong>explorer-helpers</strong></a><strong>:</strong> Add support for multi_sig_create transaction type</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/theqrl.org/commit/78963970f17fed4e84315dfe083150a854c8053d"><strong>theqrl.org</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Add research grant</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/block-explorer/commit/3d197b7c1946d3700e0b0de7427e07729628c019"><strong>block-explorer</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Wallet address changed</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/wallet-helpers/commit/199f9e8b1cb59ae239d7984a34424f1bc6c17ce4"><strong>wallet-helpers</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Update handlebars version in development dependencies</li><li>Multi-signature wallets are now live on devnet! We hope to be rolling them out to the testnet as soon as it is ready.</li></ul><h3>QRL Research Grants</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/768/1*wIWG0qZhGrmTrRUqUY_W9g.jpeg" /></figure><p>As you can see on our <a href="https://theqrl.org/research/grants/">website</a>, we are now offering a Lattice-based threshold cryptography research grant with 4 positions. If you would like to apply for the research grant, please send all inquiries to hello@qrl.foundation. These grants represent an opportunity for QRL to help meaningfully advance not just the implementation of quantum resistant cryptography, but its exploration as well.</p><p>We recognize the role that we must play in this evolving niche of the blockchain world. As innovators on the cutting edge, it is incumbent upon us to help advance the technology both through supporting research, as well as through our own development efforts.</p><h3>New Exchange Listing — Vinex</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*21SQ2V05-0YalutBb4eeeQ.png" /></figure><p>As you possibly saw earlier today in our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/new-exchange-listing-vinex-9d0fda0fbd61">previous blog</a>, QRL is now listed on <a href="https://vinex.network/">Vinex </a>on the <a href="https://vinex.network/market/BTC_QRL">QRL/BTC</a> and <a href="https://vinex.network/market/USDT_QRL">QRL/USDT</a> pairings. Vinex is a Singapore-based exchange, primarily targeted at the Vietnamese market, but also targeted at the entire ASEAN (Association of Southeast Asian Nations) region. It also marks the first exchange to list a QRL/USDT pairing.</p><h3>Upbit Update</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/500/1*O1oJHaSTGlljxIabORBpKw.jpeg" /></figure><p>Today, Upbit <a href="https://sg.upbit.com/service_center/notice?id=2284">released a notice</a> of 20 BTC pairings that would be re-enabled on October 29th. Included in that list is QRL/BTC. Upbit also released the following caveats in regards to the 20 re-opening pairings:</p><ul><li>For safe trading and accurate market information, ask orders will not be available for initial 5 minutes.</li><li>Also, ask orders lower than 10% from the reference price will not be available.</li><li>Reference price refers to 1) closing price on SGD market or 2) closing price on Bittrex, previous day.</li><li>Market price could be volatile for initial period from listing. Please be careful when trading.</li></ul><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=bc6ee2aef86b" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-10-22-10-28-bc6ee2aef86b">Last Week in QRL 10/22–10/28</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Exchange Listing — Vinex]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/new-exchange-listing-vinex-9d0fda0fbd61?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/9d0fda0fbd61</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[digital-assets-exchange]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[vinex]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 18:21:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-10-28T18:21:06.079Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>New Exchange Listing — Vinex</h3><p><em>QRL is now trading on Vinex against BTC and USDT</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*21SQ2V05-0YalutBb4eeeQ.png" /></figure><h3>What is Vinex?</h3><p>Vinex is a digital assets exchange based in Singapore. It is self-described as, “One of the 3 pillars of Midas Ecosystem: Wallet — Exchange — Fund.” <a href="https://support.vinex.network/hc/en-us/articles/360022383431-Overview-of-Vinex-Network-Crypto-Exchange">The blog goes on to say</a> that Vinex is a member of the Singapore Fintech Association, and the Digital Exchanges Association of Singapore. You can read more about it in <a href="https://support.vinex.network/hc/en-us/articles/360022383431-Overview-of-Vinex-Network-Crypto-Exchange">their own words</a>.</p><p>As you can see from their own <a href="https://support.vinex.network/hc/en-us/articles/360034567931-Quantum-Resistant-Ledger-QRL-is-now-listed-on-Vinex">blog post</a> earlier today, QRL will be available to be traded on the <a href="https://vinex.network/market/BTC_QRL">QRL/BTC</a> and <a href="https://vinex.network/market/USDT_QRL">QRL/USDT</a> pairs. Currently, both the <a href="https://vinex.network/market/BTC_QRL">QRL/BTC</a> and <a href="https://vinex.network/market/USDT_QRL">QRL/USDT</a> pairs are live — you can check it out <a href="https://vinex.network/market/BTC_QRL">here</a>.</p><h3>How Do I Access QRL On Vinex?</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/400/1*kq033gToZQQqhMtaSiWxNw.jpeg" /></figure><p>Vinex is an exchange that is focused on the Asia/Pacific region, particularly Vietnam. With over 30 digital assets on its platform, most available against three base pairs (BTC, ETH, USDT), Vinex has been looking to expand their offerings to customers in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Association_of_Southeast_Asian_Nations">ASEAN </a>(Association of Southeast Asian Nations) region.</p><p>To access QRL on Vinex, you will first need to <a href="https://id.midasprotocol.com/register?client_id=ZPP2SyMeEGoeRNPaSxMasnhQ&amp;redirect_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fvinex.network%2Foauth%2Fcallback">make an account on Vinex</a>. After making the account, you will be able to deposit, withdraw, and trade QRL on their <a href="https://vinex.network/market/BTC_QRL">markets</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=9d0fda0fbd61" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/new-exchange-listing-vinex-9d0fda0fbd61">New Exchange Listing — Vinex</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL October 15–21]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-october-15-21-ac2c1fb030aa?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/ac2c1fb030aa</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[htc]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 20:07:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-10-21T20:07:27.496Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Update, Community Nomination</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*sAMrQq5vZmDcgcRLyDYevg.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>We are now into the penultimate week of October. In blockchain news, you can now get a <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/you-can-now-get-a-masters-in-blockchain-from-a-school-in-where-else-malta">Master’s Degree in blockchain</a> from the <a href="https://www.um.edu.mt/dlt/masters">University of Malta</a>. It is pretty amazing to see how a technology that is barely over a decade old is already beginning to be integrated into academia. In technology, HTC has claimed to have developed the first <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/htcs-latest-blockchain-phone-can-run-a-full-bitcoin-node">smartphone to be able to run a full bitcoin node</a>, the Exodus 1s, allowing it to propagate transactions and blocks anywhere. Unveiling the device Saturday at the Lightning Conference in Berlin, the company claimed the new product is <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/10/19/htc-launches-exodus-1s-a-cheaper-version-of-its-blockchain-smartphone.html">going to be priced at $244</a>, or about 1/3 its predecessor, the Exodus 1.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*dP2N4vmnuJkG-n1bPKVeYg.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>validate-qrl-address:</strong> Add test cases for short addresses and bug fix</li><li><strong>theqrl.org:</strong> Images for markets</li><li><strong>block-explorer: </strong>Wallet address changed</li></ul><h3>September Community Nomination</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*s9yZ6J6XjxH863P5ThQuWA.png" /></figure><p>September’s QRL Community Nomination goes to Discord user ‘smith’, who has been an active and positive part of The QRL Contributors. He had this to say about how he found QRL and why he joined the community:</p><blockquote>Personally I am a security and privacy minded person and that has carried over to the crypto world. I started getting interested in crypto when Bitcoin was the cryptocurrency world, and I have watched the altcoins markets develop. There has been some forward thinking people in this space that considered the possibility that Quantum Computers might be a threat to cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin and that naturally got me interested in looking for good quality projects that where working to address that problem which lead me to QRL. I am a fan of the project and the community and hope to see it go from strength to strength.</blockquote><p>If you know someone that’s contributed to the QRL ecosystem who you’d like to nominate, you can do so by going to <a href="https://discord.gg/VR9kcs2">The QRL Discord</a> and nominating in the #butler channel.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=ac2c1fb030aa" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-october-15-21-ac2c1fb030aa">Last Week in QRL October 15–21</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL October 8 -14]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-october-8-14-703c0a887d21?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/703c0a887d21</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 17:08:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-10-14T17:08:05.974Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Development Updates, Community Updates</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ZoUC-E78qJmoVBDgTETRQA.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>As we enter the 3rd week of October, blockchain has been in the wider public news again. On the one hand, we have <a href="https://www.coindesk.com/bank-of-america-is-now-hiring-in-blockchain-not-just-filing-patents">Bank of America hiring for blockchain</a> positions, another signal that the banking industry is continuing to recognize how blockchain is going to be a growing part of the global financial system. On the other hand, we have the highest-profile attempt (so far) by a private corporation to bring about their own cryptocurrency, Facebook’s Libra, have <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/10/11/ebay-drops-out-of-facebook-libra-cryptocurrency-one-week-after-paypal.html">coalition members dropping out</a>, from eBay to Visa to Stripe.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*qW547AZ7pLjQz-NRSYPXJQ.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>qrllib: </strong>Add Dilithium+Kyber to webAssembly build</li><li><strong>wallet-helpers:</strong> Add checkWeightsAndThreshold function + tests</li><li><strong>qrl-cli: </strong>Adding descriptions to commands</li></ul><h3>Community</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*zYORzC9qipuIq24b4c9Aug.png" /></figure><p>Recently, Binance <a href="https://twitter.com/binance/status/1183005257703362560">announced in a tweet</a> that they were opening round 2 of the Binance Community Coin Vote. They encouraged community members to tag and retweet their favorite projects in replies to the tweet, including a link to the Binance Community Coin Vote Application Form in the tweet.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/500/1*nkKg_KPDfKKIIwPEexiewA.gif" /><figcaption>Gif included by Binance in their tweet</figcaption></figure><p>Binance has long been a topic of discussion within our community, with many users seeing the highest-profile digital assets exchange on the planet as the premiere avenue for liquidity.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=703c0a887d21" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-october-8-14-703c0a887d21">Last Week in QRL October 8 -14</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL September 1–7]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-1-7-44c65be4f4b2?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/44c65be4f4b2</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain-jobs]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 18:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-10-07T18:47:00.536Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL October 1–7</h3><p><em>Development Updates, Job Opening for Golang and UI/UX</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*qwNSvuGWPEWevyGFOKCJ8g.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>We are now into the final quarter of 2019. Recently, quantum computing has been back in the news in a bigger way, with <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-02935-4">reports of increased levels of private investment in space</a>, as well as continued attention being paid by governments. We are also continuing to post job openings (more on this below), as we look to strategically grow the team ahead of our next development objectives. Finally, we will have the September Community Nomination recipient sometime later this week or next week.</p><h3>Development</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*fJuyiylFc6FOZsiBPJg5-w.jpeg" /></figure><ul><li><strong>qrl-wallet:</strong> UX tweaks to wallet opening</li><li><strong>theqrl.org:</strong> Remove unnecessary clutter from splash</li><li><strong>block-explorer: </strong>Wallet address changed</li></ul><h3>Call for Golang Developer, UI/UX Designer</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*0AEyNpQM3HLQsrlz2jBd5A.jpeg" /></figure><p>As we have mentioned elsewhere, QRL is hiring three individuals for two specific positions (we are also separately searching for cryptographers interested in threshold lattice cryptography, for a grant we are developing) — UX/UI Designer, and Golang Developer(x2). You can see these <a href="https://angel.co/company/theqrl/jobs">job postings on angel.co</a>. We have received some interesting applications already, but want to cast as wide a net as possible to maximize the likelihood of finding the ideal candidate.</p><h4>Golang Developer</h4><p>From the <a href="https://angel.co/company/theqrl/jobs/638007-golang-developer">angel.co job posting</a>:</p><blockquote>If you’re interested but don’t fit every specification, don’t let that shy you away, it is a wish-list after all.</blockquote><blockquote>What you will do:<br>- Write industrial grade open source code that will be the backbone of a quantum resistant network.<br>- Work with a small, but growing team of talented developers and cryptography experts.<br>- Occasionally interact with the community in a polite and conductive manner.</blockquote><blockquote>What we wish you to be:<br>- You have a graduate degree or higher in computer science or affiliated field.<br>- You have written high-performance and concurrent applications.<br>- You are part of the QRL Community.<br>- You have p2p implementation experience.<br>- You are familiar with cryptography.<br>- You have a genuine desire to ensure all code is tested through writing unit and integration tests</blockquote><blockquote>Compensation<br>- Competitive based on capability and experience</blockquote><h4>UI/UX Designer</h4><p>From the <a href="https://angel.co/company/theqrl/jobs/307891-ux-ui-designer">angel.co job posting</a>:</p><blockquote>We are looking for someone to:<br>- Build a consistent brand identity and pleasurable user experience<br>- Explore ideas to improve the usability to our tools and apps<br>- Build upon corporate identity/image, color schemes, logo, layouts, visual identity</blockquote><blockquote>Your qualifications:<br>- BSc. degree in design/fine arts, related fields or experience in the area<br>- Minimum of 3yrs experience<br>- Experience in HTML/CSS, mobile applications<br>- Ideally experience in mobile hybrid frameworks such as Ionic, Framework7, etc.<br>- Previous experience with Android/iOS development.<br>- Some experience in software development is a plus.<br>- Critical thinking and able to work independently<br>- We appreciate if you can provide a portfolio of previous work.<br>- Language: English is critical</blockquote><blockquote>We offer:</blockquote><blockquote>- You will be a freelance contributor working remotely<br>- Very international team distributed around the world.<br>- Remote work and very flexible working times.<br>- Open source development, most of your work will be publicly recognized.<br>- We expect massive growth in the short/medium term.<br>- As an open source cryptocurrency project, you will receive payment in the cryptocurrency of your choice.</blockquote><h3>Community Nomination — September</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*UnmlJxDvSBsLOXxfMx9MPQ.png" /></figure><p>We do not yet have the response ready from the QRL Community Nomination recipient for September. We will probably have that later this week or early next week.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=44c65be4f4b2" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-1-7-44c65be4f4b2">Last Week in QRL September 1–7</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL: September 24th —  30th]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-24th-30th-e09ccd5b88fa?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/e09ccd5b88fa</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptography]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 04:16:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-10-01T04:16:22.064Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Last Week in QRL: September 24th — 30th</h3><h4>Quantum supremacy coverage, development updates, and a call for cryptographers for grant(s) in threshold lattice cryptography.</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/994/1*id4o3CQ7l4MRE9IlkXQ0Og.png" /></figure><p>There’s been a flurry of activity since NASA temporarily dropped a paper indicating of google reportedly achieving quantum supremacy.</p><p>From that we responded with a <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/quantum-supremacy-and-the-case-for-quantum-security-today-in-blockchain-390fe55daab5">piece reasserting our position that it’s not a matter of if but when quantum computers pose a threat, and that blockchains should be either already prepared or be preparing for a post-quantum world</a>.</p><p>This was a followup article to the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/no-ibms-quantum-computer-won-t-break-bitcoin-but-we-should-be-prepared-for-one-that-can-cc3e178ebff0">previous one</a> when IBM announced a commercial quantum computer earlier this year in January.</p><p>If you’d like to know more about google’s achievement specifically, the best source is a blog from Scott Aaronson, who does a great job at breaking it down understandably for a high-school level audience. The blog is aptly called “<a href="https://www.scottaaronson.com/blog/?p=4317">Scott’s Supreme Quantum Supremacy FAQ!</a>”.</p><h3>Some coverage</h3><p>Needless to say, we’ve had some coverage, including a latest one where Coindesk and Adam Koltun connected in an article “<a href="https://www.coindesk.com/what-googles-quantum-supremacy-means-for-the-future-of-cryptocurrency">What Google’s ‘Quantum Supremacy’ Means for the Future of Cryptocurrency</a>”</p><p><strong>Other mentions include</strong></p><ul><li><a href="https://en.ethereumworldnews.com/google-quantum-supremacy-bitcoin/">Google Achieves “Quantum Supremacy”; is Bitcoin (BTC) Threatened?</a><br>- EthereumWorldNews</li><li><a href="https://decrypt.co/9642/what-google-quantum-computer-means-for-bitcoin">What Google’s quantum computer means for Bitcoin</a><br>- Decrypt</li><li><a href="https://cryptodaily.co.uk/2019/09/how-will-blockchains-battle-quantum-computing">How Will Blockchains Battle Quantum Computing</a><br>- Crypto Daily</li><li><a href="https://www.altcoinbuzz.io/crypto-news/blockchain-technology/does-google-threaten-cryptocurrencies/">Does Google Threaten Cryptocurrencies?</a><br>- Altcoin Buzz</li></ul><h3>Development updates</h3><p>Work continues to happen for the upcoming fork, (more on that in another blog). Outside of that there’s some small updates such as one to the wallet.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/643/1*qLb955qGcfDz-yRNfKV6Ig.gif" /></figure><p>It was reported from discord user Strike Attack that the wallet seed can be snatched from eavesdropping (think security cameras). This was quickly patched by JP Lomas in 24 hours with the current functionality shown in the above animated image.</p><h3>Call for cryptographers</h3><p>As part of our Foundations research arm, we’re putting out a call for cryptographers for a grant in threshold lattice cryptography.</p><p>More details will be released on that shortly.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=e09ccd5b88fa" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-september-24th-30th-e09ccd5b88fa">Last Week in QRL: September 24th —  30th</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[QRL Now Listed on VCC Exchange]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-now-listed-on-vcc-exchange-5c6d369ac4ab?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/5c6d369ac4ab</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[vcc-exchange]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 15:46:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-09-27T15:46:42.811Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>QRL is now trading on VCC Exchange, a Bittrex partner</h4><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*_249rM2XPPQeKwSYj4hfeQ.png" /></figure><p><a href="https://vcc.exchange/">VCC Exchange</a> is a Singapore/Vietnam-based digital asset exchange focusing on blockchain who partnered with Bittrex in May of 2019 who continues to leverage its technology to offer “<a href="https://bittrex.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360028035472-VCC-Exchange-Launches-Digital-Asset-Trading-Platform-Powered-by-Bittrex-in-Vietnam-">Vietnam a secure, reliable and advanced trading experience</a>”</p><p>From Tung Dao from VCC Exchange:</p><blockquote>We are honored to launch our platform with the support of an established industry player like Bittrex. They are an ideal partner for us as we focus on compliance and transparency in the Vietnamese blockchain industry</blockquote><p>Those at VCC Exchange are cryptocurrency users too, and aim to provide a credible and transparent exchange users can actually trust and use. Their core competencies go beyond just that of being an exchange however, and includes blockchain startup crowdfunding, including IEO and incubation programs.</p><h3>Access</h3><p>Our <a href="https://vcc.exchange/exchange/basic?currency=btc&amp;coin=qrl">QRL/BTC market</a> can be accessed by creating an account and heading to our exchange page: <a href="https://vcc.exchange/exchange/basic?currency=btc&amp;coin=qrl">https://vcc.exchange/exchange/basic?currency=btc&amp;coin=qrl</a></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*hNkr6gxoGk7FYW9HhjioAQ.png" /></figure><h4>Mobile</h4><p>Other platforms for trading include iOS and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.vccexchange">Android</a> for trading on the go.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1002/1*scn0fRfF4vAiu7Z3L71z-g.png" /><figcaption>Image taken from VCC Exchange website homepage</figcaption></figure><h4>Final thoughts</h4><p>We are always wanting to expand our availability, whether that’s making cryptocurrency more usable, more developer friendly, or more otherwise accessible to those from around the world from all walks of life.</p><p>We’re happy to have VCC Exchange as part of this expansion of availability.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=5c6d369ac4ab" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-now-listed-on-vcc-exchange-5c6d369ac4ab">QRL Now Listed on VCC Exchange</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>