<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Cryptography with longevity. A post-quantum secure blockchain featuring a stateful signature scheme and unparalleled security. - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 06:44:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/the-quantum-resistant-ledger" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reflecting on Discover Blockchains Houston]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-discover-blockchains-houston-f22bc37655e?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/f22bc37655e</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[discover-blockchains]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 18:05:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-09-21T18:05:07.072Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR- Was in Houston over the weekend to speak at the Discover Blockchains Conference.</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/900/1*Ww9mirQyHDSLhKN4SyiYPQ.jpeg" /></figure><p>Over the weekend, I had the opportunity to fly to Houston, Texas to speak at the <a href="https://discoverblockchains.com/">Discover Blockchains Conference</a> — which is a series of conferences that are somewhat more educational in nature than many of the other conferences I have attended so far this year. One of the main points of departure was that there was no exhibition hall or booths. It was purely stages and seats, and was wholly dedicated to the content being put on (with some nice complimentary refreshments as well).</p><p>The speakers and panels were divided into two tracks, and generally the subject matter of any two speakers/panels that were appearing at the same time were distinct enough that there was not a high likelihood of audiences facing tough choices. One example of this was my talk, which was at the same time as a talk about the pharmaceutical industry and blockchain technology, which would leave it unlikely that someone would feel torn about which to attend.</p><p>The lack of an exhibition hall or floor made for a much more compact conference. Functionally, this created a much more relaxed atmosphere, and also helped to establish a pattern whereby people would watch speakers, then take breaks at the refreshments station and chat. It also made it easy, as a speaker, to continue the conversation after one was done. Due to some technical difficulties at the start of my presentation (only ate up a few minutes, thankfully), I was not able to have the Q&amp;A portion at the end. However, I was able to ask any interested parties to meet me by the refreshments table, and indeed a small group of 6–10 people and I continued the conversation about quantum computing and blockchain technology for longer than my talk had been!</p><p>Generally, it seemed like there was a decent interest level in what I had to say. There were people taking pictures of various slides, and definitely a large number of attentive listeners in the audience (you can always tell when people are checked out, the heads go down and the phones come out), which, as a speaker, is always the goal.</p><p>This was a conference that tried to keep its daytime agenda focused on content, and had a specific networking event at the end of the day for some light libations and the usual exchanging of business cards and contact info. While I do not necessarily think this would be the best way to run <em>all</em> blockchain conferences, I did really appreciate it as a change-of-pace from some of the more Expo-style conferences I have attended previously.</p><p>From what I heard from some speakers who had presented at previous Discover Blockchains conferences, the one in Houston had a reasonably high draw, and perhaps unsurprisingly, had (I was told) somewhat more new faces to the scene than in previous locations, like Seattle.</p><p>Discover Blockchains did a good job of inviting a broad list of speakers, representing different elements of the blockchain/cryptocurrency industry. You had people representing projects, like me, as well as more distinctly focused people — like traders, GPU miners, and IoT specialists. While there was some breaking down into groups along those lines at the networking event, I was pleasantly surprised at the cross-pollination I both witnessed and directly experienced.</p><p>Overall, it was a pleasant and productive experience that was also in many ways distinct from the other conferences I have attended this year. I think that the price depression still being seen throughout the market at large has had a net effect of lowering some of the intensity of the moment, allowing some of the less-profit-focused ideas to be heard. To my mind, that is a good thing.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=f22bc37655e" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-discover-blockchains-houston-f22bc37655e">Reflecting on Discover Blockchains Houston</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mainnet v1.1.5 is released]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/mainnet-v1-1-5-is-released-2db14b103332?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/2db14b103332</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[bech32]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[silicon]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[post-quantum]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Peter Waterland]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 14:43:54 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-09-14T14:58:20.649Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a minor iterative update including the following changes:</p><ul><li>WalletDaemon is now allowed to create XMSS trees with minimum tree height of 6 (2⁶ signature capacity)</li><li>Master/slave XMSS reserved OTS reduced from 20 to 5</li><li>Improved error handling &amp; logging</li><li>WalletAPI: Changed balance data type from UInt64 to String</li><li>WalletAPI: Added IsValidAddress &amp; GetNodeInfo</li></ul><h3>‘It’s alive!’</h3><p>The QRL network is alive and well despite several attempts to DDOS the network — one of which being fairly sophisticated using malformed transactions. We are thankful for some early real-world testing outside of our two comprehensive audits.</p><p>Speaking of audits I am pleased to report our X-41 audit which focused upon our very special post-quantum cryptography XMSS (and various implementations across our ecosystem — node, webwallet, Ledger) has completed. We will publish the report as a community resource on <em>github</em> and discuss the audit in detail in an upcoming blog.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/790/1*Ica6A6at2vdRduGQqyw6pw.png" /></figure><p>With 100k blocks firmly in the rear view mirror we have a blog coming from @Jack detailing some interesting usage statistics gleaned from the chain thus far — additionally we will be expanding the <a href="http://explorer.theqrl.org">explorer</a> to demonstrate some realtime statistics of the chain as it grows in the future (including charts).</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/264/1*-SHk3JbjRHvOBABhO-sYaQ.png" /><figcaption>when exch$@%#!!!</figcaption></figure><p>Some things in a project like the QRL are outside our control and although that can seem like inactivity to those outside the team discussion forum, keen observers of <em>github</em> can see very specific changes being made to areas like our <em>walletd</em> which track actual progress in this regard.</p><p>Integrating weird, stateful and unique pq-crypto like the QRL in a commercial system is not quite as straightforward as it appears compared with a casual user experience with the <a href="http://wallet.theqrl.org"><em>webwallet</em></a>.</p><h3>BECH32 addresses</h3><p>Andrew has finished integrating BECH32 addresses into the QRL. This means that in our next major hard fork release of the QRL will support both existing Q-addresses and a shorter, safer address B32 format which contains advanced error correction functionality.</p><p>A comparison between an existing Q-hexstring address and its’ q-bech32 counterpart is below:</p><pre>Q010500c0183a30c9170c8daf0a25d91f2102c49994a04e81a18286c1e345121f33037301c70c38</pre><pre>q1qyzspsqc8gcvj9cv3khs5fweruss93yejjsyaqdps2rvrc69zg0nxqmnxcx5p5</pre><p>More about BECH32 and why it is great can be read <a href="https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0173.mediawiki">here</a>.</p><h3>Silicon</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*9NiPR_KSXt0Mtc7c7UhxtQ.png" /></figure><p>The remainder of the blog will focus upon the first item on our roadmap to find attention — our smart address platform denoted internally as ‘project silicon’.</p><p>As the name suggests, this will add smart addresses with programmable logic capability to the QRL, a functionality more widely known as smart contracts on other platforms such as ethereum or eos.</p><p>See our draft QIP <em>here</em> for more technical details.</p><p>What is planned is a turing-incomplete highly limited set of logic instructions to allow programmed behaviours to be added to new QRL contract addresses without compromising security.</p><p>We aim to add functionality such as:</p><ol><li><strong>escrow payments</strong></li><li><strong>recurring payment schedules</strong></li><li><strong>atomic interchain swaps</strong></li><li><strong>decentralised automated multiple-signatory accounts</strong></li><li><strong>account logic based upon temporal events</strong></li><li><strong>account behaviour based upon oracle addresses</strong></li></ol><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/500/1*wY71qxSuzP_Uq5tVDqvgKw.jpeg" /></figure><p>Our ultimate aim is to move the foundation QRL funds into a multiple signatory account controlled by trustees including the community to completely decentralise project funding for development and research goals in the future.</p><h3>Details, details, details?</h3><p>A new transaction subtype ‘<em>contract</em>’ will be added to the platform.</p><p>This will contain compiled logic-code in <em>bytecode</em> form and once a contract transaction is confirmed in the chain a new contract address is duly created.</p><p>QRL contracts are simple and deliberately designed to be so.</p><p>An example contract just has two parts: declarations of variables which the contract may access, and, the nuts and bolts — the logic-code of the contract.</p><pre>{variable_declarations} {logic-code}</pre><p>Contracts are written in ‘modified python with braces’ — with a tiny instruction set such as: if, then, for, send, send_message, destroy and several cryptographic instructions required for cross-chain atomic swaps.</p><p>It is designed to be readable and easy to write or learn.</p><p>Each contract has access to a sandboxed state machine and namespace. State is frozen to reduce the attack surface.</p><h3>Logic-code — rules or hooks</h3><p>Code in a QRL contract address must either be a ‘rule’ or a ‘hook’.</p><p>A ‘rule’ is logic-code which is executed when a contract-specific transaction event occurs i.e. a transaction is received by the contract address.</p><p>A ‘hook’ is logic-code which is executed at the point of instantiation to set events to occur at a future time, say a block-height, or the nearest unixtime to a block-header timestamp.</p><p>An example contract with a rule would be:</p><pre>{}</pre><pre>{</pre><pre>rule { </pre><pre>if (address.owner == transaction.address) then {destroy} </pre><pre>}</pre><p>In this rather useless contract (with no variable declarations at all), if a transaction is received from the QRL account which created the contract, then the contract address code is deactivated.</p><p>An example hook statement would be something like this:</p><pre>hook { if (chain.blockheight ≥ 100000) then {send (address.owner, address.balance-0.001, 0.001)}</pre><pre>}</pre><p>This would return the entire contract_address balance (less 0.001 fee) to the original contract creator at block-height 100k.</p><h3>Recurring payments</h3><p>What about something more complicated? A common problem with cryptocurrency is setting payments to occur in a planned fashion.</p><p>A set of recurring payments can easily be created by simply adding a series of ‘hook’ statements to a contract address. A get out clause can also be added with a ‘rule’. i.e.</p><pre>// variable declaration first<br>{addresses=[payment_address1]}<br>// logic-code to make two payments at specific block heights</pre><pre>{ <br>hook { if (chain.blockheight==40000) then {send (addresses[0], amount=220, fee=0.0001)}<br>}<br>hook { if (chain.blockheight==60000) then {send (addresses[0], amount=220, fee=0.0001)}<br>}</pre><pre>rule { if (transaction.type == message) and (transaction.address==address.owner) then {send (address.owner, address.balance-0.001, 0.001)}<br>}</pre><pre>}</pre><p>In this contract, two payments are planned at block-height 40k and 60k for 220 QRL. If a transaction of subtype ‘message’ is received from the contract creator address then all funds are returned (NB. currently ‘message’ transactions are broadcast without a recipient.)</p><h3>Multiple signatories</h3><p>Example of decentralised logic of a smart address using multiple signatories — in this case funds sent to this address are sent to another address if all three signatories have sent a specified message.</p><pre>// variable declaration<br>{<br>addresses=[trustee_one, trustee_two, trustee_three, destination_address]<br>x=False<br>y=False<br>z=False<br>}<br>// contract logic-code<br>{<br>rule {<br>for (t in address.transactions){<br> if (t.address == addresses[0].address)and (t.message == ‘MOVEALLFUNDS’) then {x=True}<br> if (t.address == addresses[1].address)and(t.message == ‘MOVEALLFUNDS’) then {y=True}<br> if (t.address == addresses[2].address) and (t.message == ‘MOVEALLFUNDS’) then {z=True}<br> }<br>if (x==True)and(y==True)and(z==True) then {send (addresses[3].address, address.balance-0.001, fee=0.001)}<br>}<br>}</pre><p>It can be seen that using message transactions from the owner or specified address in <em>addresses, </em>contract code may be activated or deactivated easily enough.</p><h3>Dead man’s switch</h3><p>Another example would be a dead man’s switch contract. In this scenario if a contract address specific event does not occur by a given time then the contract performs an action.</p><pre>// declarations<br>{addresses=[emergency_address]}</pre><pre>// logic-code<br>{</pre><pre>hook {</pre><pre>if (chain.blockheight==200000) and (transaction==False) then {send(addresses[0],amount=balance-0.001,fee=0.001)}</pre><pre>}</pre><p>In this case if the contract does not receive <em>any</em> transaction before blockheight 200k all funds are sent to the <em>emergency_address</em>. This could be further modified to a recurring check for a transaction to occur from a specific address or with a specific message content within the last x blocks of a given blockheight(s) activation.</p><p>We forsee integrating contract transactions into the node, then building out our tools section of the webwallet to allow easy GUI-based off the shelf contract formation from a user-address, allowing functionality like dead man’s switch, recurring payments, multiple signatory setups, atomic swaps, etc.</p><h3>Timeline</h3><p>We have begun to specify project silicon in our first QIP although there will undoubtedly be wide ranging changes as we grow the concept and begin to build tools and experiment on a new dedicated devnet. We hope to hard fork the network to implement silicon by early 2019, pending testing and a further third party audit.</p><p>We will make public our new code repositories in the coming days to allow the community to get involved and inspect progress realtime.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=2db14b103332" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/mainnet-v1-1-5-is-released-2db14b103332">Mainnet v1.1.5 is released</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Discover Blockchains Conference Next Week!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/discover-blockchains-conference-next-week-dab6e0b8651b?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/dab6e0b8651b</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[discover-blockchains]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-computing]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 17:14:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-09-06T17:14:07.676Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR — Who/What/Where/When/Why of Discover Blockchains Conference</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*WBRSkJxuWD8UlCnUlQ7PQQ.png" /></figure><h3>Who</h3><p>Discover Blockchains 2018 will be attended by:</p><ul><li>Adam: Lead Business Strategist</li></ul><h3>What</h3><p>Discover Blockchains is a conference that is, like the name implies, meant to introduce new people to the blockchain industry, as well as show people already interested in blockchain something they have not seen before. I will have an <a href="https://discoverblockchains.com/agenda/#agenda">opportunity to speak</a> at the conference, and I will try to tailor my talk (as I always do) to the particular audience in attendance.</p><p>Given how often I still meet people when giving talks who come up to me afterwards to tell me that they did not know quantum computing was even possible, let alone being actively developed, I think I will be able to introduce the crowd to some new ideas. QRL is not sponsoring this conference so if you are planning to attend, we will not have a booth.</p><h3>Where</h3><p><a href="https://www.hyatt.com/en-US/hotel/texas/hyatt-regency-houston/hourh">Hyatt Regency Houston, TX</a></p><h3>When</h3><p>September 16, 2018</p><p>My talk will be at 3:00pm in the Imperial East room</p><h3>Why</h3><p>As I have stated in such blogs previously, one of the nice things about blockchain conferences is that they are not all the same. To be blunt, were this conference not in the United States, I doubt I would have been able to attend. However, given that adoption and education are still two of the largest barriers facing cryptocurrency in general, and QRL in particular, I am very glad to be able to take this opportunity to hopefully educate the audience about not only quantum computing and blockchain, but what QRL is doing about it.</p><p>Secondarily, it is nice to not have to lose days of travel to attend a conference, as by the end of my Spring gauntlet of speaking engagements, I realized I had lost altogether too much time in airports, on airplanes, and recovering from those two experiences.</p><p>As always, if you will be in attendance and would like to meet up for a chat, feel free to message me on Discord, Twitter, or send me an email.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=dab6e0b8651b" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/discover-blockchains-conference-next-week-dab6e0b8651b">Discover Blockchains Conference Next Week!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[x41 d-sec audit]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/x41-d-sec-audit-79d5243f0874?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/79d5243f0874</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 22:10:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-08-27T22:10:26.896Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Project Update</h4><p><em>TLDR — x41 D-Sec audit has commenced, mobile wallet updates, wallet API improvements, OTC market opens, tipbots, and basic concepts videos</em></p><p>Our team is global, with members currently residing in The United States of America, Canada, United Kingdom, Australia, and India. There’s usually one person alive <em>and</em> awake every hour of the day, working on improving every aspect of this project.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/392/1*EhOqRFAO3PkLna9YzujHWg.png" /></figure><h4>x41 D-Sec — Our second Auditor after Red4Sec</h4><p>A foundational part of QRL is a sustained commitment to enterprise grade security and bringing on third party auditors.</p><p>Keeping in-line with this commitment, starting last <em>Monday</em>, the <a href="https://www.x41-dsec.de/">x41 D-Sec</a> team has begun an audit in earnest and is currently boring into our QRL code. This audit is shorter than our last at 2–3 weeks and covers the cryptography portion (ie XMSS) of our codebase, including Ledger code, and its implementation.</p><p>To give an idea of x41’s capabilities, some recent vulnerabilities discovered by x41 D-Sec involve <a href="https://www.x41-dsec.de/lab/blog/smartcards/">smartcards</a>, <a href="https://www.x41-dsec.de/lab/advisories/x41-2017-006-psftpd/">PSFTPd</a>, <a href="https://www.x41-dsec.de/lab/blog/kernel_userspace/">Kernal Fuzzing in Userspace,</a> and <a href="https://www.x41-dsec.de/lab/advisories/">more</a>.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/592/1*BhOu6u5wiJlvbH0cAEzHNQ.gif" /></figure><h4>Mobile Wallet Views</h4><p>Recently we spoke about the core backend of the mobile wallet being complete and it’s just working on the views to ensure a slick experience.</p><p>Thus far the main view and backup view is complete, with only a few more key views remaining.</p><p>As a reminder, there will be both iOS and Android versions.</p><p>Like everything at QRL, this is under an MIT license and can be found on <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet">Github</a>.</p><h4>Wallet Daemon API</h4><p>Further improvements have been made to our Wallet Daemon API which automates things like Slave Transactions so that exchanges can more easily integrate QRL.</p><h4>OTC Market on Discord Opens</h4><p>Until our mainnet coin is listed on an exchange, we have opened an OTC (Over the Counter) trading channel with the kind assistance of our Butler.</p><p>It should be emphasized that doing <em>any</em> OTC trading is at your own risk, however, much of this can be mitigated by selecting a trustworthy escrow (third party to hold both parties funds and release them upon agreement).</p><p>If you would like to take part in trading your Quanta, you can <a href="https://discord.gg/vqCwVqH">join</a> and do so today.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/536/1*UVxlRS2HOdrllPDYb0OwnQ.png" /></figure><h4>More Improvements</h4><p><strong>Tipbots and Faucets</strong></p><p>Work is being initiated on our tipbot and faucet. It’s still in the very early stages so if you have seen a faucet or tipbot that you like, let us know on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/qrl">Reddit</a> or <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">Discord</a>.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/728/1*SpqBxGHiRkKsoCBRNoCfIw.png" /></figure><p><strong>Basic Concepts Videos</strong></p><p>Basics concepts videos would explain certain aspects of QRL to everyday folks. We have established a few that people would be interested in.</p><ul><li>Sending coins to QRL wallet</li><li>Making a wallet</li><li>CLI wallet use: sending / balance / etc</li><li>Explorer explanation</li><li>OTS Keys</li><li>Token use</li></ul><p>What would you like to see first? Have a different suggestion for a Basic Concepts video, let us know on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/qrl">Reddit</a> or <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">Discord</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=79d5243f0874" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/x41-d-sec-audit-79d5243f0874">x41 d-sec audit</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Go-QRL]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/go-qrl-46186f8635c5?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/46186f8635c5</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[x41]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[golang]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[security-audit]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 17:17:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-08-20T17:17:05.683Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4>Project Update</h4><p><em>TLDR — Go-QRL Node repo public, Project Carbon, incremental wallet update to v1.0.2, and Developer Meeting Summaries</em></p><p>Go.</p><p>It’s what the team and network have been doing and will continue to do. Just as the QRL network’s blocks move forward, so too will we.</p><h4>Go-QRL Node</h4><p>Our <a href="https://golang.org/">Golang</a> node of QRL has now been released to a public repository and is under active development.</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_(programming_language)">Go</a> (also known as Golang) is a new compiled programming language developed by Google in 2009 that makes it easy to build simple, reliable, and efficient software. This will allow for faster, more consistent QRL nodes with full-concurrency throughout.</p><p>You can find the repository on our <a href="https://github.com/theQRL">Github</a> at <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/go-qrl/">go-qrl</a>. It should be stressed that this is a <strong>work in progress</strong> and <strong>NOT TO BE USED IN PRODUCTION— ONLY FOR VIEWING PURPOSES</strong>.</p><h4>Project Carbon — Smart Contracts</h4><p>Continued work on the Smart Contract QIP (QRL Improvement Proposal), now dubbed <strong>Project Carbon</strong>, is well under way. Last week, attack surfaces were researched, discussed, and reflected in the upcoming QIP + blog. Along with this, compiler structure is making progress and is expected by this weekend.</p><p>There is a <em>strong</em> focus on balancing the functionality of our Smart Contract platform with preventing exploits. Feature wise, the emphasis is on financial applications, so expect things like Escrow Payments, Recurring Payment Schedules, decentralized automated multiple-signatory accounts, and more.</p><h4>Binary wallet v1.0.2 released</h4><p>An incremental update for our binary wallet for Windows, Mac and Linux has been <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-wallet/releases/tag/v1.0.2">released</a>!</p><p><strong>Changelog</strong></p><ul><li>Improved Mobile UI</li><li>Resolves transaction display bugs</li><li>Shows warning when sending to 0x Ethereum addresses</li><li>Updated CI to support CircleCI v2</li><li>Updated Meteor base to 1.7.0.4</li></ul><h4>Developer Meeting Summary</h4><p>Those with a keen watchful eye on our github may have already noticed the first release of our developer meeting summary. This summary will allow everyone to get an inside look on what is discussed every Thursday at 19:00 UTC.</p><p>Some highlights not mentioned in this blog are:</p><p><strong>BECH32 QIP</strong></p><ul><li>Planning parallel use of Q-hexstrings and BECH32 addresses</li><li>Andrew undertaking exploratory work</li></ul><p><strong>Interface/interaction</strong></p><ul><li>Early stage QIP on interaction design to visualise network activity discussed: primary draft on wallet in progress.</li><li>To be expanded both for explorer and smart contracts.</li><li>Outreach with interaction designers/interested parties in the crypto space discussed.</li></ul><p><strong>x41 audit</strong></p><ul><li>Audit to start Monday 20th August: scope and logistics discussed</li></ul><p>Be sure to read the full summary <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/dev-meetings/blob/master/2018/08/16.md">here</a>. This is something we are trialing so it may not be a permanent feature. If you find you really enjoy it, let us know in our <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">Discord</a> or <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/qrl">Reddit</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=46186f8635c5" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/go-qrl-46186f8635c5">Go-QRL</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[QRL Mainnet v1.1.1 Released]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-mainnet-v1-1-1-released-631ebc4d4208?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/631ebc4d4208</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[wallet]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[golang]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[api-integration]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 21:02:29 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-08-10T21:19:14.357Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TLDR — QRL mainnet v1.1.1 is released and brings a wallet API, wallet daemon, greater stability, and other improvements.</em></p><p>At roughly 65,000 blocks after genesis, <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/QRL/releases/tag/v1.1.1">QRL mainnet v1.1.1</a> was born, and with it comes back end non-breaking improvements. If you’re running a node you can update today:</p><pre>pip3 install qrl --upgrade</pre><h4>Improvements are</h4><ul><li>Added support for Wallet API &amp; Wallet Daemon</li><li>Fix for state validation of stale transaction in mempool ( <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/QRL/issues/1538">#1538</a> )</li><li>Mining Address are displayed properly during node start</li><li>CLI token_list now shows token name &amp; symbol</li><li>Added more unit tests</li><li>Update cryptography module to 2.3</li><li>Removed wallet.json from repo</li><li>Removed pycrypto module from test_requirements.txt</li></ul><h4>Wallet API &amp; Daemon</h4><p>One of the new features is the Wallet Daemon &amp; Wallet API which allows for extensive manipulation of <a href="https://api.theqrl.org/#wallet-api">wallet functions</a> through our <a href="https://api.theqrl.org/#qrl-api">gRPC API</a>, an important feature for exchange integration.</p><p>After the update, you can run the wallet daemon (there is no response when you do so)</p><pre>$ qrl_walletd</pre><p>From there you can go over and install the <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/walletd-rest-proxy">walletd-rest-proxy</a> on github. Be sure to use golang &gt;1.8.</p><pre>go get github.com/theQRL/walletd-rest-proxy<br>cd $GOPATH/src/github.com/theQRL/walletd-rest-proxy<br>go build<br>./walletd-rest-proxy -serverIPPort 127.0.0.1:5359 -walletServiceEndpoint 127.0.0.1:19010</pre><p>This opens access to our <a href="https://api.theqrl.org/#wallet-api">wallet API</a> with <em>a lot</em> of things a person can do.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/826/1*jFvqV54R7sQhhQfWBoxdig.png" /></figure><h4>Open Source Contribution Guide (decentralized improvements)</h4><p>We would welcome your help and support as we move to further decentralize this project as one of our longstanding goals.</p><p>For that we are preparing a contribution guide which will be released shortly. While you’re waiting, you can check out some of our <a href="http://These &#39;help wanted&#39; labels are for the public? https://github.com/theQRL/QRL/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22Help+Wanted%22">issues with the label “Help Wanted”</a>, read our <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org">Documentation</a>, and ask questions in our <a href="https://discord.gg/RX5SWPN">Discord</a> or <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/QRL/">Reddit</a> community to become more familiar with everything.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=631ebc4d4208" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-mainnet-v1-1-1-released-631ebc4d4208">QRL Mainnet v1.1.1 Released</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mobile app, QIPs, and More!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/mobile-app-qips-and-more-72a96bbee0a3?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/72a96bbee0a3</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain-development]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[react-native]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[mobile-application]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[p2p]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 20:54:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-08-03T20:54:58.507Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TLDR — Mobile app technical side complete, the QIP process, In the Media Section, and a P2P exchange network listing commit.</em></p><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/step-by-step-what-weve-been-up-to-f6cd800e0a63">Last week</a> we spoke about Ledger progress, mobile (web) improvements, API documentation, our new post-quantum notarisation feature, and a brief update on smart contracts!</p><p>This week, we’re now past 55,000 blocks, with a different set of updates.</p><h4>Mobile Application</h4><p>The technical side of the mobile phone application is <strong>complete</strong>, which means it’s building out the aesthetic designs (shown below) made by Luke Hahn, our design lead.</p><p>As an overview, some of the components which are built and working on mobile are:</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrllib">qrllib</a> (QRL Core Library)</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrllib/tree/master/src/shasha">shasha </a>(to support additional sha2 hash function)</li><li><a href="https://eprint.iacr.org/2017/634.pdf">Kyber</a> &amp; <a href="https://cryptojedi.org/papers/dilithium-20170627.pdf">Dilithium</a> (used for ephemeral messaging)</li></ul><p>Along with this is properly working bi-directional communication between react-native (JavaScript) and native code (Objective-C for iOS and Java for Android) using bridges.</p><p>Great work Adem Bilican!</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/375/1*ATPZu7zBl6zry3KEqPZpAA.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/375/1*WqnynBhXl8gG2bjMt3eZ3w.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/375/1*SIMv8AUWra64BKJ4jF3EwQ.png" /></figure><h3>QRL Improvement Proposals (QIPs)</h3><p>With our main network launched it’s critical to maintain a stable and secure system for any integration&#39;s that would effect things at the network level, or are otherwise significant in nature.</p><p>This is where QIPs come in, which follows a formal process full of checks and balances. You can check out the <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips">repository</a> and read more about the <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/tree/master/0.Process">process</a>.</p><p>Soon to be released will be our first QIP for smart contracts with forth-like scripting. From this, anybody will be able to use it as an example and initiate their own QRL Improvement Proposal (QIP) process.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/386/1*Hz3zkVZskyV27dStSRAglA.png" /></figure><h4>Website addition — In the media</h4><p>Our new In the media tracks mentions as well as quantum-news and advancements. You can check it out on the website now at <a href="https://theqrl.org/media">theqrl.org/media</a>. Expect more updates to the site as we have a lot planned for it beyond the <em>In the Media</em> section.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/952/1*ezM5CGWWoy1wk0mmAfvqLg.png" /></figure><h4>Bisq.network — P2P Exchange Network</h4><p>While we are working with exchanges to list our main network coin, we have made a <a href="https://github.com/bisq-network/bisq-assets/pull/91">commit</a> to be listed on the <a href="https://bisq.network/">bisq.network</a> to help facilitate person to person trades. Bisq works a little different than other exchanges, and we have a video below, from Bisq, that explains it a bit. You can also check out their <a href="https://bisq.network/faq/">FAQ.</a></p><iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2Fjj4x4x1OlAY%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3Djj4x4x1OlAY&amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2Fjj4x4x1OlAY%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;key=a19fcc184b9711e1b4764040d3dc5c07&amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;schema=youtube" width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><a href="https://medium.com/media/8ab12dfce7b01a4e82abb87aa07a6c3e/href">https://medium.com/media/8ab12dfce7b01a4e82abb87aa07a6c3e/href</a></iframe><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=72a96bbee0a3" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/mobile-app-qips-and-more-72a96bbee0a3">Mobile app, QIPs, and More!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Step by step, what we’ve been up to]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/step-by-step-what-weve-been-up-to-f6cd800e0a63?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/f6cd800e0a63</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledgerwallet]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[api-documentation]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 20:07:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-07-26T20:07:04.485Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>tldr; Ledger progress, mobile improvements, API documentation, our new post-quantum notarisation feature, and a brief update on smart contracts!</em></p><p>We have now surpassed our 44,000th block with no major issues, a testament to the amount of testing done by the development side at QRL. To date, nobody has locked up their funds (to our knowledge) on the QRL blockchain.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/480/1*x2IMle4WkmTOEXlYzXfBsA.gif" /><figcaption>Post Launch — Team at QRL HQ</figcaption></figure><p>With mainnet out of the way, many of us took alternating breaks, while a few others continued drumming on.</p><h4>Ledger Progress</h4><p>While the main codebase for the Ledger has been completed, there is now webwallet Ledger support for complete end-to-end support. This just needs to be reviewed by the Ledger team for full hardware support.</p><p>You can use the code yourself by heading to the respective repositories below, this comes of course with a caveat emptor (warning), test at your own risk!</p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/ledger-qrl-js">theQRL/ledger-qrl-js</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/ledger-qrl">theQRL/ledger-qrl</a></li></ul><h4>Mobile Improvements</h4><p>Both the <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org">webwallet</a> and the <a href="https://explorer.theqrl.org/">explorer</a> have had some adjustments to make everything work across all platforms, from desktop to mobile.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/413/1*G6DiQ7GQ8Xp2_xqbBNWheQ.gif" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/413/1*l6KaeT00quSag_RDdIYYbw.gif" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/413/1*txJj_moRTFuFlrU6vWrg0Q.gif" /></figure><h4>Post Quantum Resistant Document Notarisation</h4><p>After a successful launch, it’s time to start looking for the future! There will be a more blogs coming, that will go over what is on the horizon. In the meantime, it’s nice to build off of what we already have operational on QRL.</p><p>One of our first new features is Post Quantum Resistant Notarisation! For those that don’t know,<strong> Notarisation </strong>(British spelling)<strong> </strong>is the official fraud-deterrent process that assures the parties of a transaction that a document is authentic, and can be trusted. As you can imagine, this is a big thing in many industries. You can read more at <a href="https://www.nationalnotary.org/knowledge-center/about-notaries/what-is-notarization">national notary</a>.</p><p>You can try notarisation yourself <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org">here</a> by going to our <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org">webwallet</a> and selecting ‘Tools -&gt; Notarise Document’.</p><p>Don’t want to go through the whole process of notarising a document?</p><ol><li>Download a test document (<a href="https://cryptome.org/2016/01/CNSA-Suite-and-Quantum-Computing-FAQ.pdf">here</a>)</li><li>Go to the explorer <a href="https://explorer.theqrl.org/tx/9f2b01c3ed74cdeb7d5bffa4ed1b42bae4c2dfd91d15c94aef8f5589f11f711b">here</a>, select the file downloaded in step one, and click ‘Verify Notarisation’.</li></ol><p>There is more to come in this area to make it easier to use. Nice work Scott!</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/540/1*7rhh3NxTQXg4oHHGkgS1rg.gif" /></figure><h4>Smart Contracts</h4><p>There has been some initial work with our smart contracts, which there will be a <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/QIPS/">QIP</a> of soon.</p><p>To avoid any potential compromisation of security we will limit the scope of smart contract code execution, and confine such code to fairly narrow logic statements. You can still do <em>almost </em>anything with such a design, but it makes for a much more secure system.</p><h4>QRL API documentation</h4><p>While we have had <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/">documentation</a> for various elements of our ecosystem up to this point, James has been hard at work with the API documentation, complete with examples on how to get started. The documentation is now live at <a href="https://api.theqrl.org">api.theqrl.org</a>. This is a major step in facilitating utility that will make it easier for developers, as well as outside organizations that may be interested, to build off our chain.</p><p>Now is the time to get started and head over to the <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/">qrl documentation site</a>, <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org/node/QRLnode/">run a node</a>, and browse the <a href="https://discord.gg/KAg5fAm">#qrl-app-ideas</a> channel on our <a href="https://discord.gg/KAg5fAm">Discord</a> for ideas — or share one there yourself!</p><h4>Our road ahead</h4><p>As we get some final legal aspects sorted, and our main network coin listed on a known exchange, we have many exciting developments that we cannot wait to share with our users and the wider cryptocurrency community. Stay tuned!</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=f6cd800e0a63" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/step-by-step-what-weve-been-up-to-f6cd800e0a63">Step by step, what we’ve been up to</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Red4Sec security audit concludes; a summary]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/red4sec-security-audit-concludes-a-summary-563ecfe04c75?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/563ecfe04c75</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[red4sec]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[security-audit]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 16:14:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-06-24T18:13:21.131Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR — Red4Sec finished, more audits coming, and an update regarding mainnet</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/600/1*2_UP8IGhmeUbwSiaN6Gecw.png" /></figure><p><a href="https://red4sec.com/en">Red4Sec</a>, our auditor for the last 7 weeks, has completed their audit and submitted their report to QRL. Red4Sec consists of a talented team that has spent much of the past 2 months poring over our code 8 hours a day, 5 days a week. They were joined in parallel by our own team, also scouring our codebase for vulnerabilities and mishaps, as well as dealing with issues raised by Red4Sec as they came up.</p><p>During the analysis, whose report runs over 200 pages, a total of 67 vulnerabilities were detected. Many of these vulnerabilities did not pose any risk by themselves and therefore have been classified as informative.</p><p>All vulnerabilities were classified according to the impact level defined by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Common_Vulnerability_Scoring_System">CVSS</a> (Common Vulnerability Scoring System): critical, high, medium, low and informative.</p><p>A summary of the issues per project area is described below.</p><h3>What Red4Sec covered</h3><p>Red4Sec’s report was exhaustive, and covered the entirety of our project space, with the exception of our Post Quantum Cryptography, which will be covered by a further audit as it’s more specialized in nature. Below is a rundown of issues raised by Red4Sec by section of our network, as well as impact level.</p><h4>Blockchain</h4><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/QRL">QRL</a> (Python)<br><strong>Critical</strong>: 6 issues identified — All fixed by end of audit<br><strong>High</strong>: 3 issues identified — All fixed by end of audit<br><strong>Medium</strong>: 4 issues identified — 2 fixed by end of audit, outstanding fixes have now been applied (everything is fixed)<br><strong>Low/Informative</strong>: 21 issues or queries which have all been reviewed by the team, with changes made to the codebase where necessary.</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qryptonight">Qryptonight</a> (C++)<br><strong>Critical</strong>: 1 issue identified — fixed by end of audit</li><li><a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrllib">Qrllib</a> (C++)<br><strong>Informative</strong>: 1 issue which was closed by the end of the audit.</li></ul><h4>Public facing Infrastructure</h4><ul><li><a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org">QRL Wallet</a> (JS)<br><strong>Critical</strong>: 1 issue identified — fixed by end of audit<br><strong>High</strong>: 1 issue identified as informative by Red4Sec — the team rated it as High, however, and it was fixed by the end of the audit</li><li><a href="https://explorer.theqrl.org">Block Explorer</a> (JS)<br><strong>Low/Informative</strong>: 1 Low and 1 Informative level issue which were both closed by the end of the audit.</li><li><a href="http://theqrl.org">theqrl.org</a> (JS)<br><strong>Medium</strong>: 1 issue identified — fixed by the end of audit</li></ul><h4>Backend &amp; Team processes</h4><ul><li>Infrastructure includes nodes, cloud services, mail services and any other service that QRL relies upon for development and other team processes.<br><strong>Medium</strong>: 5 issues identified — all fixed by end of audit.<br><strong>Low/Informative</strong>: 11 issues have been identified and all have been fixed.</li></ul><h4>Some words from Red4Sec:</h4><blockquote>In general terms, it has been detected that the design and logic of the project is well defined.</blockquote><blockquote>The project code follows a methodology of safe programming and good practices. The project has great support from the team as some of the vulnerabilities have been resolved at the time they were detected by Red4Sec, mitigating the possible impact and repercussion that could cause to the project.</blockquote><p>The whole QRL team thanks Red4Sec for their professionalism and attention to detail in improving the quality of our ecosystem.</p><h3>More audits</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/256/1*KJ97NABMOdKXiBWnyINcEw.png" /></figure><p>As our codebase and ecosystem grows, it is important to continually appraise the security of our implementations.</p><p>We are, therefore, pleased to announce that we have signed an agreement with <a href="https://www.x41-dsec.de/">X41 D-Sec GmbH</a> to undertake a <em>secondary</em> security audit in the coming months. This audit will be differently focused than the Red4Sec audit, leveraging some of the specific expertise at X41 such as covering the Post Quantum Cryptography portion of QRL.</p><h3>Mainnet Progress Update</h3><p>It has been a long ride to reach our main network, and our launch is just the beginning of the overall QRL journey.</p><p>A date for the launch of the QRL main network has been finalized and will be announced in the coming days.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*wOpNyhey8Kogd6i88dfuoA.jpeg" /><figcaption>QRL On the Horizon — User art by Discord user @snannerb</figcaption></figure><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=563ecfe04c75" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/red4sec-security-audit-concludes-a-summary-563ecfe04c75">Red4Sec security audit concludes; a summary</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pre-Genesis Project Update]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/pre-genesis-project-update-80c7dbe89ac0?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/80c7dbe89ac0</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[updates]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Elliott Gregory Dehnbostel]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 17:51:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-06-05T19:50:53.395Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It has been some time since our last general progress update blog. In this blog we will do our best to detail as much as we can regarding:</p><ul><li>The ongoing audit with Red4Sec</li><li>The creation of mobile wallets</li><li>Support for Ledger Nano S</li><li>Token burn update</li><li>Bug bounties</li><li>Transform PR</li><li>Conference/expo/meeting appearance summary</li><li>Mainnet plans</li></ul><p>This will likely be the last general update blog before the announcement of our main network, with smaller updates in the interim.</p><h3>The ongoing audit with Red4Sec</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/200/1*MgE-EIz1eOdKfzR32AW6FA.png" /><figcaption>Red4Sec logo</figcaption></figure><p>In the last week of April, our audit with <a href="https://red4sec.com/en">Red4Sec</a> (henceforth R4S) started, and we are happy to say that progress is steady and we can expect it to complete within the next 2–4 weeks. Over the past month, we have closed every issue on the private GitHub by R4S in a timely manner, as they have been raised. Fortunately, nothing thus far has been what we or Red4Sec would consider a critical vulnerability.</p><p>We are close to signing on our second audit partner, who will have a different focus on our repository than that which R4S is guided by. Mainnet launch will not be delayed for the conclusion of this audit.</p><p>We will have a separate blog discussing the audit once it has concluded. Moreover, we will be announcing information about the second auditor shortly.</p><h3>The creation of mobile wallets</h3><p>Our mobile wallet developer, Adem, has been hard at work (with the help of our designer, Luke Hahn) developing Android and iOS versions of a QRL wallet! We are happy to share some of the preliminary pictures of what the mobile wallets may ultimately look like:</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/234/1*nVtplmj0cD-CZoZvcliC2w.gif" /><figcaption>Quick demo (low fps due to Medium filesize limits)</figcaption></figure><p>Due to the early nature of their development, no date can yet be made available regarding when these applications will be available to the general public. It should also be noted that design and UI elements may change between now and when the mobile wallets are launched. However, we can say that the mobile wallet should be operational within a reasonable time frame following the launch of our main network.</p><p>The repository for the iOS and Android version is <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/mobile-wallet">now available</a>.</p><h3><strong>Support for Ledger Nano S </strong>🎉</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/902/1*mQy3h4Xg2YQs_wh_LFrFJg.png" /><figcaption>Ledger generating private keys for a new wallet</figcaption></figure><p>We recognize that many of you have been patiently waiting for an update on this item in particular. Our developers have made great progress towards full Ledger support: we now have full wallet functionality inside a development environment. Due to computational limitations, the device takes about 45 minutes to generate a wallet. However, this only needs to be done once, and it only takes a few seconds to sign a transaction.</p><p>There is still some work to be done in order to make it ready for general consumers, but we cannot overstate the technical feat that has been accomplished here. From the outset, it was clear that it would be a difficult task to achieve functional Ledger support. We are very thankful to Juan for his tireless work in this regard, and to Leon for his invaluable technical advice and consult.</p><p>We will make more information available regarding Ledger support as development moves forward in this area. To be precise, we are at the point in time where the Ledger team is going to be reviewing our code. Pending approval, the code can and will be made available for public use on Ledger Nano S.</p><p>There is now a public repository for <em>some</em> (but not all) of the code related to the Ledger: <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qrl-ledger-js">here</a>.</p><h3>Token burn update</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/821/1*or_uwJy9Z14oKco-rOrbxg.png" /></figure><p>The beginning of our token burn process was a big milestone towards the launch of our main network. We are able to provide an update on its progress: ~25% of QRL ERC20 tokens at large have been burned. <strong>If you’ve already burned your tokens, remember to keep track of that wallet file, and back it up on at least two separate devices!</strong> It is the <em>only </em>means by which you will able access your funds on the main network. <em>If you lose this file, the team can do nothing in order to return your funds to you, due to the very nature of blockchain technology. </em>Unlike other blockchains, a large quantum computer will not help you recover your coins on our network.</p><p>If you are reading this and would like to burn your tokens in order to have your wallet credited inside the genesis block, please read our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/qrl-token-migration-begins-b0d5b53f697f">token migration blog</a>.</p><h3>Bug bounties</h3><p>Some time ago we announced a general plan to implement bug bounties. This was not forgotten. Thus far, we have fleshed out the framework of the program that we intend to use. It is now pending legal review in order to ensure that all participating parties are kept safe. Therefor it is likely that the official bounty program will be in place soon after mainnet launch.</p><h3>Transform PR</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/256/1*zla7a6BKBiIYrAzSc96siQ.png" /><figcaption>Transform Group logo</figcaption></figure><p>We’ve hired a PR agency to help bring our marketing and promotional efforts to a new level. You can read our blog post about it <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/we-hired-a-pr-firm-9ef9c19bb219">here</a>.</p><h3>Conference Appearances and Other Things</h3><p>In case you missed them: here are the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-apac-blockchain-2018-1fbba71a50f">APAC</a>, <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-consensus-2018-ef1509897eec">Consensus</a>, and <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-blockchain-expo-2018-83055106aae0">Blockchain Expo</a> blogs giving an overview of the various conferences and expos that we attended. Adam is currently in the process of identifying and coordinating conference, expo, and other visits of interest for the second half of 2018.</p><p>In addition, you can read up on the summaries of some of our meetings with <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-dc-finances-high-tech-family-office-meetings-b7fe8067d40d">DC Finance</a> and the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-my-evening-with-the-financial-services-club-in-london-573d5713f001">Financial Services Club</a>. The networking made available to us through these is invaluable, and we are very thankful to have been allowed the privilege of presenting.</p><p>We will have a blog with a full or partial list of conference appearances in a few weeks, as new conferences are still being announced and communicated with.</p><h3>Mainnet plans</h3><p>This section is likely to be the most interesting part of the blog for most people. Now that we are nearing the conclusion of the pre-genesis development effort, our plans for launch can be made more clear.</p><p>One can expect us to launch a few weeks after the R4S audit has completed. On launch, the following will be immediately available within the Quantum Resistant Ledger ecosystem:</p><ul><li>The first fully quantum resistant cryptocurrency on its own main network.</li><li>Agnostic Cryptonight Proof-of-Work mining (<a href="https://getmonero.org/">Monero</a> mining compatible)</li><li>Post-genesis ERC20 QRL-to-mainnet migration tool</li><li>Quantum Resistant Tokens, also on the QRL network.</li><li>The web wallet, for easy interface with the QRL network.</li><li>Node documentation, in order to assist developers in their participation with this open source effort.</li><li>Public, audited node (including related) code available on GitHub</li></ul><p>In the future, after mainnet launch, the following will likely be made available, in no particular order:</p><ul><li>Ledger Nano S support</li><li>Bug bounty program</li><li>Ephemeral messaging layer</li><li>Android and iOS mobile wallets</li><li>Proof of Stake</li></ul><p>Some things that we have in mind for the future:</p><ul><li>Smart contract feasibility evaluation immediately following mainnet</li></ul><p>We understand that many of our supporters would have liked to see some of these features at launch. However, due to time constraints and an acute understanding that a quarter of all tokens at large (and rising) are currently locked into migration, certain non-critical features had to be pushed back.</p><p>Regarding exchange support for our main network: per instruction, we cannot discuss whether or not any given exchange listing our ERC20 token will or will not convert automatically those ERC20 tokens to our mainnet QRL. Please look to those exchanges for notice in regard to these matters.</p><p>We are also in talks with new exchanges about listing our mainnet QRL coin. Exchange support information will be made available as soon as we are free to share it.</p><p>In conclusion: it is reasonable to expect us to launch in the weeks following the conclusion of both the R4S audit and the CryptoValley conference.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=80c7dbe89ac0" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/pre-genesis-project-update-80c7dbe89ac0">Pre-Genesis Project Update</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>