<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Cryptography with longevity. A post-quantum secure blockchain featuring a stateful signature scheme and unparalleled security. - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>The Quantum Resistant Ledger - Medium</title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:41:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://medium.com/feed/the-quantum-resistant-ledger" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week(s) at QRL: Dec 18–Jan 6]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-s-at-qrl-dec-18-jan-6-87f2b17c8c94?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/87f2b17c8c94</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledgerwallet]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 18:16:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2019-01-08T18:16:13.246Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*OGirdELd8Xkc8YjwCbAVOw.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>It has been a little while since our last “Last Week in QRL” blog. So in honour of this being the first blog of 2019, “Happy New Year!”</p><p>Obviously this blog will have closer to just one week’s worth of content in it, despite covering two weeks, as both Christmas (check out our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/12-days-of-xmass-e787fd958d2c">12 days of XMaSS blog</a>) and New Year’s occurred during those weeks. As always, life in a startup project can be very hectic, and everyone enjoyed the opportunity to be able to spend some quality time with their families, and perhaps reflect upon the past year.</p><p>As we have stated elsewhere, 2018 was obviously a disappointing year across the cryptocurrency market, in terms of price. However, we believe that both within our project, and across the wider blockchain ecosystem, that some very important and meaningful work has been completed this year. 2018 saw QRL go from an ERC20 to a fully-realised, fully-functional blockchain network. The close of 2018 had QRL as a mineable PoW coin, with liquidity secured, robust documentation and API sites, and many exciting features on the horizon. Given where we were at the start of 2018, we cannot help but look at it as a success.</p><p>Hopefully, as time goes on, the overall prices across the blockchain ecosystem begin to more meaningfully reflect the hard work and real progress being made behind the scenes.</p><h3>GO-QRL</h3><p>Go-QRL has been running stable for around a month now running QRL mainnet. While stable, there’s still components required to bring it up to feature parity with the Python implementation — and beyond. Over the holidays, Kaushal continued his perseverance and added a Public API, makefile support, with a new JSON-based backend infrastructure in progress.</p><p>The JSON-based backend will make it easier for people to interact with the API without requiring the setup and maintenance of our wallet daemon, walletd.</p><h3>Block Explorer</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/488/1*v1io_xyLgIhMdT1dkrhdEw.gif" /><figcaption>Dark and Light Theme</figcaption></figure><p>From the outset, we at QRL have recognised that a piece of software is only as good as the user’s ability to utilise it. To that end, we have never stopped making improvements to our UI/UX. The latest of these improvements, adding a dark theme to our wallet and block explorer, have been another step in that process. This was met with much applause, and some disdain from the community lamenting the disappearance of a light theme.</p><p>Based on this feedback, as the above GIF should show, the <a href="https://explorer.theqrl.org/">QRL Block Explorer</a> will soon have a button to toggle the theme from Light to Dark, and vice versa. We believe this will help make our block explorer experience more pleasant and useful.</p><h3>Mobile Wallet Testing</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*_1tj04T7JUzIsbu7DvkpQA.png" /></figure><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-s-in-qrl-december-4th-17th-2018-e7f744845075">When we last checked in</a> on our mobile app on iOS and Android, we were finishing up internal testing and getting ready to move on to a first round of testing to a select group in the community.</p><p>We are happy to report that this has taken place, and that the testing so far has been both productive and encouraging. We recognise that a mobile wallet app is an element that, along with the release of our Ledger app, many in our community have been waiting for.</p><p>After some fixes and tweaks take place, we’ll be opening this up to the wider community to test in the next few weeks.</p><h3>Ledger Nano S</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/971/1*JOUTMbvrI1VFrYGMi7E4HQ.png" /></figure><p>Speaking of the Ledger App, we have more news. As we stated in our previous “Last Week” blog, we had a release-candidate version of the Ledger app up on our GitHub.</p><p><strong><em>We can now say that we have entirely completed the Ledger integration, and are now awaiting only a full and thorough review from the Ledger team themselves</em></strong>, before the app should be ready for release. Integrating with quality hardware like that which Ledger produces represents a significant achievement on the part of the development team, and we are all very proud of the hard work and long hours it has taken to get to being on this precipice of its materialisation.</p><p>Scott Donald has studiously put together a tech demonstration on how the wallet and the Ledger Nano S works harmonistically together.</p><iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FNL_u9biLy1g%3Ffeature%3Doembed&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DNL_u9biLy1g&amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FNL_u9biLy1g%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;key=a19fcc184b9711e1b4764040d3dc5c07&amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;schema=youtube" width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><a href="https://medium.com/media/43eaedbd6040b4e280addd9df5a4279e/href">https://medium.com/media/43eaedbd6040b4e280addd9df5a4279e/href</a></iframe><h4>Ledger Nano X</h4><p>After 1.5 million devices sold, the Ledger team announced the Ledger Nano X, which you can read more about <a href="https://www.ledger.com/pages/ledger-nano-x">here</a>.</p><p>To answer the inevitable question early on as to whether QRL will work on the Ledger Nano X, the answer is the device will work on the QRL wallet, but there’s more work to enable it on the Ledger mobile and desktop apps. We will have more information on this in a separate, Ledger-specific blog.</p><p>Of course, this means more toys for the developers to play with!</p><h3>Confirmed for DeveloperWeek 2019</h3><p>Adam Koltun will be speaking at <a href="https://www.developerweek.com/">DeveloperWeek 2019</a> in Oakland, California on February 20th, at the Oakland Convention Center. <a href="https://developerweek2019.sched.com/speaker/adam_koltun.1yz9ak9c">Link to his speaker bio</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=87f2b17c8c94" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-s-at-qrl-dec-18-jan-6-87f2b17c8c94">Last Week(s) at QRL: Dec 18–Jan 6</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[12 Days of XMaSS]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/12-days-of-xmass-e787fd958d2c?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/e787fd958d2c</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[xmss]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[12-days-of-christmas]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 19:44:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-12-24T19:44:22.044Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR — This is a cheerful, jovial blog meant to take a fun, non-serious look at where the project is at as 2018 comes to a close, but mostly to have some festive fun before the end of the year. Enjoy!</em></p><p>On the first day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>A private key in an (extended) Merkle Tree</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/728/1*-m3M7AyBdz8OQrSUatYVNw.png" /></figure><p>On the second day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>Two Separate Audits</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/599/1*GaVAZkT7xXayfq54ijcSBg.png" /></figure><p>On the third day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><a href="https://theqrl.org/"><strong>Three Different Desktop Wallets</strong></a></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*cakH5GpAQ39JhfnY_vPGhw.jpeg" /></figure><p>On the fourth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me <br><strong>4k Discord Members</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/811/1*se_sPGWwewD6PGzLHo8b8Q.png" /></figure><p>n the fifth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong> 5 Community Members Nominated</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*rC1VxV2hR2aWKkeWGXkJIA.png" /></figure><p>On the sixth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me <br><strong>6 QRL Block Reward</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*_NZ25cqH3Be67uZ920dHug.png" /></figure><p>On the seventh day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>7 Podcast Interviews</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/539/1*cnW4-roIbNHsFwVW07f95A.jpeg" /></figure><p>On the eighth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>8 Presentations Given</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1018/1*YJEsFeL0uuCTq02mIt7T0A.png" /></figure><p>On the ninth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>9 Whitepaper Translations</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/472/1*XndAzJRLUNypXvzznvuZGw.jpeg" /></figure><p>On the tenth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>10 QRL Developers</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ZsLRt1UHh56lG2syshBGFg.jpeg" /></figure><p>On the eleventh day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>11 Conferences Attended</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/768/1*lrlKw5OqQlHg8tVeS2tgkw.png" /></figure><p>On the twelfth day of XMaSS my true love sent to me<br><strong>12+ Team Members!</strong></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/780/1*VNnreXNsnpUaAN-3zMP21Q.png" /></figure><h3>See you all next year!</h3><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=e787fd958d2c" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/12-days-of-xmass-e787fd958d2c">12 Days of XMaSS</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last week(s) in QRL: December 4th — 17th, 2018]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-s-in-qrl-december-4th-17th-2018-e7f744845075?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/e7f744845075</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[last-week-in-qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:54:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-12-18T00:54:55.330Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*BT-HSmeZOIkEl8DbZVI-Nw.png" /></figure><h3>Last Week(s) in QRL: December 4th — 17th, 2018</h3><h3>Ledger Nano S</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1000/1*Kv7G47q3znR9TZ4zemMHVQ.jpeg" /></figure><p>We are happy to report that the Ledger app is complete! We just need the web integration to be finished, and testing to commence, before we call ledger-qrl-js v1.0.0 ready for a full release. We will probably have a pre-release version of the app up on our GitHub before New Year’s Eve, for those who cannot wait and want to see our Ledger app in action ASAP.</p><p>We know how long many of you in the community have been waiting for this; it is close to being completely ready!</p><h3>Mobile app</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*klBbafDPyPTSXB3pJiULfw.png" /></figure><p>Mobile app is passing internal testing and should be going out to a hand-picked cohort of community members to do the first round of testing soon for iOS and Android users.</p><p>Features include:</p><ul><li>Transferring a wallet from the desktop to mobile through QR hexseed scanning</li><li>PIN security</li><li>Multiple wallets</li><li>Sending to QR Code address</li><li>Receiving with a QR Code address</li><li>Seeing a history of transactions</li></ul><h3>API &amp; documentation</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*awrKfdtjTwDU-KZ6DWYK9A.png" /><figcaption><a href="https://api.theqrl.org/#qrl-api">https://api.theqrl.org/#qrl-api</a></figcaption></figure><p>New updates to gettotalbalance as a request from upbit is in place. Go-client documentation is in process to help facilitate community testing and those to want to run our <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/go-qrl">go-lang QRL node</a>.</p><h3>Cryptoblockcon</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*6f9_bfwjzuJMR4kN1C7j8g.png" /></figure><p>Jack Matier and Adam Koltun were at <a href="https://www.cryptoblockcon.com/">CryptoBlockCon</a> in Las Vegas, Nevada this week on the 11th and 12th. You can read more about it on the <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/crypto-block-conference-this-week-1a8f4d1d0cc4">blog penned by Adam Koltun</a>. But to briefly review; this was the 11th conference attended by QRL this year. QRL name recognition much higher than at start of 2018. Presentation was given on the 2nd day of the conference, video can be found <a href="https://youtu.be/G7K5REE152w">here</a>. CBC was our last conference of 2018.</p><h3>QIP-1 (to CNv1 or CNv2, that is the question)</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/750/1*dhlNj5gdbpQ9vexXD-49hg.jpeg" /></figure><p>Consensus of the team is that migration at this point would not be in the best interests of the project at this time. Reasons cited include:</p><ul><li>It would take time out of progress on other aspects of QRL, including PoS/Consensus upgrade.</li><li>Every consensus upgrade involves backwards portability, meaning support for the life of the project.</li><li>Whether or not ASICS help or hinder the security of a network is still a hot topic with no clear consensus in either direction, as far as security is concerned.</li><li>There’s no firm evidence that there are ASICS in the wild, many of the claims surrounding it are conjecture.</li></ul><p>As this was a discussion technical in nature, we didn’t open the vote up to the public,<strong> QIP-1 has therefore been closed</strong>, though not without some amazing (and respectful) discussion on both sides! You can read the discourse <a href="https://github.com/theQRL/qips/pull/2">here</a>. As with all technical matters, should to context meaningfully change we would be open to resuming discussion with the new context in mind.</p><h3>Nominations</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*DvAHSmqbjjes08TtT8C3Uw.png" /></figure><p>Nominations will be moved from weekly to monthly events with an increased award from 250 Quanta to 750 Quanta. This will be started immediately with the first award being announced by the end of January, 2019.</p><p>However, to wrap up the last two weeks of our Community Nominations we have discord users qrl_dude and Cryptographic for their contributions, insight, and thoughts.</p><h3>Explorer dark mode</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*B3AdBDdKJ3_Y1PGAKYCYjA.png" /></figure><p>JP Lomas has been at work putting together a dark mode to the QRL Explorer, which is currently being implemented and test in devnet, let us know what you think. To note, dark mode would be a <em>new</em> mode and not something available by toggling.</p><p>In addition to this, there will be a select few json methods available in the future available via REST (and curl) requests for easily parsing of data.</p><h3><strong>Bittrex</strong></h3><p>In case it was missed, Bittrex has finished it’s migration of QRL ERC20 tokens to QRL’s mainnet Quanta. This establishes proper liquidity for the QRL ecosystem.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=e7f744845075" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-s-in-qrl-december-4th-17th-2018-e7f744845075">Last week(s) in QRL: December 4th — 17th, 2018</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bittrex Exchange Migration Complete!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/bittrex-exchange-migration-complete-fab674992588?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/fab674992588</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[bittrex]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 22:51:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-12-17T22:51:58.939Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*1QW-t_bHtK3cEonGUQjcEg.png" /></figure><p>We are delighted to announce that <a href="https://bittrex.com"><strong>Bittrex</strong></a> has successfully migrated the QRL ERC20s in their possession and that all QRL markets on Bittrex are now trading the mineable, main network Quanta (while still maintaining the $QRL ticker). Link to <a href="https://bittrex.com/Market/Index?MarketName=BTC-QRL">QRL-BTC Bittrex market</a>.</p><p>As we stated in our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/bittrex-exchange-migration-proper-liquidity-secured-for-the-qrl-df41045497e3">announcement blog</a>, the entire QRL team would like to thank the team at Bittrex for working closely with us to ensure this smooth transition.</p><p>As a reminder The QRL is the first fully post-quantum blockchain ecosystem designed from the ground up with a core of:</p><ul><li>multiple implementations for qrl node (python, go)</li><li>desktop GUI wallet (mac, windows, linux)</li><li>a fantastic <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org/">web-wallet</a> with built in features such as document notarisation and full token support</li><li>CLI Wallet</li><li>our trusty web e<a href="https://explorer.theqrl.org/">xplorer</a></li><li>growing <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org">documentation</a></li><li><a href="https://api.theqrl.org">API</a> — we are easy to build into!</li></ul><h3>Migration deadline</h3><p>Reminder: We have set a deadline (contingent on Ledger release of version 1.5) for <strong>28th February 2019 </strong>for when we will close our automated migration <a href="http://migration.theqrl.org">portal</a>. If you would like to know how to migrate using the current system, we have a handy how-to video on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3YxjMZGxm7A">YouTube</a>. For further help on this process you can always contact the team via <a href="http://support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a> or discuss with the team on <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">Discord</a>.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=fab674992588" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/bittrex-exchange-migration-complete-fab674992588">Bittrex Exchange Migration Complete!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reflecting on CBC 2018]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-cbc-2018-2f039b4b6f8d?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/2f039b4b6f8d</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptoblockcon]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[conference]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 21:39:52 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-12-17T23:13:19.718Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>TL;DR — Was in Las Vegas last week with Jack for the Crypto Blockchain Conference</em></p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*6iCdt_MWNmIeO4eN1Ai3GQ.png" /></figure><h3>Met Jack!</h3><p>Last week, Jack and I attended <a href="https://www.cryptoblockcon.com/">CryptoBlockCon</a>. This was my first time working in person with Jack (bringing my total number of QRL team members met to 8, only a few more to go!), and I have to say, while Canadians are supposed to be polite, it is always more impressive in person.</p><h3>Blockchain In The Wider World</h3><p>The event was held at the <a href="https://www.mandalaybay.com/en.html">Mandalay Bay</a> Resort and Casino. In addition to CBC, the <a href="http://www.milb.com/milb/events/winter_meetings/y2018/agenda_events.jsp">MLB Winter Meetings</a>, and a <a href="https://www.nfrexperience.com/">National Finals Rodeo</a> competition was being held nearby, so many of the competitors were staying at Mandalay Bay. Certainly, literal cowboys, baseball executives and blockchain enthusiasts rubbing shoulders made for some interesting juxtapositions. As much as those of us within the industry can sometimes get weary of terms like “adoption” or “mainstream” or “awareness” — moments like these serve as an eloquent reminder, to me, that blockchain/cryptocurrency are still completely unknown to large swaths of American society, at least. It’s useful, I find, to sometimes recognize that for all the drama this space can sometimes produce, that in the long-run, these are minor speedbumps that will be hardly (if at all) remembered by the vast majority of crypto users within the next 10 years.</p><h3>Spreading The Word</h3><p>On the first day of the conference, I sat for an interview with <a href="https://coinstructive.com/category/lab-radio/">LAB Radio</a>, of <a href="https://coinstructive.com/">Coinstructive Consulting</a>. The interview went very well, though at the end of it we discovered that the camera had filled up its memory card part-way through. However, I believe all the audio was salvaged, so it is possible that interview will come out as audio-only. We will tweet out the link to that interview when it is available to us. It was an enjoyable interview, and I am very happy it was not entirely sacrificed to the gods of technological variance.</p><p>Met some individuals who are attempting to help inform the blockchain community more accurately and easily, something in sore need of in this space. <a href="https://blockchainweekly.net/">Blockchain Weekly</a> is, as the name implies, a weekly newsletter delivering various blockchain and cryptocurrency related links, videos, and articles. I cannot wait until there is true, comprehensive coverage of this industry in a reliable and accurate manner. Or at least until there is sufficient competition as to make that a plausible situation. As is, mediocre outlets with no interest in follow-up or fact-checking dominate the space, and sow confusion with every inaccuracy they publish, or quasi-accuracy they fail to properly vet.</p><h3>Made An Impression</h3><p>Over the past year, my speaking times, circumstances, and indeed my presentation itself has shifted and mutated as needed. This time, my speaking slot was at the very end of the last day of the conference. Now, while it might be nice to close out a music festival, functionally closing out a conference is a different matter altogether. After a few long days inside an at-times labyrinthine building like the Mandalay Bay Resort and Casino (which was made more confusing by 3 separate conferences all being held inside it at once), people are tired. To be blunt; speaking first or last on the last day of a conference can be tough — people are tired, they may have already seen many of the booths available, and the disinterest is sometimes real.</p><p>Which is why I was so pleasantly surprised that, after my presentation was over, I was excitedly approached by a professor from a university in America who was interested in potentially collaborating with us, or at the very least exchanging information in a hopefully mutually beneficial way. I am leaving this description purposefully vague at this time as we are not sure what this potential relationship may or may not blossom in to.</p><p>If you would like to view a video of my presentation at CBC, here is a <a href="https://youtu.be/G7K5REE152w">link </a>to it on our <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZl6N10P9LNpYkrMwWYtK1w">YouTube page.</a></p><h3>Looking Forward</h3><p>CBC was our last conference of the year. It was also our 11th. I had the opportunity and pleasure of attending 10 of them (only one I missed was the Crypto Valley Conference), and can honestly say that while they were not all created equal, they all brought slightly different visions of what a blockchain/cryptocurrency conference could/should be.</p><p>To review, our 2018 appearances were:</p><ul><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/event-blockdelhi-conference-february-21st-3a15fe318302">BlockDelhi 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/apac-blockchain-conference-2018-3817679b45b">APAC Blockchain 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/global-blockchain-expo-2018-next-week-77afb5a9c61c">Global Blockchain Expo 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-dc-finances-high-tech-family-office-meetings-b7fe8067d40d">DC Finance’s New York High Tech Family Office Meeting</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/consensus-conference-next-week-63f206bd0641">Consensus 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-my-evening-with-the-financial-services-club-in-london-573d5713f001">Financial Services Club of London</a></li><li>Crypto Valley Conference 2018</li><li>New York FinTech Week</li><li>Voice of Blockchain 2018</li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/discover-blockchains-conference-next-week-dab6e0b8651b">Discover Blockchains</a></li><li>CryptoBlockCon Las Vegas</li></ul><h3>One Final Note</h3><p>One of the highlights of my conference tour in 2018 were those rare and precious moments when I got to interact with community members. These were all informal (mostly in the context of a bar/pub) meetups; we shared a drink (or two), and got to talk and get to know one another. Meeting the people that use QRL always fills me with a sense of optimism and opportunity. I know that this protocol, and its ecosystem, will continue to blossom in 2019, as it has in 2018.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=2f039b4b6f8d" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-cbc-2018-2f039b4b6f8d">Reflecting on CBC 2018</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crypto Block Conference This Week!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/crypto-block-conference-this-week-1a8f4d1d0cc4?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/1a8f4d1d0cc4</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[las-vegas]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[crypto-block-conference]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 19:43:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-12-09T19:43:39.473Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*qelVD0Rgu1BBcFsNIUVcag.jpeg" /></figure><p><em>TL;DR — Who/What/Where/When/Why of CryptoBlockCon 2018</em></p><h3>Who</h3><p>CryptoBlockCon 2018 will be attended by:</p><ul><li>Adam</li><li>Jack</li></ul><h3>What</h3><p>CryptoBlockCon is a conference series that convenes four times a year, everywhere from Las Vegas to London, to discuss the future benefits &amp; possibilities of blockchain technology &amp; crypto assets. The traveling event serves to showcase companies who are using blockchain, educate current and future industry participants on blockchain technology, and serve as a platform for industry participants to network with one another.</p><h3>Where</h3><p><a href="https://www.mandalaybay.com/en.html">Mandalay Bay Resort and Casino,</a> Las Vegas</p><h3>When</h3><p>December 11–12, 2018</p><h3>Why</h3><p>When we were approached with the opportunity to present at CBC 2018, we had to consider the various factors that make a given conference appearance worth it or not. We had to consider travel distance, the length and prominence of our presentation slot, what we would be presenting, and of course, weigh that against overall cost, both in time and money. When we looked at all of these factors, it made sense to seize this opportunity, and try to maximize it.</p><p>As always, if you will be in Las Vegas this week, whether you are there for the conference or not, and would like to meet up with us, please do not hesitate to reach out. It is always tons of fun to meet users and community members out in the real world. Barring an unforeseen event, this will be our last conference of 2018 — so this will be your last, best chance to see us in person before next year.</p><p>To review, our 2018 appearances were:</p><ul><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/event-blockdelhi-conference-february-21st-3a15fe318302">BlockDelhi 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/apac-blockchain-conference-2018-3817679b45b">APAC Blockchain 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/global-blockchain-expo-2018-next-week-77afb5a9c61c">Global Blockchain Expo 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-dc-finances-high-tech-family-office-meetings-b7fe8067d40d">DC Finance’s New York High Tech Family Office Meeting</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/consensus-conference-next-week-63f206bd0641">Consensus 2018</a></li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/reflecting-on-my-evening-with-the-financial-services-club-in-london-573d5713f001">Financial Services Club of London</a></li><li>Crypto Valley Conference 2018</li><li>New York FinTech Week</li><li>Voice of Blockchain 2018</li><li><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/discover-blockchains-conference-next-week-dab6e0b8651b">Discover Blockchains</a></li><li>CryptoBlockCon Las Vegas</li></ul><p>We are all looking forward to an even more productive 2019!</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=1a8f4d1d0cc4" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/crypto-block-conference-this-week-1a8f4d1d0cc4">Crypto Block Conference This Week!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Last Week in QRL: Nov 26-Dec 3]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-nov-26-dec-3-565a24965ed4?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/565a24965ed4</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[quantum-resistant-ledger]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[weekly-report]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Adam Koltun]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 20:49:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-12-03T21:00:13.683Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*6bheEm5gsDX00SkHRzBssw.png" /></figure><h3>Introduction</h3><p>We are going to be putting out these “Last Week in QRL” blogs moving forward. Because of the intended regularity of these posts (we will sincerely try to post them around the same day each week, excepting holidays), their length/depth will necessarily vary, sometimes radically.</p><p>Obviously, these blogs should not be taken as being indicative or representative of the entirety of our activities — as with the recent Bittrex migration announcement (which was in the works for months) there are sometimes very exciting developments that we cannot speak on in real-time (due to an NDA or other controlling variable). Additionally, sometimes the language employed in these blogs will be necessarily vague regarding the specifics of what is going on.</p><p>However, we hope that these blogs will serve as a useful and enjoyable insight into what is going on at The Quantum Resistant Ledger. So without further ado, here is what has been going on this past week.</p><h3>Team Updates</h3><p>Elliott has moved on to a new and exciting opportunity, and we wish him the best in his new endeavors.</p><h3>Development Updates</h3><p>We are excited to bring you more images from the continuing development of the QRL mobile wallet (Thanks again Adem!)</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*NMBtNCfJHNtohDtxkznHuw.png" /><figcaption>Mobile Wallet UI</figcaption></figure><p>As you have probably noticed, we now have QR (as in matrix barcode) codes in the upcoming build of the mobile wallet! Enabling users a variety of ways to access and control their funds has always been a guiding star for us, and we are happy to be able to take a step further along that trajectory.</p><h3>Marketing Updates</h3><p>Adam and Jack will be heading to Las Vegas December 11th and 12th for the <a href="https://www.cryptoblockcon.com/">Crypto Block Conference</a>.</p><p>Adam <a href="https://www.cryptoblockcon.com/speaker/adam-koltun/">will be speaking</a> there on the 12th, and if you are interested in attending, <a href="https://www.cryptoblockcon.com/register-now/">tickets are available</a>. There will be a preview blog going into further detail closer to the event.</p><h3>Community Updates</h3><p>Our <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/community-nominations-bc4a1f5d5995">community nominations</a> are now live, and have been for the past few weeks.</p><p>Our first community nomination winner was Discord user Doney, for their written contributions.</p><p>Statement from Doney on how he came to the QRL</p><blockquote>I heard about QRL when a friend of mine introduced me to blockchain and crypto. I started reading about blockchain and doing some research on crypto and eventually invested in a few projects. I was looking for unique projects, low market cap, a bit more risk, but higher possible profits. QRL since then became one of the favorite projects for me. So I started to read more and more about the subject. I like to test my opinions and fresh knowledge on reddit. I mean, post something there and you’ll be sure it gets blown to pieces if possible. Talking on reddit about quantum computers and the possible threat for blockchain, always guarantees fireworks, but info from the QRL team and community on slack and now discord has never been proven to be wrong so far. So I really like the technical side of the project and the people involved. The concept of QRL has materialized into a real, technically strong project. I really like the continuing technical development and the extra functionality that is added after launch, and I have a lot of faith in the developers and how they will continue to extend QRL.</blockquote><p>Our second community nomination winner was Discord user snannerb, for their artistic contributions. Snannerb has also created a <a href="https://discord.gg/VFFWbzq">QRL Community Art Discord Server</a> where you can see and contribute artwork about or involving QRL.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*EOfaVw_OZ_6_JlUmCZqhyw.png" /><figcaption>Image created by snannerb</figcaption></figure><p>Statement from snannerb on how he came to the QRL</p><blockquote>It was January 2018 that I learned about the QRL , basically because it was holding its value while the rest of the market was folding. Eventually QRL would follow the rest of the market but after learning about this project I knew I had found what I had been looking for. I had bounced around from project to project since the summer of 2017, and something about QRL just stuck, I love the story of QRL, it really belongs in a comic book or something. I am not the most technical person but it is easy to see that the world is only becoming more digital and the safekeeping of data is to me why QRL is so important. I want to use this technology for what its purpose is, and I love the long term approach of this team, and the great community of folks who keep the knowledge and insight flowing.</blockquote><p>Our most recent community nomination winner is Discord user dr_gonzo, whose positive and productive contributions earned them this week’s community nomination.</p><p>Statement from dr_gonzo regarding the QRL</p><blockquote>I became acquainted with QRL in the depths of the r/ethtrader subreddit in early 2017, where I stumbled upon a link Peter posted to his whitepaper. I had previously read a book about the progression of encryption throughout history, and in that book there was a description of the principles behind RSA. The authors noted that it was the hardest challenge yet for would-be code breakers, but that on a long enough timeline there would likely be a quantum computer capable of cracking our public-key infrastructure. I am excited for more people to learn about QRL as quantum computing news continues to accelerate.</blockquote><p>Remember, to nominate someone, head over to the main QRL <a href="https://discord.gg/V5ZDUAr">Discord</a>, channel #butler</p><h3>Other Updates</h3><p>Yet Another Reminder That Bittrex Is Migrating All ERC20s at 02:00 UTC on December 5th, 2018 UTC.</p><p><a href="https://bittrex.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360001472046-Support-for-the-Quantum-Resistant-Ledger-QRL-blockchain-upgrade">Bittrex Announcement</a> Regarding Migration of QRL ERC20s</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=565a24965ed4" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/last-week-in-qrl-nov-26-dec-3-565a24965ed4">Last Week in QRL: Nov 26-Dec 3</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bittrex Exchange Migration: Proper liquidity secured for The QRL!]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/bittrex-exchange-migration-proper-liquidity-secured-for-the-qrl-df41045497e3?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/df41045497e3</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[bittrex]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 20:54:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-11-26T16:03:24.093Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Bittrex Exchange Migration: liquidity secured for mainnet QRL!</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*vxh2w-LbTpoHkHPDI_ihGg.png" /></figure><p>We are delighted to announce that <a href="https://bittrex.com"><strong>Bittrex</strong></a> will be migrating to <strong>QRL mainnet</strong> on the <strong>4th of December 2018</strong>. You can read their announcement <a href="https://bittrex.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360001472046-Support-for-the-Quantum-Resistant-Ledger-QRL-blockchain-upgrade"><strong>here</strong></a> in full.</p><p>The QRL is the first fully post-quantum blockchain ecosystem designed from the ground up with a core of:</p><ul><li>multiple implementations for qrl node (python, go)</li><li>desktop GUI wallet (mac, windows, linux)</li><li>a fantastic <a href="https://wallet.theqrl.org/">web-wallet</a> with built in features such as document notarisation and full token support</li><li>CLI Wallet</li><li>our trusty web e<a href="https://explorer.theqrl.org/">xplorer</a></li><li>growing <a href="https://docs.theqrl.org">documentation</a></li><li><a href="https://api.theqrl.org">API</a> — we are easy to build into!</li><li>And shortly to be released — a fully compliant Ledger implementation and mobile wallet support (iOS and Android support)..</li></ul><p>Remember that our core code has been extensively audited by red4sec and x41 D-sec to ensure it is enterprise grade. Plus we have an incredibly exciting roadmap we can’t wait to build out.</p><h3>Bittrex</h3><p>We would like to thank the Bittrex team for their professionalism in working closely with us on developing the necessary architecture to ensure smooth exchange integration.</p><p><a href="https://theqrl.org">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> and <a href="https://bittrex.com">Bittrex</a> have a long history and we are proud they are the first major platform to be integrating the QRL mainnet.</p><p>As a project featuring cutting edge post-quantum cryptography, the QRL was not trivial to integrate — our crypto is peculiar and strange! But that is what sets our project apart from every other blockchain in the crypto ecosystem.</p><p>After extensive work between our developers and the Bittrex team, we are pleased that further integration with other platforms should now be a far smoother process. We encourage any organisations interested in joining with the QRL to reach out via email or on <a href="https://twitter.com/QRLedger">Twitter </a>or <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">Discord</a>.</p><p>On that note we have another exciting future relationship to announce in the coming weeks.</p><h3>Migration deadline</h3><p>Following Bittrex migration our previous token will be officially deprecated.</p><p>We will set a hard deadline for <strong>28th February 2019 </strong>for users to migrate using our automated migration <a href="http://migration.theqrl.org">portal</a>. For further help on this process you can always contact the team via <a href="http://support@theqrl.org">support@theqrl.org</a> or discuss with the team on <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">Discord</a>.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*uvXxBT9GzqLSuO5Ue_CcTQ.jpeg" /><figcaption>User art from Discord user SnannerB</figcaption></figure><p>Thank you for your patience and cheers from the QRL family!</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=df41045497e3" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/bittrex-exchange-migration-proper-liquidity-secured-for-the-qrl-df41045497e3">Bittrex Exchange Migration: Proper liquidity secured for The QRL!</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Community: Nominations]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/community-nominations-bc4a1f5d5995?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/bc4a1f5d5995</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Jack Matier]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 18:51:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-11-01T18:51:59.014Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Community Nominations</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*VJIc1dUL1jlGO_atmegZqA.jpeg" /></figure><p>Our community contains an amazing assortment of people that have a wide range of professions and origins. <em>Many</em> of those people continually go above and beyond in improving QRL and furthering Quantum Computing Awareness in the blockchain space.</p><p>It’s time we recognised these people who go above and beyond, which we will do with <em>nominations.</em></p><p><strong><em>Nominations </em></strong>are a<strong><em> </em></strong>way for the <em>community</em> to point out <em>other</em> community members on a weekly basis who contribute positively to QRL or Quantum Computing in general. Of these people that the community points out, one will be selected to be <em>nominated </em>to receive 250 Quanta.</p><h3>How it works</h3><p>One requirement is that nominations are made through Discord, so if you’re not already signed up, do so <a href="https://discord.gg/jBT6BEp">here</a>.</p><p>Anyone can<em> </em>nominate a wide variety of people active in different platforms like Reddit, Medium, Twitter, and Discord (more added as necessary). These people don’t <em>have</em> to be active in our community either, as we will reach out.</p><p>The nominations are gathered <em>weekly </em>and settled at Monday’s meeting, with an award of 250 Quanta (at the mercy of scheduling and other such conflicts of course). We do take into heavy consideration how many <em>votes</em> a person has, <em>however</em>, also reserve the final say (to prevent novelty votes from reigning supreme — this is the internet after all).</p><p>Once a person has been nominated, contacted, <em>and</em> awarded, they are exempt from winning a nomination for 8 weeks.</p><p>On a final note, these are for <em>people</em>, not Companies and/or Organisations.</p><h4>Nominating (how it works, technically)</h4><p>Nominating is easy, in the <em>butler</em> channel on discord you can add:</p><pre>nominate add [reddit/discord/twitter/medium/github] username</pre><p>or remove (only your own nomination, of course):</p><pre>nominate remove [reddit/discord/twitter/medium/github] username</pre><p>If you want to see the <em>current</em> nominations:</p><pre>nominate list</pre><p>To see nominations from previous weeks (but not necessarily the winners), you’ll need to specify the week # (‘w’ is optional):</p><pre>nominate list W15</pre><h3>What we’re looking for</h3><p>Want to be in line for a nomination? Bringing awareness/contributions to QRL or Quantum Computing in general is a good mindset to start from.</p><p>This can include:</p><ul><li>Code Contributions</li><li>User Art</li><li>Github Issues</li><li>Positive social contribution online</li></ul><h3>When is this starting?</h3><p>We’ll be opening up nominations on Tuesday, November 6th, 2018 and having our first settlement, assuming an appropriate nominee is found, on Monday, November 12th, 2018.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=bc4a1f5d5995" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/community-nominations-bc4a1f5d5995">Community: Nominations</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Post-quantum secure multisignature wallets]]></title>
            <link>https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/post-quantum-secure-multisignature-wallets-321f75323e50?source=rss----507e55639b6c---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/321f75323e50</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[qrl]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[multisignature]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[post-quantum]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Peter Waterland]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 16:53:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2018-10-21T16:53:19.549Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Whilst our current plan is to transition to an abstracted unified transaction format with the release of our ‘silicon’ smart contract platform (pencilled for release mid 2019), we have decided internally to integrate multisignature functionality into the QRL early in our upcoming hard fork.</p><p>As this brief blog will describe this adds some unique and powerful functionality to the chain and in doing so will be the first example in the world of post-quantum secure multisignature technology in the wild.</p><h3>What actually is ‘multisig’?</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/640/1*l3D93DHhbZV3A4RTLe8C0A.jpeg" /><figcaption>multisig not multipass!</figcaption></figure><p>“Multisig” or <a href="https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Multisignature">multiple signature transactions</a> require one or more different valid signatures to transfer funds from a special construct called a multisignature address to a destination address. The idea being that funds held in a multisignature address cannot be spent without the cryptographic agreement of a specified number of parties.</p><p>A multisig address can be setup with a certain number of addresses able to take part (<em>n</em>), of which a specified number (<em>m</em>) must provide valid signatures together for a multisig transaction to be valid and spendable. Thus, a multisig address may be said to require <em>m of n</em> signatures.</p><p>An example would be a multisig address which includes three signatory addresses but only requires two signatures for funds to move. This would be: <em>m of n</em> equals 2<em> of </em>3.</p><p>What all of this means in practice is that it allows custody and control of funds to be made much more transparently secure than current reliance upon access via a single private key or wallet. This is important for bigger clients who may wish to use a particular chain such as institutional investors, hedge funds, etc.</p><h3>QRL multisig</h3><p>So how will it work in the QRL? Is it different from other existing solutions? As usual we have to do things slightly differently because of our post-quantum signature scheme XMSS.</p><p>Briefly, we will introduce the new tx subtypes <em>multisig_create </em>and <em>multisig_spend </em>in the next hard fork, introducing hard-coded functionality which is immune to the multisig issues seen previously with ethereum.</p><p>Creating a new multisig address which can be seen on the explorer and receive funds like any other address is simple — just send a <em>multisig_create </em>transaction. This transaction incorporates a list of valid co-signers (addresses or public keys) and thus <em>n</em>, the weighting of each signatory, <em>w</em>, and the required number of signatories for a successful spend — the <em>m</em>.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1008/1*d18vunKh58PN23w72J4zRg.png" /><figcaption>example weighting of a multisignature address</figcaption></figure><p>What do you mean by ‘weighting’? In conventional multisig each signature counts as a single vote. So, to reach an <em>m</em> of three requires three signatures. Whilst this remains default behaviour in the QRL, our implementation allows a specific signatory address to carry more voting weight than another. We implement this simply by attaching an integer value to each party during multisig address formation.</p><p>An example of this would be a new multisig address created in which <em>m of n</em> is 4 of 7. Signatory address 1 has weighting 3, whilst all other signers have weighting 1. Thus, to move funds successfully from the multisig address if signatory address 1 and 2 both sign a valid transaction, then 4 of 7 is satisfied and the transaction will be valid. Similarly, if signatory address 2, 3, 4 and 5 sign a valid transaction then this too would be valid and allow the funds to be spent.</p><p>Alternatively, one could create a new multisig address where one address has functional spending control. One could have an <em>m</em> of four required signatures, with an <em>n</em> of four signatory addresses. If address 1 had a weighting of 3, and all the rest had a weighting of 1, then even if addresses 2, 3, and 4 all signed, they would not have the 4 of 4 required signatures to spend.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/528/1*Rf32CxWwOEH_NOs-A3EpHA.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/528/1*SHZZfe7J-U5kE6VUK2RrbQ.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/528/1*W_5auSQVL2AB96mkxpoxJQ.png" /></figure><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/528/1*Qi63M02T0iGrrhH9uBuKAQ.png" /><figcaption>multisig spend examples</figcaption></figure><p>This variability allows specific control rights to be delegated to funds held in a multisignature wallet — which we think is a very powerful concept, that can be applied in a variety of ways to useful effect.</p><h3>So how will this work in practice?</h3><p>A user can create a multisignature address through the multisig section of the <em>webwallet</em>. A number of co-signers and their weightings are added to the address page, with a minimum weighted number of co-signers for a valid spend recorded. This is then propagated to the network and confirmed in the chain. The address may be looked upon in the explorer and the above details seen and verified by anyone.</p><p>Funds can be sent to the new address like any other. To spend funds however requires the sufficient signatories to send a <em>multisig_spend </em>transaction from their <em>webwallet</em>. Once the <em>m of n </em>for the multisignature address is satisfied then funds will transfer when the last valid <em>multisig_spend</em> transaction reaches the threshold for <em>m</em> set in the <em>multisig_create</em> transaction.</p><p>This is a slightly different approach to bitcoin where the spend transaction requires a script which is signed by each party in turn and then propagated to the network as a single spend transaction.</p><p>In our case the <em>multisig_spend</em> transaction simply signs the: multisignature address, a nonce or 32 byte shared key (which for convenience may be randomly generated in the webwallet to be shared amongst co-signers), the destination address, amount and fee.</p><p>So the only information co-signers need to know is the amount (and fee) and destination of the intended funds and the shared key (for example ‘some collection of random words’).</p><p>Why did we choose this different method of implementing multisignature support which requires each co-signer to make a spend transaction? Because the QRL has a stateful signature scheme, sending XMSS signatures from your wallet off-chain to a third party is not recommended. Such behaviour may lead to inadvertent one-time-signature reuse and reduce the security of the system. So the development team feel this is a more robust method of achieving full multisignature address support without increasing user risk at all.</p><h3>When?</h3><p>In actual fact the changes are fairly minor to the node and state machine to introduce completely post-quantum secure multisignature functionality. Additional changes are planned to our <em>webwallet</em> to make this functionality work straight out-of-the-box. We plan to bundle some state machine backend optimisations in the planned upgrade, which as it involves new transaction subtypes will be a hard fork upgrade.</p><p>Originally, like monero, we had targeted an approximately six monthly hard fork schedule which means we will be planning to hard fork with community consensus in the next 6–8 weeks with a precise blockheight for the fork to be announced in due course.</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=321f75323e50" width="1" height="1"><hr><p><a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger/post-quantum-secure-multisignature-wallets-321f75323e50">Post-quantum secure multisignature wallets</a> was originally published in <a href="https://medium.com/the-quantum-resistant-ledger">The Quantum Resistant Ledger</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>